<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110757753</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110757753</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/D14010001</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Reproductive Success of an Endangered Plant after Invasive Bees Supplant Native Pollinator Services</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>DeNittis, Alyson M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meyer, Susan E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-12-21</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>reproductive success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive bee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>pollinator</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Arctomecon humilis (dwarf bear poppy) is an endangered gypsophile restricted to the St. George area in southern Utah, USA. Extirpation of the rare oligolectic bee Perdita meconis and decline of other native pollinators within the last 20 years has been largely attributed to the advent of invasive Africanized honeybees (AHBs), which have become the predominant pollinator for A. humilis. A three-year study was carried out to determine if reliance on AHBs had a negative effect on reproductive output. In the first year, pollen addition experiments were carried out in a small, isolated population to determine if pollinator scarcity or genetic factors affected reproductive output. In the subsequent two years, reproductive output studies were conducted across four populations. In all years, fruit set across study sites was exceptionally high. There was no consistent effect from flower number or interplant distance, which have historically been shown to have a significant impact on reproductive output prior to AHB arrival. The consequences and sustainability of this relatively young relationship between A. humilis and the AHB remain unclear. However, high reproductive success shows that the AHB is currently capable of adequately fulfilling pollinator services for A. humilis.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>