<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q120376316</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q120376316</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/INP.2018.12</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Response of twelve Florida cogongrass (&lt;i&gt;Imperata cylindrica&lt;/i&gt;) populations to herbicide treatment</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Enloe, Stephen F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lucardi, Rima D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loewenstein, Nancy J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lauer, Dwight K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-06-15</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Imperata cylindrica</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>plant invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press (CUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractCogongrass [Imperata cylindrica(L.) Beauv.] is an invasive grass in the southeastern United States, and its impacts strongly affect the region, especially Florida. Herbicide strategies have been limited to glyphosate in natural areas and imazapyr in managed pine forests and non-crop areas where its soil residual activity is of less concern. This lack of options has raised concern for herbicide resistance, which has never been documented forI. cylindrica. Land managers have also reported variableI. cylindricacontrol, especially with glyphosate. To determine whether herbicide resistance was a possible explanation, we examined glyphosate response ofI. cylindricafrom 12 Florida populations. We also tested aminocyclopyrachlor with and without glyphosate and flumioxazin with glyphosate. Results indicated that herbicide performance was similar acrossI. cylindricapopulations: glyphosate and aminocyclopyrachlor reducedI. cylindricabiomass by 78% and 76%, respectively, and the combined tank mix reduced cogongrass biomass by 91%. Flumioxazin tank mixed with glyphosate did not improve control compared with glyphosate alone. There were no differences in pretreatmentI. cylindricashoot height, with the exception of two panhandle populations that were shorter. Subsequent harvests indicated few differences in shoot and root plus rhizome weights among untreated controls for almost all populations, with the exception of one of the initially shorter panhandle populations. Our findings indicate that variability in glyphosate efficacy, as suggested by managers, is unlikely due to any conferred resistance. Other abiotic factors such as drought and shade and applicator factors such as carrier water quality should be examined to better understand this issue. Additional studies examining non-target impacts of aminocyclopyrachlor should be conducted to determine its potential fit intoI. cylindricamanagement.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>