<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q53052441</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3760/CMA.J.ISSN.0529-5807.2016.08.010</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>[Impact of 2013 American Society of Clinical Oncology/College of American Pathologist guidelines on borderline immunostaining results for HER2: a retrospective study on HER2 FISH results in 1 780 cases of invasive breast cancers].</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Xu, Y</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bai, Q M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yang, F</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhu, X L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lu, Y M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yang, W T</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhou, X Y</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-08-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>zh</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>&lt;h4&gt;Objective&lt;/h4&gt;To analyze the impact of the revised 2013 American Society of Clinical Oncology/College of American Pathologist(ASCO/CAP)HER2 testing guidelines on the status of HER2 and its clinical significance in invasive breast cancers by fluorescent in situ hybridization(FISH).&lt;h4&gt;Methods&lt;/h4&gt;One thousand seven hundred and eighty invasive breast cancer cases with equivocal 2+ immunostaining detected by FISH were retrospectively selected from 2010 to 2014, and the HER2/CEP17 dual-probe results were evaluated according to both the 2007 and 2013 ASCO/CAP guidelines for comparative analysis.&lt;h4&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;Among the 1 780 IHC HER2 (2+ ) invasive breast cancers, the number of HER2 positive, equivocal and negative case were 310(17.41%), 66(3.71%)and 1 404(78.88%) respectively, basing on the 2007 guidelines; whereas basing on the 2013 ASCO/CAP HER2 guidelines, the number of HER2 positive, equivocal and negative case was 360 (20.22%), 182 (10.23%)and 1 238 (69.55%) respectively. Compared with the 2007 guidelines, the proportion of positive and equivocal cases were higher in the 2013 guidelines (17.41% versus 20.22%, 3.71% versus 10.23% respectively), while the proportion of negative cases was lower(78.88% versus 69.55%).&lt;h4&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h4&gt;Using the 2013 ASCO/CAP guidelines could lead to an increase in positive and equivocal cases, and a decrease in negative cases. The increase can probably be attributable to the inclusion of HER2 copy number besides HER2/CEP17 ratio as positive criteria, and it improves the accuracy and may be of important value for screening more population who benefit from HER2 targeting treatment; however the benefits for HER2 positive with low HER2 copy number and the clinical significance of the equivocal cases need to be further investigated.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>