<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110809162</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110809162</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.20903/CSNMBS.MASA.2018.39.2.126</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>OCCURRENCE OF THE NEW INVASIVE INSECT CYDALIMA PERSPECTALIS WALKER ON BOX TREE IN THE REPUBLIC OF MACEDONIA</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Načeski, Sterja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Papazova–Anakieva, Irena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivanov, Blagoj</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lazarevska, Stanislava</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Šurbevski, Blagoj</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-12-28</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive insect</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cydalima perspectalis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Macedonian Academy of Sciences and Arts</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The box tree pyralid Cydalima perspectalis (Walker 1859) is a new invasive moth species in Europe. Box tree moth was recorded for the first time in the Republic of Macedonia on box seedlings in parks, gardens and other urban green spaces in the city of Skopje in 2014. The aim of this study was to investigate the distribution and spread, the biol-ogy and lifecycle, as well as the damage caused by the different generations of the box tree moth in natural box tree stands, as well as in urban areas in R. Macedonia. In natural populations of Buxus, it was firstly recorded on the Vodno mountain in 2015. Since then, its population has a trend of progradation. Based on the results obtained, recommendations are given with measures for gradual regulation of the box tree moth populations. Standard entomo-logical methods (monitoring of the phenomenon, population density and percentage of defoliation) were used.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>