<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111174015</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0246665</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ecological restoration of habitats invaded by Leucanthemum vulgare that alters key ecosystem functions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Khan, Mohd Asgar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hussain, Khursheed</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shah, Manzoor A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-03-26</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Leucanthemum vulgare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ecological restoration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>restoration ecology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ecosystem function</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Precise assessment of the impacts of invasive alien species (IAS) on ecosystem structure and functions is paramount for implementing appropriate management and restoration strategies. Here we investigated the impacts of &lt;jats:italic&gt;Leucanthemum vulgare&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (ox-eye daisy), an aggressive invader in Kashmir Himalaya, on species diversity and primary productivity. We also evaluated bunch of strategies for the ecological restoration of the habitats invaded by this species. We found that uninvaded plots harbored on an average of 6.11 (±2.92) more species per 1m&lt;jats:sup&gt;2&lt;/jats:sup&gt; of quadrat than invaded plots. At multivariate scale, the ordination (nMDS) and ANOSIM exhibited significant differences between invaded and uninvaded plots with R = 0.7889 and &lt;jats:italic&gt;p &lt;&lt;/jats:italic&gt; 0.001. The decrease in diversity indices in invaded as compared to uninvaded plots was associated with more productive plant communities due to &lt;jats:italic&gt;Leucanthemum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; invasion. Higher altitude Gulmarg site was more affected by &lt;jats:italic&gt;Leucanthemum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; invasion than lower altitude Drung site. We tested different approaches for restoration and management of invaded habitats that include herbicide treatment at seedling stage, herbicide treatment before and after flowering stage, mowing and herbicide treatment together, joint mowing, digging and herbicide treatment and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Leucanthemum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; uprooting. Among these treatments, uprooting and combined digging, mowing and herbicide treatment proved to be most effective in controlling &lt;jats:italic&gt;Leucanthemum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; invasion. The implications of these results for effective management of ecologically sensitive and socio-culturally important landscapes are discussed.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>