<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q58109264</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1111/MEC.14910</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Inbreeding tolerance as a pre-adapted trait for invasion success in the invasive ant Brachyponera chinensis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eyer, Pierre-André</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Matsuura, Kenji</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vargo, Edward L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yashiro, Toshihisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Suehiro, Wataru</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Himuro, Chihiro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yokoi, Tomoyuki</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guénard, Benoit</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dunn, Robert R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tsuji, Kazuki</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-12-10</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/termsAndConditions#am</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pachycondyla chinensis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive ant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive trait</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Identifying traits that facilitate species introductions and successful invasions of ecosystems represents a key issue in ecology. Following their establishment into new environments, many non-native species exhibit phenotypic plasticity with post-introduction changes in behaviour, morphology or life history traits that allow them to overcome the presumed loss of genetic diversity resulting in inbreeding and reduced adaptive potential. Here, we present a unique strategy in the invasive ant Brachyponera chinensis (Emery), in which inbreeding tolerance is a pre-adapted trait for invasion success, allowing this ant to cope with genetic depletion following a genetic bottleneck. We report for the first time that inbreeding is not a consequence of the founder effect following introduction, but it is due to mating between sister queens and their brothers that pre-exists in native populations which may have helped it circumvent the cost of invasion. We show that a genetic bottleneck does not affect the genetic diversity or the level of heterozygosity within colonies and suggest that generations of sib-mating in native populations may have reduced inbreeding depression through purifying selection of deleterious alleles. This work highlights how a unique life history may pre-adapt some species for biological invasions.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>