<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q90736304</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/NU12040903</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>An Extract of Olive Mill Wastewater Downregulates Growth, Adhesion and Invasion Pathways in Lung Cancer Cells: Involvement of CXCR4</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gallazzi, Matteo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Festa, Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Corradino, Paola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sansone, Clementina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Albini, Adriana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Noonan, Douglas M</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-03-26</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wastewater</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Several diet-derived compounds have been reported to exert antioxidant, anti-proliferative and anti-angiogenic effects in numerous cancers and could be beneficial in cancer prevention. Olive oil production involves the generation of an aqueous phase defined as olive mill wastewater (OMWW), a polluting effluent rich in soluble polyphenols. Here, we assessed the cancer preventive properties exerted by a purified extract of OMWW (A009) for its activity on lung cancer cell lines. Hydroxytyrosol, the most abundant polyphenol present in our A009 extracts, was used as reference molecule in the assays performed. Extracts from OMWW from two different olive oil cultivars were used. We found that the A009 extracts limit lung cancer cell proliferation in a dose and time dependent manner. These effects were associated with the induction of apoptosis. A009 extracts were effective in inhibiting adhesion capabilities on a fibronectin layer accompanied with a reduction in their ability to generate invasive sprouts in a Matrigel layer. The production of chemokine CXCL12 and CXCR4 receptor were reduced by treatment with the extracts. Also, A009 interfered with the production of proangiogenic and pro-inflammatory VEGF, CXCL8, and CCL2 (as detected by FACS analysis) in the lung cell lines. A009 extracts were able to decrease STAT3 phosphorylation in lung cancer cells. Our results show that A009 extracts reduced activities related to tumor cell behavior in lung cancer cell lines, suggesting that they could have a potential cancer preventive role.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>