<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q49910256</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q49910256</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5775418</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-017-19000-7</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Distribution and the origin of invasive apple snails, Pomacea canaliculata and P. maculata (Gastropoda: Ampullariidae) in China.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Yang, Qian-Qian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, Su-Wen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He, Chao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yu, Xiao-Ping</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-01-19</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Pomacea canaliculata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Ampullariidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractSpecies of Pomacea, commonly known as apple snails, are native to South America, and have become widely distributed agricultural and environmental pests in southern China since their introduction in the 1980s. However, only since 2010 have researchers recognized that at least two species, P. canaliculata and P. maculata, are present in China. Although impacts of apple snails have been extensively documented, confusion still persists regarding current distributions and origin of the species in China. To resolve this confusion, we used phylogenetic and phylogeographic methods to analyze 1464 mitochondrial COI sequences, including 349 new sequences from samples collected in southern China and 1115 publicly available sequences from snails collected in the native and introduced ranges. Pomacea canaliculata was found at_all sampled localities, while P. maculata was found at only five sampled localities in the Sichuan basin and Zhejiang province. Our data indicate that Chinese populations of P. canaliculata share an Argentinian origin, consistent with multiple introductions of this species elsewhere in Asia. In addition, just a_single lineage ofP. maculata is established in China, which shares with populations in Brazil.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>