<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q26247786</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q26247786</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5747333</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.12688/F1000RESEARCH.9364.1</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Predicted protein interactions of IFITMswhich inhibit Zika virus infection</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ganapathiraju, Madhavi K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ganapathiraju, Madhavi K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Karunakaran, Kalyani B</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Correa-Menéndez, Josefina</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-08-05</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Zika virus</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Zika virus infection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Zika virus proteome</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>microcephaly</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>F1000 Research Ltd</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>After the first reported case of Zika virus in Brazil, in 2015, a significant increase in the reported cases of microcephaly was observed. Microcephaly is a neurological condition in which the infant’s head is significantly smaller with complications in brain development. Recently, two small membrane-associated interferon-inducible transmembrane proteins (IFITM1 and IFITM3) have been shown to repress members of the flaviviridae family which includes the Zika virus. However, the exact mechanisms leading to the inhibition of the virus are yet unknown. Here, we assembled an interactome of IFITM1 and IFITM3 with known protein-protein interactions (PPIs) collected from publicly available databases and novel PPIs predicted using High-confidence Protein-Protein Interaction Prediction (HiPPIP) model. We analyzed the functional and pathway associations of the interacting proteins, and found that there are several immunity pathways (interferon signaling, cd28 signaling in T-helper cells crosstalk between dendritic cells and natural killer cells), neuronal pathways (axonal guidance signaling, neural tube closure and actin cytoskeleton signaling) and developmental pathways that are associated with these interactors. These results could help direct future research in elucidating the mechanisms underlying the viral immunity to Zika virus and other flaviviruses.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>