<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q33482830</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2706987</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0006297</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Bacterial thymidine kinase as a non-invasive imaging reporter for Mycobacterium tuberculosis in live animals</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Davis, Stephanie L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Be, Nicholas A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lamichhane, Gyanu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nimmagadda, Sridhar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pomper, Martin G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bishai, William R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jain, Sanjay K</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2009-07-16</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>Mycobacterium tuberculosis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>tuberculosis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>non-invasive imaging</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>&lt;h4&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;Bacteria can be selectively imaged in experimentally-infected animals using exogenously administered 1-(2'deoxy-2'-fluoro-beta-D-arabinofuranosyl)-5-[(125)I]-iodouracil ([(125)I]-FIAU), a nucleoside analog substrate for bacterial thymidine kinase (TK). Our goal was to use this reporter and develop non-invasive methods to detect and localize Mycobacterium tuberculosis.&lt;h4&gt;Methodology/principal findings&lt;/h4&gt;We engineered a M. tuberculosis strain with chromosomally integrated bacterial TK under the control of hsp60 -- a strong constitutive mycobacterial promoter. [(125)I]FIAU uptake, antimicrobial susceptibilities and in vivo growth characteristics were evaluated for this strain. Using single photon emission computed tomography (SPECT), M. tuberculosis P(hsp60) TK strain was evaluated in experimentally-infected BALB/c and C3HeB/FeJ mice using the thigh inoculation or low-dose aerosol infection models. M. tuberculosis P(hsp60) TK strain actively accumulated [(125)I]FIAU in vitro. Growth characteristics of the TK strain and susceptibility to common anti-tuberculous drugs were similar to the wild-type parent strain. M. tuberculosis P(hsp60) TK strain was stable in vivo and SPECT imaging could detect and localize this strain in both animal models tested.&lt;h4&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;We have developed a novel tool for non-invasive assessment of M. tuberculosis in live experimentally-infected animals. This tool will allow real-time pathogenesis studies in animal models of TB and has the potential to simplify preclinical studies and accelerate TB research.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>