<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117804657</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117804657</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.82.97998</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>_Shining a LAMP on the applications of isothermal amplification for monitoring environmental biosecurity</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Deliveyne, Nathan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Young, Jennifer M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Austin, Jeremy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cassey, Phillip</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-02-24</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Environmental biosecurity risks associated with the transnational wildlife trade include the loss of biodiversity, threats to public health, and the proliferation of invasive alien species. To assist enforcement agencies in identifying species either intentionally (trafficked) or unintentionally (stowaway) entrained in the trade-chain pathway, rapid forensic techniques are needed to enable their detection from DNA samples when physical identification is not possible. Loop Mediated Isothermal Amplification (LAMP) is an emerging technique, with recent applications in biosecurity and forensic sciences, which has potential to function as a field-based detection tool. Here we provide an overview of current research that applies LAMP to environmental biosecurity, including identification of ornamental wildlife parts, consumer products, and invasive species monitoring and biosecurity detection. We discuss the current scope of LAMP as applied to various wildlife trade scenarios and biosecurity checkpoint monitoring, highlight the specificity, sensitivity, and robustness for these applications, and review the potential utility of LAMP for rapid field-based detection at biosecurity checkpoints. Based on our assessment of the literature we recommend broader interest, research uptake, and investment in LAMP as an appropriate field-based species detection method for a wide range of environmental biosecurity scenarios.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>