<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q120644764</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q120644764</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1002/PS.7510</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Exploiting exotic pathogens as mycoherbicides against invasive alien weeds: Japanese knotweed as a case study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kurose, Daisuke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seier, Marion K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Evans, Harry C</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-05-09</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractPlant species have been introduced increasingly into non‐native ranges, where many have become exotic weeds with adverse impacts on native ecosystems, as well as on farming and other livelihoods. In biological control, the classical or inoculative approach is the one most commonly used for the management of invasive alien weeds and is based on the use of co‐evolved natural enemies from the native range to control the invasive weed. Typically, the inundative or mycoherbicide approach targets problematic weeds using local plant pathogens that, in the case of introduced species, have ‘jumped’ onto the exotic host. The leaf‐spot fungus, Mycosphaerella polygoni‐cuspidati, co‐evolved with its host, Reynoutria (Fallopia) japonica (Japanese knotweed), in Japan and has a unique history of being investigated both as a classical biological control agent and a mycoherbicide against this highly invasive weed in the United Kingdom and North America. Here, we highlight our research on M. polygoni‐cuspidati as part of a biological control programme for Japanese knotweed and review the potential of mycoherbicides using exotic pathogens for the management of invasive alien weeds. © 2023 The Authors. Pest Management Science published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Society of Chemical Industry.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>