<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q58913871</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q58913871</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1155/2012/746342</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The Influence of Abiotic Factors on an Invasive Pest of Pulse Crops,Sitona lineatus(L.) (Coleoptera: Curculionidae), in North America</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weiss, R. M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cárcamo, H. A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meers, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>beetles</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Curculionidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sitona lineatus</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive pest</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Pea leaf weevil,Sitona lineatus(L.), native to Europe and North Africa, has been introduced into many other countries around the world, including the USA and Canada. Adults are oligophagous pests on leguminaceous plants.Sitona lineatuswas first recorded in Canada in 1997, near Lethbridge, Alberta. Since then, it has spread north in Alberta and west into Saskatchewan in 2007. Bioclimatic simulation models were used to predict the distribution and extent of establishment ofS. lineatusin Canada based on its current geographic range, phenology, relative abundance, and empirical data. The study identified areas in Canada that are at risk for future establishment ofS. lineatusand developed a better understanding of climate effects. Climate change projections (General Circulation Models) were then imposed on the bioclimatic model ofS. lineatus. Bioclimatic model output varied for each of the three General Circulation Models. In terms of suitability for pest establishment (Ecoclimatic Index), the NCAR273 CCSM climate data resulted in the most significant shift northward.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>