<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q30044868</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q30044868</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PPAT.1000265</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Malaria parasite invasion of the mosquito salivary gland requires interaction between the Plasmodium TRAP and the Anopheles saglin proteins</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ghosh, Anil K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Devenport, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jethwaney, Deepa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kalume, Dario E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pandey, Akhilesh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Anderson, Vernon E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sultan, Ali A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kumar, Nirbhay</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jacobs-Lorena, Marcelo</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>thrombospondin-related anonymous protein</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>malaria</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>parasite invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>SM1 is a twelve-amino-acid peptide that binds tightly to the Anopheles salivary gland and inhibits its invasion by Plasmodium sporozoites. By use of UV-crosslinking experiments between the peptide and its salivary gland target protein, we have identified the Anopheles salivary protein, saglin, as the receptor for SM1. Furthermore, by use of an anti-SM1 antibody, we have determined that the peptide is a mimotope of the Plasmodium sporozoite Thrombospondin Related Anonymous Protein (TRAP). TRAP binds to saglin with high specificity. Point mutations in TRAP's binding domain A abrogate binding, and binding is competed for by the SM1 peptide. Importantly, in vivo down-regulation of saglin expression results in strong inhibition of salivary gland invasion. Together, the results suggest that saglin/TRAP interaction is crucial for salivary gland invasion by Plasmodium sporozoites.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>