<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q113904305</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113904305</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S10530-022-02780-Z</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Massive economic costs of biological invasions despite widespread knowledge gaps: a dual setback for India</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bang, Alok</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cuthbert, Ross N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haubrock, Phillip J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fernández, Romina D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moodley, Desika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diagne, Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Turbelin, Anna J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Renault, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dalu, Tatenda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Courchamp, Franck</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-04-05</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>knowledge gap hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q1481327</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:knowledge gap hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q1481327</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>knowledge gap</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractBiological invasions are one of the top drivers of the ongoing biodiversity crisis. An underestimated consequence of invasions is the enormity of their economic impacts. Knowledge gaps regarding economic costs produced by invasive alien species (IAS) are pervasive, particularly for emerging economies such as India—the fastest growing economy worldwide. To investigate, highlight and bridge this gap, we synthesised data on the economic costs of IAS in India. Specifically, we examine how IAS costs are distributed spatially, environmentally, sectorally, taxonomically, temporally, and across introduction pathways; and discuss how Indian IAS costs vary with socioeconomic indicators. We found that IAS have cost the Indian economy between at least US$ 127.3 billion to 182.6 billion (Indian Rupees _ 8.3 trillion to 11.9 trillion) over 1960–2020, and these costs have increased with time. Despite these massive recorded costs, most were not assigned to specific regions, environments, sectors, cost types and causal IAS, and these knowledge gaps are more pronounced in India than in_the rest of the world. When costs were specifically assigned, maximum costs were incurred in West, South and North India, by invasive alien insects in semi-aquatic ecosystems; they were incurred mainly by the public and social welfare sector, and were associated with damages and losses rather than management expenses. Our findings indicate that the reported economic costs grossly underestimate the actual costs, especially considering the expected costs given India’s population size, gross domestic product and high numbers of IAS without reported costs. This cost analysis improves our knowledge of the negative economic impacts of biological invasions in India and the burden they can represent for its development. We hope this study motivates policymakers to address socio-ecological issues in India and launch a national biological invasion research programme, especially since economic growth will be accompanied by greater impacts of global change.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>