<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110759235</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1051/KMAE/2021028</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The first unified inventory of non-native fishes of the South Caucasian countries, Armenia, Azerbaijan, and Georgia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kuljanishvili, Tatia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mumladze, Levan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Japoshvili, Bella</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mustafayev, Namig</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ibrahimov, Shaig</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Patoka, Jiří</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pipoyan, Samvel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kalous, Lukáš</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>EDP Sciences</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The South Caucasus (SC) region is recognized for its high biological diversity and various endemic animal taxa. The area has experienced many fish introductions over the years, but the overall information about non-native fishes in the three SC countries, Armenia, Azerbaijan, and Georgia did not exist. Although these three countries belong to the Kura River drainage, Caspian Sea basin (only the western half of Georgia drains into the Black Sea), the legislative framework for each country regarding introduction of non-native fish species and their treatment is different and poorly developed. The goal of the present study was to make an initial inventory of non-native fish species in the three SC countries, and summarize the existing knowledge as a basis for future risk assessment models and formulation of regional management policies. Here, we present a unified list of 27 non-native species recorded in the wild in Armenia, Azerbaijan, and Georgia. Among these 27 species, eight were translocated from the Black Sea basin to the Caspian Sea basin. Out of these 27 non-native fishes, 15 species have become established (three of them being considered invasive) and six fish species could not survive in the wild.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>