<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q100465701</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q100465701</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/ZOOKEYS.970.54801</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Exotic-looking Neotropical Tischeriidae (Lepidoptera) and their host plants</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stonis, Jonas R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dikus, Arnas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Remeikis, Andrius</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Solis, Maria Alma</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Katinas, Liliana</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-09-21</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Lepidoptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tischeriidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Seven new species of Tischeriidae are described from the Neotropics: Astrotischeria jociui Dikus &amp;amp; Stonis, sp. nov. (feeding on Wissadula excelsior (Cav.) C. Presl., Malvaceae), A. atlantica Dikus &amp;amp; Stonis, sp. nov. (feeding on Baccharis spicata (Lam.) Baill., Asteraceae), A. cornuata Dikus &amp;amp; Stonis, sp. nov. (host plant unknown), Paratischeria guarani Dikus &amp;amp; Stonis, sp. nov. (feeding on Elephantopus mollis Kunth, Asteraceae), P. mesoamericana Dikus &amp;amp; Stonis, sp. nov. (feeding on Montanoa hibiscifolia Benth., Asteraceae), P. suprafasciata Dikus &amp;amp; Stonis, sp. nov. (feeding on Allophyllus edulis (A. St.-Hil., A. Juss. &amp;amp; Cambess.) Hieron. ex Niederl., Sapindaceae), and P. braziliensis Dikus &amp;amp; Stonis, sp. nov. (host plant unknown). Additionally, an updated distribution map of Paratischeria neotropicana (Dikus &amp;amp; Stonis, 2015), which currently has the broadest distribution range among the Neotropical Tischeriidae is provided along with new host-plant data, a list of all recorded host plants in the Neotropics, and a brief discussion on trophic relationships of Tischeriidae. It is hypothesized that host-plant distribution ranges can provide clues to potential distribution ranges of these specialized, monophagous or oligophagous, leaf miners. All new taxa are illustrated with photographs of the adults, their genitalia, and, if available, leaf mines.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>