<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q97070432</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q97070432</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7429548</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S10265-020-01212-0</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The ability of seeds to float with water currents contributes to the invasion success of Impatiens balfourii and I. glandulifera</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Najberek, Kamil</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olejniczak, Paweł</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berent, Katarzyna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gąsienica-Staszeczek, Magdalena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Solarz, Wojciech</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-07-03</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q109467185</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Impatiens balfourii</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractTwo alien species in Europe,Impatiens glanduliferaandI. balfourii, are closely related, have similar growth rates and reproductive capacities, and are very attractive to pollinators. Nevertheless, onlyI. glanduliferais a highly invasive alien species in Europe, whileI. balfouriiis non-invasive. We assumed that the varying levels of invasiveness are driven by differences in the floating ability of their seeds, which may determine the invasion success of riparian alien plants, such as theImpatiensspecies. By mimicking two types of aquatic conditions, we determined seed floating ability for each species from younger and older populations. We also analyzed four seed traits: seed viability, surface, shape and coat structure. Seeds of the non-invasiveI. balfouriifloat less well than seeds of the invasiveI. glandulifera. We also found that the seeds ofI. balfouriifrom the younger population have a higher floating ability in comparison with that of the seeds from the older population. The results forI. glanduliferawere the opposite, with decreased floating ability in the younger population. These differences were associated with seed surface, shape and coat structure. These results indicate that the floating ability ofI. balfouriiseeds may increase over time following its introduction into a given area, while in the case ofI. glandulifera, this ability may gradually decrease. Therefore, the former species, currently regarded as a poor disperser, has the potential to become invasive in the future, whereas the latter does not seem to benefit from further investments in the floating ability of its seeds.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>