<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117046985</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117046985</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/PLANTS12010128</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Non-Additive Effects of Environmental Factors on Growth and Physiology of Invasive Solidago canadensis and a Co-Occurring Native Species (Artemisia argyi)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Yang, Bin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cui, Miaomiao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dai, Z-C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Jian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yu, Haochen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fan, Xue</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rutherford, Susan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Du, Daolin</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-12-27</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Artemisia argyi</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Solidago canadensis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>native species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Changes in environmental factors, such as temperature and UV, have significant impacts on the growth and development of both native and invasive plant species. However, few studies examine the combined effects of warming and enhanced UV on plant growth and performance in invasive species. Here, we investigated single and combined effects of warming and UV radiation on growth, leaf functional and photosynthesis traits, and nutrient content (i.e., total organic carbon, nitrogen and phosphorous) of invasive Solidago canadensis and its co-occurring native species, Artemisia argyi, when grown in culture racks in the greenhouse. The species were grown in monoculture and together in a mixed community, with and without warming, and with and without increased UV in a full factorial design. We found that growth in S. canadensis and A. argyi were inhibited and more affected by warming than UV-B radiation. Additionally, there were both antagonistic and synergistic interactions between warming and UV-B on growth and performance in both species. Overall, our results suggested that S. canadensis was more tolerant to elevated temperatures and high UV radiation compared to the native species. Therefore, substantial increases in temperature and UV-B may favour invasive S. canadensis over native A. argyi. Research focusing on the effects of a wider range of temperatures and UV levels is required to improve our understanding of the responses of these two species to greater environmental variability and the impacts of climate change.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>