<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q36913783</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q36913783</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3676857</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/IJMS140510608</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Effect of plant derived antimicrobials on Salmonella enteritidis adhesion to and invasion of primary chicken oviduct epithelial cells in vitro and virulence gene expression</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Upadhyaya, Indu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Upadhyay, Abhinav</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Johny, Anup Kollanoor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Darre, Michael J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Venkitanarayanan, Kumar</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2013-05-21</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Salmonella enteritidis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Salmonella Enteritidis (SE) is a major foodborne pathogen in the United States and one of the most frequently reported Salmonella serotypes globally. Eggs are the most common food product associated with SE infections in humans. The pathogen colonizes the intestinal tract in layers, and migrates to reproductive organs systemically. Since adhesion to and invasion of chicken oviduct epithelial cells (COEC) is critical for SE colonization in reproductive tract, reducing these virulence factors could potentially decrease egg yolk contamination. This study investigated the efficacy of sub-inhibitory concentrations of three plant-derived antimicrobials (PDAs), namely carvacrol, thymol and eugenol in reducing SE adhesion to and invasion of COEC, and survival in chicken macrophages. In addition, the effect of PDAs on SE genes critical for oviduct colonization and macrophage survival was determined using real-time quantitative PCR (RT-qPCR). All PDAs significantly reduced SE adhesion to and invasion of COEC (p </dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>