<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111154527</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111154527</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/ANI11071966</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Monthly eDNA Monitoring of an Invasive Bryozoan, Bugulina californica, in Seawater Using Species-Specific Markers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Philjae</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yoon, Tae-Joong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shin, Sook</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-06-30</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>environmental DNA</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive bryozoan</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Environmental DNA (eDNA) method used by many ecologists as effective investigation tool can detect endangered species, rare species, and invasive species. In case of invasive species, eDNA method help to monitor the target species when the species was hard to detect through the traditional survey such as the early stage of invasion, low abundance, and larva or juvenile stage. The bryozoan, Bugulina californica, was known as a marine fouling invasive species in Korea since its first reported in 1978. This species expanded nationwide, and damages to ascidian aquaculture through attached on the ship hulls and artificial facilities. To monitor the distribution and biomass of invasive bryozoan, B. californica, the qPCR analysis of environmental DNA was performed on seawater samples from 12 harbors. In this study, we designed species-specific markers which can calculate the detected DNA copies of B. californica, and the presence and monitoring of this species can be more accurately estimated by environmental DNA analysis than by traditional survey, in which it is difficult to identify the species. Real-time PCR analysis using environmental DNA is an effective monitoring method that can determine both the distribution and the monthly change in biomass of B. californica in Korea.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>