<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q112765894</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q112765894</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/SU14020746</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Interaction between Nitrogen, Phosphorus, and Invasive Alien Plants</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Youli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leng, Zhanrui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wu, Yueming</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jia, Hui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yan, Chongling</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Xinhong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ren, Guangqian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wu, Guirong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Jian</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-01-11</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Plant invasion is significantly affected by environmental factors in the recipient habitats and affects the stability and sustainable development of society. The invasiveness of alien plants may be increased by anthropogenic-mediated disturbances, such as fluctuations in nutrients caused by excessive emissions of nitrogen (N) and phosphorus (P). To improve our understanding of the interactions between N and P fluctuations and invasive alien plants, the current report focuses on the biogeochemical behavior of N and P among invasive alien plants, native plants, and the soil within the plant–soil ecosystem. Our research, together with a synthesis of the literature, shows that fluctuations in N and P resources provide more opportunities and competitiveness for plant invasion. At the same time, the biogeochemical cycles of N and P are promoted because of their efficient and increased utilization and rate of release by invasive alien plants. However, there is no consensus on whether the N and P compositions of invasive species are different from those of the natives in their habitat. Quantitative studies that compare N and P contents in plant, litter, and soil between native plant communities and invaded communities on a global scale are an indispensable area of research focus for the future.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>