<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q56771064</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1614/IPSM-08-118.1</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive White Sweetclover (Melilotus officinalis) Control with Herbicides, Cutting, and Flaming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Conn, Jeffery S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seefeldt, Steven S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2009-07</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://www.cambridge.org/core/terms</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Melilotus officinalis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press (CUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;White sweetclover is invading the Alaska glacial river floodplains and roadsides adjacent to natural areas, and control methods are needed. Chlorsulfuron, 2,4-DB, clopyralid, triclopyr, and 2,4-D controlled white sweetclover seedlings below recommended rates in the greenhouse. Biomass of established plants in the field was reduced by chlorsulfuron at recommended (17.6 g ai/ha), 1/2, and 1/4 rates and was reduced by triclopyr and 2,4-D at recommended rates (1,260 and 1,600 g ai/ha). Herbicides were more effective at reducing white sweetclover viable seed production in 2007 than in 2006. Only chlorsulfuron at 17.6 g ai/ha (recommended rate) eliminated seed production in both years. Flaming killed first-year plants, but some second-year plants resprouted and produced viable seed. Cutting at the 2.5 or 10 cm height did not control first-year plants because of regrowth, and second-year plant density and seed production was reduced by cutting at 2.5 cm but not by cutting at 10 cm.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>