<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q33521231</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q33521231</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2794534</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0008501</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Influence of two vaccination campaigns on genetic diversity of invasive Neisseria meningitidis isolates in northern Spain (1997-2008)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vicente, Diego</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Esnal, Olatz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Goicoechea, José López</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cisterna, Ramón</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pérez-Trallero, Emilio</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2009-12-30</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Neisseria meningitidis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>genetic diversity</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>BackgroundNeisseria meningitidis diversifies rapidly, due to its high recombination rates. The aim of this study was to analyze the possible impact of two vaccination campaigns (a once-off A/C polysaccharide vaccination campaign in people aged 18 months to 20 years old in 1997, and a meningococcal C conjugate vaccination campaign in children aged Methodology/principal findingsThe isolates were analyzed for diversity using multilocus sequence typing, eBURST and the S.T.A.R.T.2 program. One hundred and seven sequence types (ST) and 20 clonal complexes were obtained. Five different STs (ST11, ST8, ST33, ST1163 and ST3496) included 56.4% of the isolates. With the exception of ST11, all other STs were associated with a specific serogroup. Epidemic circulation of serogroup C ST8 isolates was detected in 1997-1998, as well as epidemic circulation of ST11 isolates (serogroups B and C) in 2002-2004. The epidemic behavior of serogroup B ST11 (ST11_B:2a:P1.5) was similar, although with lesser intensity, to that of ST11 of serogroup C. Although clonality increased during epidemic years, the overall diversity of the meningococcal population did not increase throughout the 12 years of the study.ConclusionThe overall diversity of the meningococcal population, measured by the frequency of STs and clonal complexes, numbers of alleles, polymorphic sites, and index of association, remained relatively constant throughout the study period, contradicting previous findings by other researchers.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>