<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117788603</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117788603</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/JPE/RTAB100</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Interactions between invasive plants and heavy metal stresses: a review</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Li, Jian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leng, Zhanrui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wu, Yueming</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Du, Yizhou</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dai, Z-C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Biswas, Asim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zheng, Xiaojun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Guanlin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mahmoud, Esawy Kasem</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jia, Hui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Du, Daolin</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-08-27</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractGlobal changes have altered the distribution pattern of the plant communities, including invasive species. Anthropogenic contamination may reduce native plant resistance to the invasive species. Thus, the focus of the current review is on the contaminant biogeochemical behavior among native plants, invasive species and the soil within the plant–soil ecosystem to improve our understanding of the interactions between invasive plants and environmental stressors. Our studies together with synthesis of the literature showed that (i) the impacts of invasive species on environmental stress were heterogeneous, (ii) the size of the impact was variable and (iii) the influence types were multidirectional even within the same impact type. However, invasive plants showed self-protective mechanisms when exposed to heavy metals (HMs) and provided either positive or negative influence on the bioavailability and toxicity of HMs. On the other hand, HMs may favor plant invasion due to the widespread higher tolerance of invasive plants to HMs together with the ‘escape behavior’ of native plants when exposed to toxic HM pollution. However, there has been no consensus on whether elemental compositions of invasive plants are different from the natives in the polluted regions. A quantitative research comparing plant, litter and soil contaminant contents between native plants and the invaders in a global context is an indispensable research focus in the future.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>