<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q44964707</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/J.MARENVRES.2008.12.007</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Limited impact of Sargassum muticum on native algal assemblages from rocky intertidal shores.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Olabarria, Celia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rodil, Iván F</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Incera, Mónica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Troncoso, Jesús S</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2008-12-30</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://www.elsevier.com/tdm/userlicense/1.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sargassum muticum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier BV</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive species represent a serious threat to natural ecosystems through a range of negative effects on native species in the region invaded. The invasive species Sargassum muticum has invaded several temperate regions worldwide including the Galician rocky shoreline (northwestern Spain) in Western Europe. The main aim of this study was to assess if colonization by S. muticum has any effect on native algal assemblages by experimental removal of S. muticum. We predicted that in those plots where S. muticum plants were removed, the structure of native algal assemblages would differ from that in plots where S. muticum plants were untouched. In addition, we predicted that the effect of Sargassum removal would be more important than other causes of variability at the small scale investigated. Results indicated limited impact of S. muticum on native assemblages. The impact was only evident on the total number of native taxa and two understory morpho-functional groups, filamentous and foliose algae, rather than on the entire macroalgal assemblages.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>