<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q51160991</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q51160991</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3988741</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1155/2014/952051</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ecological effects of roads on the plant diversity of coastal wetland in the Yellow River Delta.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Li, Yunzhao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yu, Junbao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ning, Kai</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Du, Siyao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Han, Guangxuan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Qu, Fanzhu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Guangmei</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fu, Yuqin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhan, Chao</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2014-03-31</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>biodiversity</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>coastal wetland</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>coastal invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>coastal ecology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>stream ecology</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The 26 sample sites in 7 study plots adjacent to asphalt road and earth road in coastal wetland in the Yellow River Delta were selected to quantify plant diversity using quadrat sampling method in plant bloom phase of July and August 2012. The indice ofβTand Jaccard’s coefficient were applied to evaluate the species diversity. The results showed that the plant diversities and alien plants were high in the range of 0–20_m to the road verge. There were more exotics and halophytes in plots of asphalt roadside than that of earth roadside. However, proportion of halophytes in habitats of asphalt roadsides was lower than that of earth roadside. By comparingβ-diversity, there were more common species in the asphalt roadsides than that in the earth roadsides. The similarity of plant communities in studied plots of asphalt roadsides and earth roadsides increased with increasing the distance to road verge. The effect range of roads for plant diversity in study region was about 20_m to road verge. Our results indicate that the construction and maintenance of roads in wetland could increase the plant species diversities of communities and risk of alien species invasion.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>