<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q113233715</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113233715</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1590/1982-0224-2021-0123</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Prey selectivity of the invasive largemouth bass towards native and non-native prey: an experimental approach</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Cárdenas-Mahecha, Liliana Paola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vitule, Jean Ricardo Simões</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padial, André Andrian</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-06-29</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasional meltdown hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q115322315</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:invasional meltdown hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q115322315</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>FapUNIFESP (SciELO)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract Non-native predators are known to cause ecological impacts through heightened consumption of resources and decimation of native species. One such species is Micropterus salmoides. Often introduced for sport fishing worldwide; it has been listed by International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources as one of the 100 of the world’s worst invasive species. Whilst impacts conferred towards native prey are well known, its relationship with other non-native species has received much less attention. Therefore, the aim of this study was to experimentally investigate the feeding preference of M. salmoides towards native prey (Geophagus iporangensis) compared to non-native prey (Oreochromis niloticus and Coptodon rendalli) using comparative consumption and the Manly-Chesson selectivity index. We found a higher consumption by M. salmoides towards the non-native prey and a tendency for this non-native preference to increase when prey availability increased. Our results are in line with the hypothesis that the invasion of the non-native predator can be facilitated by the high abundance and reproductive rate of the non-native prey. This is relevant considering the interaction of multiple invaders in an ecosystem, in particular environments modified by humans. Interspecific relationships are complex and their understanding is necessary for environmental management decision-making.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>