<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q47915189</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1146/ANNUREV-ENTO-031616-034933</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ecology, Worldwide Spread, and Management of the Invasive South American Tomato Pinworm, Tuta absoluta: Past, Present, and Future.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Biondi, Antonio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guedes, Raul Narciso C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wan, Fang-Hao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Desneux, Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-10-04</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tuta absoluta</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Annual Reviews</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt; The South American tomato pinworm, Tuta absoluta (Meyrick), is native to the western Neotropics. After invading Spain in 2006, it spread rapidly throughout Afro-Eurasia and has become a major threat to world tomato production. Integrated pest management (IPM) strategies have been developed, but widespread insecticide use has caused selection for insecticide resistance as well as undesirable effects on key beneficial arthropods. Augmentation and conservation biological control relying on omnivorous mirid predators has proved successful for management of T. absoluta, where implementation is dependent on abiotic, biotic (e.g., alternative prey), and anthropogenic factors (e.g., pesticides). Research has been carried out on larval parasitoids, showing potential for further development of sustainable control. The development of resistant tomato varieties is ongoing, but they are not commercially available yet. Knowledge gaps remain to be filled to optimize IPM packages on tomato crops and to help prevent further spread worldwide. &lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>