<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q55126919</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q55126919</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-018-25989-2</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Increasing densities of an invasive polychaete enhance bioturbation with variable effects on solute fluxes.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kauppi, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bernard, G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bastrop, R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Norkko, A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Norkko, Joanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-05-16</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>bioturbation</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractBioturbation is a key process affecting nutrient cycling in soft sediments. The invasive polychaete genus Marenzelleria spp. has established successfully throughout the Baltic Sea increasing species and functional diversity with possible density-dependent effects on bioturbation and associated solute fluxes. We tested the effects of increasing density of M. arctia, M. viridis and M. neglecta on bioturbation and solute fluxes in a laboratory experiment. Benthic communities in intact sediment cores were manipulated by adding increasing numbers of Marenzelleria spp. The results showed that Marenzelleria spp. in general enhanced all bioturbation metrics, but the effects on solute fluxes varied depending on the solute, on the density and species identity of Marenzelleria, and on the species and functional composition of the surrounding community. M. viridis and M. neglecta were more important in predicting variation in phosphate and silicate fluxes, whereas M. arctia had a larger effect on nitrogen cycling. The complex direct and indirect pathways indicate the importance of considering the whole community and not just species in isolation in the experimental studies. Including these interactions provides a way forward regarding our understanding of the complex ecosystem effects of invasive species.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>