<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111816703</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/BDJ.10.E81410</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>SLAM Project - Long Term Ecological Study of the Impacts of Climate Change in the Natural Forest of Azores: II - A survey of exotic arthropods in disturbed forest habitats</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Borges, Paulo A.V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lamelas-Lopez, Lucas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stüben, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ros-Prieto, Alejandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gabriel, Rosalina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boieiro, Mário</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tsafack, Noelline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ferreira, Maria Teresa</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-03-29</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>climate change</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The data we present consist of an inventory of exotic arthropods, potentially invasive, collected in exotic and mixed forests and disturbed native forest patches of the Azores Archipelago. The study was carried out between 2019 and 2020 in four islands: Corvo, Flores, Terceira and Santa Maria, where a total of 45 passive flight interception SLAM traps were deployed, during three to six consecutive months. This manuscript is the second contribution of the “SLAM Project - Long Term Ecological Study of the Impacts of Climate Change in the Natural Forest of Azores”.&lt;/jats:p&gt;
          &lt;jats:p&gt;We provide an inventory of terrestrial arthropods belonging to Arachnida, Diplopoda, Chilopoda and Insecta classes from four Azorean islands. We identified a total of 21,175 specimens, belonging to 20 orders, 93 families and 249 species of arthropods. A total of 125 species are considered introduced, 89 native non-endemic and 35 endemic. We registered 34 new records (nine for Corvo, three for Flores, six for Terceira and 16 for Santa Maria), of which five are new for Azores, being all exotic possibly recently introduced: &lt;jats:italic&gt;Dieckmanniellus nitidulus&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Gyllenhal, 1838), &lt;jats:italic&gt;Gronops fasciatus&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Küster, 1851, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Hadroplontus trimaculatus&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Fabricius, 1775), &lt;jats:italic&gt;Hypurus bertrandi&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Perris, 1852) (all Coleoptera, Curculionidae) and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Cardiocondyla mauritanica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Forel, 1890 (Hymenoptera, Formicidae). This publication highlights the importance of planted forests and disturbed native forest patches as reservoirs of potentially invasive arthropods and refuges for some rare relict endemic arthropod species.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>