<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114921503</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114921503</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.2298/GSF1205051G</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Quick-dip and contact method of cutting rooting of Zelkova carpinifolia (Pall.) K. Koch as an alternative non-invasive species</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Grbic, Mihailo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Skocajic, Dragana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Djukic, Matilda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Djunisijevic-Bojovic, Danijela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Obratov-Petkovic, Dragica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bjedov, Ivana</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012-07-02</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>National Library of Serbia</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Two methods of rooting of Zelkova softwood cuttings were analyzed: (1)
   quick-dip method and (2) contact method - the thin polyethylene film (20 mm)
   laid directly over the cuttings during the rooting process. The control for
   contact method was a low tunnel with a thick polyethylene film. One group of
   cuttings in the contact method was treated with quick-dip (IBA 2,500
   ?g?mL-1, carrier-ethyl alcohol) during 5 sec, and the other group was
   treated with water solution of IBA (50 ?g?mL-1) in 24-hour treatment. The
   third group was control - untreated cuttings. The same groups of cuttings
   were also used in low tunnels. The number and length of primary and
   secondary roots were measured on rooted cuttings. The results of all
   treatments show that contact method in combination with water solution of
   IBA was the best with 92% of rooted cuttings. No significant differences
   were obtained between this treatment and quick-dip + contact method (85.3%).
   Rooting of cuttings under low tunnel was significantly lower. In general,
   contact method was better than low tunnel, disregarding the carrier used.
   These results recommend the almost unknown contact method in nursery
   propagation of Zelkova, as an alternative, non-invasive species for the
   conditions in Serbia.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>