<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q63045331</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q63045331</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6405985</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-019-40321-2</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Inhibition of parasite invasion by monoclonal antibody against epidermal growth factor-like domain of Plasmodium vivax merozoite surface protein 1 paralog</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Han, Jin-Hee</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cheng, Yang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Muh, Fauzi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ahmed, Atique</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cho, Jee-Sun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nyunt, Myat Htut</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jeon, Hye-Yoon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ha, Kwon-Soo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Na, Sunghun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Park, Won Sun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hong, Seok-Ho</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shin, Ho-Joon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Russell, Bruce Malcolm</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Han, Eun-Taek</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-03-07</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>merozoite surface protein 1 paralog</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Plasmodium vivax</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractThe Plasmodium vivax merozoite surface protein 1 paralog (PvMSP1P), which has epidermal growth factor (EGF)-like domains, was identified as a novel erythrocyte adhesive molecule. This EGF-like domain (PvMSP1P-19) elicited high level of acquired immune response in patients. Antibodies against PvMSP1P significantly reduced erythrocyte adhesion activity to its unknown receptor. To determine PvMSP1P-19-specific antibody function and B-cell epitopes in vivax patients, five monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) and 18-mer peptides were generated. The mAb functions were determined by erythrocyte-binding inhibition assay and invasion inhibition assay with P. knowlesi. B-cell epitopes of PvMSP1P-19 domains were evaluated by peptide microarray. The pvmsp1p-19 sequences showed limited polymorphism in P. vivax worldwide isolates. The 1BH9-A10 showed erythrocyte binding inhibitory by interaction with the N-terminus of PvMSP1P-19, while this mAb failed to recognize PkMSP1P-19 suggesting the species-specific for P. vivax. Other mAbs showed cross-reactivity with PkMSP1P-19. Among them, the 2AF4-A2 and 2AF4-A6 mAb significantly reduced parasite invasion through C-terminal recognition. The linear B-cell epitope in naturally exposed P. vivax patient was identified at three linear epitopes. In this study, PvMSP1P-19 N-terminal-specific 1BH9-A10 and C-terminal-specific 2AF4 mAbs showed functional activity for epitope recognition suggesting that PvMSP1P may be useful for vaccine development strategy for specific single epitope to prevent P. vivax invasion.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>