<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q54990029</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q54990029</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5955948</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-018-26092-2</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Niche conservatism of Aedes albopictus and Aedes aegypti - two mosquito species with different invasion histories</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Cunze, Sarah</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kochmann, Judith</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koch, Lisa K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klimpel, Sven</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-05-16</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Aedes aegypti</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Asian tiger mosquito</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>niche conservatism</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractBiological invasions have been associated with niche changes; however, their occurrence is still debated. We assess whether climatic niches between native and non-native ranges have changed during the invasion process using two globally spread mosquitoes as model species, Aedes albopictus and Aedes aegypti. Considering the different time spans since their invasions (&gt;300 vs. 3040 years), niche changes were expected to be more likely for Ae. aegypti than for Ae. albopictus. We used temperature and precipitation variables as descriptors for the realized climatic niches and different niche metrics to detect niche dynamics in the native and non-native ranges. High niche stability, therefore, no niche expansion but niche conservatism was revealed for both species. High niche unfilling for Ae. albopictus indicates a great potential for further expansion. Highest niche occupancies in non-native ranges occurred either under more temperate (North America, Europe) or tropical conditions (South America, Africa). Aedes aegypti has been able to fill its native climatic niche in the non-native ranges, with very low unfilling. Our results challenge the assumption of rapid evolutionary change of climatic niches as a requirement for global invasions but support the use of native range-based niche models to project future invasion risk on a large scale.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>