<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q118143841</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q118143841</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/D14121019</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Spatial Distribution Pattern and Risk Assessment of Invasive Alien Plants on Southern Side of the Daba Mountain Area</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Yuanyuan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Deng, Hongping</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zuo, Youwei</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yang, Jun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yang, Yubing</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huang, Yan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Qin, Qi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yang, Chongyi</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-11-23</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The southern side of the Daba Mountain area is a hotspot of global biodiversity and an essential barrier promoting ecological security. However, knowledge about the distribution status and transmission pathways of invasive alien species (IAS) in this area is limited. We counted the IAS on the southern side of the Daba Mountain area through sample transects and analyzed the factors affecting their spatial distribution. We also assessed IAS risk using the analytic hierarchy process (AHP), which found 64 IAS belonging to 23 families and 53 genera. Around rivers and roads, the results showed a vertical two-way dispersal pattern. Human and environmental factors, such as a very dense transportation network, can affect the distribution pattern of IAS. AHP assessed 43 IAS (67.19%), primarily distributed in villages and towns, as being of high or medium risk. High- and medium-risk IAS should be the focus of invasion prevention and control, and priority should be given to controlling the spread of IAS around rivers and roads.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>