<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q104737240</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q104737240</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7761189</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.7717/PEERJ.10454</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Supraspecific units in correlative niche modeling improves the prediction of geographic potential of biological invasions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Castaño-Quintero, Sandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Escobar-Luján, Jazmín</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Osorio-Olvera, Luis</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peterson, Andrew Townsend</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chiappa-Carrara, Xavier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martínez-Meyer, Enrique</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yañez-Arenas, Carlos</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-12-22</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>PeerJ</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>
Background
Biological invasions rank among the most significant threats to biodiversity and ecosystems. Correlative ecological niche modeling is among the most frequently used tools with which to estimate potential distributions of invasive species. However, when areas accessible to the species across its native distribution do not represent the full spectrum of environmental conditions that the species can tolerate, correlative studies often underestimate fundamental niches.


Methods
Here, we explore the utility of supraspecific modeling units to improve the predictive ability of models focused on biological invasions. Taking into account phylogenetic relationships in correlative ecological niche models, we studied the invasion patterns of three species (Aedes aegypti, Pterois volitans and Oreochromis mossambicus).


Results
Use of supraspecific modeling units improved the predictive ability of correlative niche models in anticipating potential distributions of three invasive species. We demonstrated that integrating data on closely related species allowed a more complete characterization of fundamental niches. This approach could be used to model species with invasive potential but that have not yet invaded new regions.
</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>