<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110756338</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110756338</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/LIFE11060531</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Microsatellite Loci Reveal Genetic Diversity of Asian Callery Pear (Pyrus calleryana) in the Species Native Range and in the North American Cultivars</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sapkota, Shiwani</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boggess, Sarah L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trigiano, Robert N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klingeman, William E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hadziabdic, Denita</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Coyle, David R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olukolu, Bode A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuster, Ryan D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nowicki, Marcin</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-06-07</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>genetic diversity</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>native range</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pyrus calleryana</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Pyrus calleryana Decne. (Callery pear) includes cultivars that in the United States are popular ornamentals in commercial and residential landscapes. Last few decades, this species has increasingly naturalized across portions of the eastern and southern US. However, the mechanisms behind this plant’s spread are not well understood. The genetic relationship of present-day P.calleryana trees with their Asian P. calleryana forebears (native trees from China, Japan, and Korea) and the original specimens of US cultivars are unknown. We developed and used 18 microsatellite markers to analyze 147 Pyrus source samples and to articulate the status of genetic diversity within Asian P. calleryana and US cultivars. We hypothesized that Asian P. calleryana specimens and US cultivars would be genetically diverse and would show genetic relatedness. Our data revealed high genetic diversity, high gene flow, and presence of population structure in P. calleryana, potentially relating to the highly invasive capability of this species. Strong evidence for genetic relatedness between Asian P. calleryana specimens and US cultivars was also demonstrated. Our data suggest the source for P. calleryana that have become naturalized in US was China. These results will help understand the genetic complexity of invasive P. calleryana when developing management for escaped populations: In follow-up studies, we use the gSSRs developed here to analyze P. calleryana escape populations from across US.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>