<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q38480451</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3900453</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0086012</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Sequencing, De Novo assembly and annotation of the Colorado Potato Beetle, Leptinotarsa decemlineata, Transcriptome</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kumar, Abhishek</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Congiu, Leonardo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lindström, Leena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Piiroinen, Saija</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vidotto, Michele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grapputo, Alessandro</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2014-01-23</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>transcriptome</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Colorado potato beetle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>&lt;h4&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;The Colorado potato beetle (Leptinotarsa decemlineata) is a major pest and a serious threat to potato cultivation throughout the northern hemisphere. Despite its high importance for invasion biology, phenology and pest management, little is known about L. decemlineata from a genomic perspective. We subjected European L. decemlineata adult and larval transcriptome samples to 454-FLX massively-parallel DNA sequencing to characterize a basal set of genes from this species. We created a combined assembly of the adult and larval datasets including the publicly available midgut larval Roche 454 reads and provided basic annotation. We were particularly interested in diapause-specific genes and genes involved in pesticide and Bacillus thuringiensis (Bt) resistance.&lt;h4&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;Using 454-FLX pyrosequencing, we obtained a total of 898,048 reads which, together with the publicly available 804,056 midgut larval reads, were assembled into 121,912 contigs. We established a repository of genes of interest, with 101 out of the 108 diapause-specific genes described in Drosophila montana; and 621 contigs involved in insecticide resistance, including 221 CYP450, 45 GSTs, 13 catalases, 15 superoxide dismutases, 22 glutathione peroxidases, 194 esterases, 3 ADAM metalloproteases, 10 cadherins and 98 calmodulins. We found 460 putative miRNAs and we predicted a significant number of single nucleotide polymorphisms (29,205) and microsatellite loci (17,284).&lt;h4&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h4&gt;This report of the assembly and annotation of the transcriptome of L. decemlineata offers new insights into diapause-associated and insecticide-resistance-associated genes in this species and provides a foundation for comparative studies with other species of insects. The data will also open new avenues for researchers using L. decemlineata as a model species, and for pest management research. Our results provide the basis for performing future gene expression and functional analysis in L. decemlineata and improve our understanding of the biology of this invasive species at the molecular level.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>