<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111149997</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111149997</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/JMSE8110915</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Transition in Population Dynamics of the Intertidal Barnacle Balanus glandula after Invasion: Causes and Consequences of Change in Larval Supply</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Noda, Takashi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ohira, Masashi</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-11-17</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>population dynamics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Balanus glandula</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>To elucidate how the population dynamics of the acorn barnacle Balanus glandula transitioned after its invasion in 2000 along the Pacific coast of Japan, a population census was conducted from 2004 to 2014 at five shores along 49 km of coastline 144193 km east outside of the invasion front. Survey areas at each shore consisted of five paired plots (cleared recruitment plots and control plots). Larval recruitment was first detected in 2004 but benthic individuals were not detected until 2 years later. The abundance and occurrence of B. glandula increased until around 2010; abundance then decreased but occurrence remained high (70%) until 2014, suggesting that the metapopulation of this barnacle approached a maximum around 2011. From 2011, the population dynamics of B. glandula changed considerably at two contrasting spatial scales: at a regional scale, the dependency of the number of larvae on stock size decreased, whereas at a local scale, the relative contribution of larval supply as a determinant of local population dynamics decreased. These findings suggest that the major driving force of population dynamics of the introduced barnacle changed in just a few years after invasion; therefore, population census data from just after an invasion, including larval recruitment monitoring just outside the invasion front, is essential to understanding invasion dynamics by sessile marine organisms.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>