<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114922678</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114922678</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.17816/SNV201873114</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive species of Asteraceae family in Kursk flora</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nagornaya, Olga Vyacheslavovna</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-08-15</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Asteraceae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Samara State University of Social Sciences and Education</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The paper deals with biological features and quantitative characteristics of populations of some invasive species of the family Asteraceae in Kursk flora and their distribution. Kursk, being the industrial and administrative center of the Kursk Region, is characterized by a strong degree of flora transformation, as a result of the active transformation of the territory in recent years, which determines the suitable conditions for the introduction of invasive species and their wide distribution. In Kursk flora there are 43 invasive species, the proportion of Asteraceae is 21%. The paper presents biological features and characteristics of Xanthium albinum and Cyclachaena xanthiifolia populations. The following population indicators were studied: number of individuals, height and total projective cover. It was revealed that the populations of Xanthium albinum in different growing conditions show significant differences in the studied parameters. In the populations of Cyclachaena xanthiifolia fluctuations were observed in the number of individuals per 1 m. The reasons that determine the parameters of populations of invasive species is the degree of disturbance and shading. The study of urban vegetation is a necessary step in the development of measures to optimize the urban environment. The obtained materials will allow to evaluate the consequences of the introduction of these invasive species in the plant communities of Kursk and will provide a scientific basis for monitoring in order to prevent biological invasions.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>