<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111154780</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3389/FPLS.2021.643425</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Can the Non-native Salt Marsh Halophyte Spartina alterniflora Threaten Native Seagrass (Zostera japonica) Habitats? A Case Study in the Yellow River Delta, China</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Yue, Shidong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhou, Yi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xu, Shaochun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Xiaomei</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, Mingjie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Qiao, Yongliang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gu, Ruiting</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xu, Shuai</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Yu</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-05-20</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Spartina alterniflora</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Zostera japonica</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>halophyte</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>salt marsh</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Frontiers Media SA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Seagrass meadows are critical ecosystems, and they are among the most threatened habitats on the planet. As an anthropogenic biotic invader, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Spartina alterniflora&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Loisel. competes with native plants, threatens native ecosystems and coastal aquaculture, and may cause local biodiversity to decline. The distribution area of the exotic species &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. alterniflora&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in the Yellow River Delta had been expanding to ca.4,000 ha from 1990 to 2018. In this study, we reported, for the first time, the competitive effects of the exotic plant (&lt;jats:italic&gt;S. alterniflora&lt;/jats:italic&gt;) on seagrass (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Zostera japonica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Asch. &amp;amp; Graebn.) by field investigation and a transplant experiment in the Yellow River Delta. Within the first 3 months of the field experiment, &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. alterniflora&lt;/jats:italic&gt; had pushed forward 14 m into the &lt;jats:italic&gt;Z. japonica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; distribution region. In the study region, the area of &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. alterniflora&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in 2019 increased by 516 times compared with its initial area in 2015. Inhibition of &lt;jats:italic&gt;Z. japonica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; growth increased with the invasion of &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. alterniflora&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;Z. japonica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; had been degrading significantly under the pressure of &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. alterniflora&lt;/jats:italic&gt; invasion. &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. alterniflora&lt;/jats:italic&gt; propagates sexually via seeds for long distance invasion and asexually by tillers and rhizomes for short distance invasion. Our results describe the invasion pattern of &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. alterniflora&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and can be used to develop strategies for prevention and control of &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. alterniflora&lt;/jats:italic&gt; invasion.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>