<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q46304544</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q46304544</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1111/MEC.14353</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Selection on a behaviour-related gene during the first stages of the biological invasion pathway.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mueller, Jakob C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Edelaar, Pim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baños-Villalba, Adrián</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carrete, Martina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Potti, Jaime</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blas, Julio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tella, Jose Luis</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kempenaers, Bart</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-09-19</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Human-induced biological invasions are common worldwide and often have negative impacts on wildlife and human societies. Several studies have shown evidence for selection on invaders after introduction to the new range. However, selective processes already acting prior to introduction have been largely neglected. Here, we tested whether such early selection acts on known behaviour-related gene variants in the yellow-crowned bishop (Euplectes afer), a pet-traded African songbird. We tested for nonrandom allele frequency changes after trapping, acclimation and survival in captivity. We also compared the native source population with two independent invasive populations. Allele frequencies of two SNPs in the dopamine receptor D4 (DRD4) gene-known to be linked to behavioural activity in response to novelty in this species-significantly changed over all early invasion stages. They also differed between the African native population and the two invading European populations. The two-locus genotype associated with reduced activity declined consistently, but strongest at the trapping stage. Overall genetic diversity did not substantially decrease, and there is little evidence for new alleles in the introduced populations, indicating that selection at the DRD4 gene predominantly worked on the standing genetic variation already present in the native population. Our study demonstrates selection on a behaviour-related gene during the first stages of a biological invasion. Thus, pre-establishment stages of a biological invasion do not only determine the number of propagules that are introduced (their quantity), but also their phenotypic and genetic characteristics (their quality).</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>