<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q41549854</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q41549854</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5575248</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-017-10231-2</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Microbial communities in marine sediments modify success of an invasive macrophyte</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gribben, Paul E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Shaun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seymour, Justin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bradley, Daniel J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>West, Matthew N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomas, Torsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-08-29</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>macrophyte</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive macrophyte</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>marine sediment</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractInvasive plants have extensive impacts on ecosystem function and biodiversity globally. Our inability to manage invasive species stems in part from a lack of understanding of the processes that control their successful establishment and spread. To date, studies have largely considered how above-ground processes control native/invasive plant interactions. Emerging research from terrestrial and wetland ecosystems demonstrates that below-ground processes under microbial control can determine the outcome of interactions between native and invasive plants. Whether sediment microbes modify the success of invasive macrophytes in marine ecosystems is untested, despite marine sediment microbes controlling many ecological processes (e.g. nutrient cycling) comparable to those in terrestrial ecosystems. We first show that sediment bacterial communities differ between the native seagrass Zostera capricorni and the invasive alga Caulerpa taxifolia and that those differences relate to functional changes in sulfur cycling between the macrophytes. Second, by experimentally manipulating the microbial communities we show that intact microbial communities in Z. capricorni sediments provide biotic resistance by reducing C. taxifolia fragment growth 119% compared to when they are inactive, and intact microbial communities in C. taxifolia sediments have positive feedbacks by increasing fragment growth 200%. Thus, similar to terrestrial ecosystems, microorganisms appear to indirectly control the success of invasive macrophytes in marine ecosystems.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>