<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q33887886</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0178577</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Population-based incidence, seasonality and serotype distribution of invasive salmonellosis among children in Nanoro, rural Burkina Faso</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Guiraud, Issa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Post, Annelies</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diallo, Seydou Nakanabo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lompo, Palpouguini</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maltha, Jessica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thriemer, Kamala</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tahita, Christian Marc</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ley, Benedikt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Derra, Karim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bottieau, Emmanuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kazienga, Adama</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schurmans, Céline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ravinetto, Raffaella</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rouamba, Eli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Van Griensven, Johan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bertrand, Sophie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tinto, Halidou</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jacobs, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-07-10</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Burkina Faso</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;h4&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;Bloodstream infections (BSI) caused by Salmonella Typhi and invasive non-Typhoidal Salmonella (iNTS) frequently affect children living in rural sub-Saharan Africa but data about incidence and serotype distribution are rare.&lt;h4&gt;Objective&lt;/h4&gt;The present study assessed the population-based incidence of Salmonella BSI and severe malaria in a Health and Demographic Surveillance System in a rural area with seasonal malaria transmission in Nanoro, Burkina Faso.&lt;h4&gt;Methods&lt;/h4&gt;Children between 2 months-15 years old with severe febrile illness were enrolled during a one-year surveillance period (May 2013-May 2014). Thick blood films and blood cultures were sampled and processed upon admission. Population-based incidences were corrected for non-referral, health seeking behavior, non-inclusion and blood culture sensitivity. Adjusted incidence rates were expressed per 100,000 person-years of observations (PYO).&lt;h4&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;Among children &lt; 5 years old, incidence rates for iNTS, Salmonella Typhi and severe malaria per 100,000 PYO were 4,138 (95% Confidence Interval (CI): 3,740-4,572), 224 (95% CI: 138-340) and 2,866 (95% CI: 2,538-3,233) respectively. Among those aged 5-15 years, corresponding incidence rates were 25 (95% CI: 8-60), 273 (95% CI: 203-355) and 135 (95% CI: 87-195) respectively. Most iNTS occurred during the peak of the rainy season and in parallel with the increase of Plasmodium falciparum malaria; for Salmonella Typhi no clear seasonal pattern was observed. Salmonella Typhi and iNTS accounted for 13.3% and 55.8% of all 118 BSI episodes; 71.6% of iNTS (48/67) isolates were Salmonella enterica serovar Typhimurium and 25.4% (17/67) Salmonella enterica serovar Enteritidis; there was no apparent geographical clustering.&lt;h4&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;The present findings from rural West-Africa confirm high incidences of Salmonella Typhi and iNTS, the latter with a seasonal and Plasmodium falciparum-related pattern. It urges prioritization of the development and implementation of Salmonella Typhi as well as iNTS vaccines in this setting.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>