<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114921499</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114921499</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.2298/GSF1205189T</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Public attitude in the city of Belgrade towards invasive alien plant species</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tomicevic, Jelena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grbic, Mihailo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Skocajic, Dragana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Radovanovic, Dragana</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012-07-02</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>National Library of Serbia</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Biological invasions are seen as a major threat to biodiversity at a global
   level, while the number of new invasions is increasing at an alarming rate.
   Raising the awareness of the public, academic world and policy makers about
   the dangers caused by invasive species, is essential for the creation of the
   support needed to implement and coordinate the policies necessary to address
   this problem. The aim of this study is to determine the level of local public
   awareness of the existence of these plant species, examine the public
   attitude towards alien invasive plant species and willingness to get involved
   in the prevention of their spreading. The survey was conducted in four
   nurseries on the territory of the City of Belgrade and the investigation
   dealt only with alien invasive woody plant species. Thirty customers were
   questioned in each of the four nurseries. The results show that local public
   is uninformed on the issue of invasive plant species. It is necessary to
   constantly and intensively raise their awareness of this issue, as well as
   the awareness of harmful consequences that may occur due to the uncontrolled
   spreading of alien invasive species. This refers not only to the population
   that visits the nurseries and buys the plants there and to those employed in
   plant production and selling, but also to the whole local public and decision
   makers.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>