<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q100465701</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/ZOOKEYS.970.54801</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Exotic-looking Neotropical Tischeriidae (Lepidoptera) and their host plants</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stonis, Jonas R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diškus, Arūnas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Remeikis, Andrius</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Solis, Maria Alma</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Katinas, Liliana</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-09-21</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Lepidoptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tischeriidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Seven new species of Tischeriidae are described from the Neotropics: &lt;jats:italic&gt;Astrotischeria jociui&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Diškus &amp;amp; Stonis, &lt;jats:bold&gt;sp. nov.&lt;/jats:bold&gt; (feeding on &lt;jats:italic&gt;Wissadula excelsior&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Cav.) C. Presl., Malvaceae), &lt;jats:italic&gt;A. atlantica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Diškus &amp;amp; Stonis, &lt;jats:bold&gt;sp. nov.&lt;/jats:bold&gt; (feeding on &lt;jats:italic&gt;Baccharis spicata&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Lam.) Baill., Asteraceae), &lt;jats:italic&gt;A. cornuata&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Diškus &amp;amp; Stonis, &lt;jats:bold&gt;sp. nov.&lt;/jats:bold&gt; (host plant unknown), &lt;jats:italic&gt;Paratischeria guarani&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Diškus &amp;amp; Stonis, &lt;jats:bold&gt;sp. nov.&lt;/jats:bold&gt; (feeding on &lt;jats:italic&gt;Elephantopus mollis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Kunth, Asteraceae), &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. mesoamericana&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Diškus &amp;amp; Stonis, &lt;jats:bold&gt;sp. nov.&lt;/jats:bold&gt; (feeding on &lt;jats:italic&gt;Montanoa hibiscifolia&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Benth., Asteraceae), &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. suprafasciata&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Diškus &amp;amp; Stonis, &lt;jats:bold&gt;sp. nov.&lt;/jats:bold&gt; (feeding on &lt;jats:italic&gt;Allophyllus edulis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (A. St.-Hil., A. Juss. &amp;amp; Cambess.) Hieron. ex Niederl., Sapindaceae), and &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. braziliensis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Diškus &amp;amp; Stonis, &lt;jats:bold&gt;sp. nov.&lt;/jats:bold&gt; (host plant unknown). Additionally, an updated distribution map of &lt;jats:italic&gt;Paratischeria neotropicana&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Diškus &amp;amp; Stonis, 2015), which currently has the broadest distribution range among the Neotropical Tischeriidae is provided along with new host-plant data, a list of all recorded host plants in the Neotropics, and a brief discussion on trophic relationships of Tischeriidae. It is hypothesized that host-plant distribution ranges can provide clues to potential distribution ranges of these specialized, monophagous or oligophagous, leaf miners. All new taxa are illustrated with photographs of the adults, their genitalia, and, if available, leaf mines.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>