<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111154521</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111154521</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/ANI11072018</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Comparison of the Genetic Structure of Invasive Bigheaded Carp (Hypophthalmichthys spp.) Populations in Central-European Lacustrine and Riverine Habitats</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Molnár, Tamás</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lehoczky, István</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meleg, Erika Edviné</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boros, Gergely</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Specziár, András</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mozsár, Attila</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vitál, Zoltán</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Józsa, Vilmos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Allele, Wahiba</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Urbányi, Béla</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fatle, Fatema Ali Al</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kovács, Balázs</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-07-06</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Bigheaded carps (bighead carp, Hypophthalmichthys molitrix, and silver carp, Hypophthalmichthys nobilis) and their hybrids play an important ecological and economic role in their original habitat, while their introduced stocks may pose serious ecological risks. To address questions about the persistence and invasiveness of these fish, we need to better understand their population structures. The genetic structures of bigheaded carp populations inhabiting Lake Balaton and the Tisza River were examined with ten microsatellite markers and a mitochondrial DNA marker (COI). The Lake Balaton stock showed higher genetic diversity compared with the Tisza River stock. Based on hierarchical clustering, the Tisza population was characterized only by only silver carps, while the Balaton stock included hybrid and silver carp individuals. All COI haplotypes originated from the Yangtze River. Based on the high genomic and mitochondrial diversity, along with the significant deviation from H–W equilibrium and the lack of evidence of bottleneck effect, it can be assumed that bigheaded carps do not reproduce in Lake Balaton. The present stock in Balaton may have originated from repeated introductions and escapes from the surrounding fishponds. The Tisza stock consists solely of silver carp individuals. This stock appears to have significant reproductive potential and may become invasive if environmental factors change due to climate change.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>