<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q38253056</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1155/2014/386470</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Newcastle disease virus interaction in targeted therapy against proliferation and invasion pathways of glioblastoma multiforme</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Abdullah, Jafri M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mustafa, Zulkifli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ideris, Aini</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2014-08-27</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>glioblastoma</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>brain tumor</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Newcastle disease virus</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>targeted therapy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Newcastle disease</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Glioblastoma multiforme (GBM), or grade IV glioma, is one of the most lethal forms of human brain cancer. Current bioscience has begun to depict more clearly the signalling pathways that are responsible for high-grade glioma initiation, migration, and invasion, opening the door for molecular-based targeted therapy. As such, the application of viruses such as Newcastle disease virus (NDV) as a novel biological bullet to specifically target aberrant signalling in GBM has brought new hope. The abnormal proliferation and aggressive invasion behaviour of GBM is reported to be associated with aberrant Rac1 protein signalling. NDV interacts with Rac1 upon viral entry, syncytium induction, and actin reorganization of the infected cell as part of the replication process. Ultimately, intracellular stress leads the infected glioma cell to undergo cell death. In this review, we describe the characteristics of malignant glioma and the aberrant genetics that drive its aggressive phenotype, and we focus on the use of oncolytic NDV in GBM-targeted therapy and the interaction of NDV in GBM signalling that leads to inhibition of GBM proliferation and invasion, and subsequently, cell death.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>