<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q108540266</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q108540266</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/PLANTS10040773</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive Plant Species Distribution Is Structured by Soil and Habitat Type in the City Landscape</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Szumaska, Ilona</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lubiska-Mieliska, Sandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kamiski, Dariusz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rutkowski, Lucjan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nienartowicz, Andrzej</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Piernik, Agnieszka</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-04-15</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>IAS</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Alien Species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>habitat type</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>species distribution</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive alien species (IAS) is a global problem that largely relates to human activities and human settlements. To prevent the further spread of IAS, we first need to know their pattern of distribution, to determine which constitutes the greatest threat, and understand which habitats and migration pathways they prefer. Our research aimed to identify the main vectors and distribution pattern of IAS of plants in the city environment. We checked the relations between species distribution and such environmental factors as urban soil type and habitat type. We applied data on IAS occurrence (collected in the period 19732015) in 515 permanent plots with dimensions of 0.5 × 0.5 km and analyzed by direct ordination methods. In total, we recorded 66 IAS. We found a 27% variance in the IAS distribution pattern, which can be explained by statistically significant soil and habitat types. The most important for species distribution were: river and alluvial soils, forests and related rusty soils, and places of intensive human activities, including areas of urbisols and industriosols. Our results provide details that can inform local efforts for the management and control of invasive species, and they provide evidence of the different associations between natural patterns and human land use.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>