<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114728721</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114728721</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.77.83205</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>_Complex origins indicate a potential bridgehead introduction of an emerging amphibian invader (Eleutherodactylus planirostris) in China</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hong, Yanhua</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He, Yanhong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lin, Zhiqiang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Du, Yuanbao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chen, Shengnan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Han, Lixia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Qing</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gu, Shimin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tu, Weishan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hu, Shengwei</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yuan, Zhiyong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, Xuan</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-10-14</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Eleutherodactylus planirostris</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Identifying the origins of established alien species is important to prevent new introductions in the future. The greenhouse frog (Eleutherodactylus planirostris), native to Cuba, the Bahamas, and the Cayman Islands, has been widely introduced to the Caribbean, North and Central America, Oceania and Asia. This invasive alien amphibian was recently reported in Shenzhen, China, but the potential introduction sources remain poorly understood. Based on phylogenetic analysis using mitochondrial 16S, COI and CYTB sequences, we detected a complex introduction origin of this species, which may be from Hong Kong, China, the Philippines, Panama and Florida, USA, all pointing to a bridgehead introduction. In addition, the nursery trade between the four countries or regions and mainland China from 2011 to 2020 was also significantly higher than other areas with less likelihood of introductions, which supported the molecular results. Our study provides the first genetic evidence of the potential sources of this emerging amphibian invader in mainland China, which may help develop alien species control strategies in the face of growing trade through globalization.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>