<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q46247362</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5717255</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-017-17169-5</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Germination Biology of Two Invasive Physalis Species and Implications for Their Management in Arid and Semi-arid Regions.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ozaslan, Cumali</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Farooq, Shahid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Onen, Huseyin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ozcan, Selcuk</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bukun, Bekir</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gunal, Hikmet</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-12-05</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Two Solanaceae invasive plant species (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Physalis angulata&lt;/jats:italic&gt; L. and &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. philadelphica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Lam. var. &lt;jats:italic&gt;immaculata&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Waterfall) infest several arable crops and natural habitats in Southeastern Anatolia region, Turkey. However, almost no information is available regarding germination biology of both species. We performed several experiments to infer the effects of environmental factors on seed germination and seedling emergence of different populations of both species collected from various locations with different elevations and habitat characteristics. Seed dormancy level of all populations was decreased with increasing age of the seeds. Seed dormancy of freshly harvested and aged seeds of all populations was effectively released by running tap water. Germination was slightly affected by photoperiods, which suggests that seeds are slightly photoblastic. All seeds germinated under wide range of temperature (15–40 °C), pH (4–10), osmotic potential (0 to −1.2 MPa) and salinity (0–400 mM sodium chloride) levels. The germination ability of both plant species under wide range of environmental conditions suggests further invasion potential towards non-infested areas in the country. Increasing seed burial depth significantly reduced the seedling emergence, and seeds buried below 4 cm of soil surface were unable to emerge. In arable lands, soil inversion to maximum depth of emergence (i.e., 6 cm) followed by conservational tillage could be utilized as a viable management option.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>