<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q28596549</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q28596549</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/SREP36089</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Mitochondrial genomes and comparative genomics of Aphanomyces astaci and Aphanomyces invadans</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Makkonen, Jenny</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vesterbacka, Arto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martin, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jussila, Japo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diéguez-Uribeondo, Javier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kortet, Raine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kokko, Harri</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-11-03</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Aphanomyces astaci</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>genomics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>comparative genomics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Aphanomyces invadans</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractThe genus Aphanomyces (Saprolegniales, Oomycetes) includes species with a variety of ecologies from saprotrophs to plant and animal parasites. Two important species in this genus are A. astaci, the cause of crayfish plague and its close relative, A. invadans, which causes the epizootic ulcerative syndrome on fish. In this study, we have assembled and annotated the mitochondrial (mt) genomes of A. astaci and A. invadans from the whole genome shotgun sequence reads (PRJNA187372; PRJNA258292, respectively). The assembly was generated from A. astaci Pc-genotype strain APO3 and A. invadans strain NJM9701. The sizes of the mtDNAs were 49,489_bp and 49,061_bp for A. astaci and A. invadans, respectively. The species shared similar genetic content and organization encoding 35 proteins, two ribosomal RNAs, three putative open reading frames and 33 transfer RNAs of 19 amino acids for peptide synthesis. Both species also had a large inverted repeat region (LIR) of approximately 12_kb, the LIR contained large and small ribosomal RNAs and eight protein coding genes. These annotated mt genomes serve as a valuable genetic backbone for further development of diagnostic methods and phylogenetic and migration studies of the animal parasitic species of Aphanomyces.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>