<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q120798812</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q120798812</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.84.95761</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>_Awareness, detection and management of new and emerging tree pests and pathogens in Europe: stakeholders’ perspectives</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Green, Samantha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dehnen-Schmutz, Katharina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Drakulic, Jassy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eschen, René</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Orazio, Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Douma, Jacob C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lundén, Karl</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Colombari, Fernanda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jactel, Hervé</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-05-18</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Emerging and invasive tree pests and pathogens in Europe are increasing in number and range, having impacts on biodiversity, forest services, ecosystems and human well-being. Stakeholders involved in tree and forest management contribute to the detection and management of new and emerging tree pests and pathogens (PnPs). We surveyed different groups of stakeholders in European countries. The stakeholders were mainly researchers, tree health surveyors and forest managers, as well as forest owners, nurseries, policy-makers, advisors, forestry authorities, NGOs and civil society. We investigated which tools they used to detect and manage PnPs, surveyed their current PnP awareness and knowledge and collated the new and emerging PnP species of concern to them. The 237 respondents were based in 15 European countries, with the majority from the United Kingdom, France and the Czech Republic. There was a strong participation of respondents with a work focus on research and surveying, whereas timber traders and plant importers were less represented. Respondents were surveyed on 18 new, emerging PnPs in Europe and listed an additional 37 pest species and 21 pathogen species as potential future threats. We found that species on EPPO’s list of ‘priority pests’ were better known than those not listed. Stakeholders working in urban environments were more aware of PnPs compared to those working in rural areas. Stakeholders’ awareness of PnPs was not related to the number of new, emerging PnP species present in a country.
          Stakeholders want access to more detection and management tools, including long-term citizen-science monitoring, maps showing spread and range of new PnPs, pest identification smartphone apps, hand-held detection devices, drone monitoring and eDNA metabarcoding. To help facilitate better forest health across Europe, they called for mixed forest development, reduced nursery stock movement, biosecurity and data sharing amongst organisations. These results indicate that stakeholder knowledge of a few key PnP may be good, but given that the large diversity of threats is so large and future risks unknown, we conclude that multiple and varied methods for generic detection, mitigation and management methods, many in development, are needed in the hands of stakeholders surveying and managing trees and woodlands in Europe.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>