<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110757117</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S10530-019-02114-6</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Impact of the invasive alien topmouth gudgeon (Pseudorasbora parva) and its associated parasite Sphaerothecum destruens on native fish species</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Spikmans, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lemmers, Pim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Camp, Huub J. M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haren, Emiel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kappen, Florian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blaakmeer, Anko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Velde, Gerard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Langevelde, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leuven, Rob S. E. W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alen, Theo A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-11-12</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pseudorasbora parva</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;
              &lt;jats:p&gt;The Asian cyprinid &lt;jats:italic&gt;Pseudorasbora parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt; is considered to be a major threat to native fish communities and listed as an invasive alien species of European Union concern. Our study aims to gain evidence-based knowledge on the impact of both &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and its parasite &lt;jats:italic&gt;Sphaerothecum destruens&lt;/jats:italic&gt; on native fish populations by analysing fish assemblages and body condition of individuals of native fish species in floodplain water bodies that were invaded and uninvaded by &lt;jats:italic&gt;P&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. We explored the use of environmental DNA (eDNA) techniques to detect &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. destruens&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. Prevalence of &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. destruens&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in native fish species was assessed. Fish samplings showed significantly negative correlations between the abundance of &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and the native &lt;jats:italic&gt;Leucaspius delineatus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Pungitius pungitius&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and three biodiversity indices of the fish assemblages (Simpson’s diversity index, Shannon–Wiener index and evenness). Contrastingly, the abundances of the native &lt;jats:italic&gt;Gasterosteus aculeatus&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt; were positively related. In nearly all isolated water bodies with &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, this species is outnumbering native fish species. No effect of &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt; presence was found on body condition of native fish species. &lt;jats:italic&gt;Sphaerothecum destruens&lt;/jats:italic&gt; was demonstrated to occur in both &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;G. aculeatus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;Gasterosteus aculeatus&lt;/jats:italic&gt; is suggested to be an asymptomatic carrier that can aid the further spread of &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. destruens.&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Analysis of eDNA proved to be a promising method for early detection of &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. destruens&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, here showing that &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. destruens&lt;/jats:italic&gt; presence coincided with &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt; presence. The ongoing invasion of both &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. destruens&lt;/jats:italic&gt; is predicted to pose a significant risk to native fish communities.
&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>