<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q97077924</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q97077924</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7522108</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S00267-020-01325-1</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Steam and Flame Applications as Novel Methods of Population Control for Invasive Asian Clam (Corbicula fluminea) and Zebra Mussel (Dreissena polymorpha)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Coughlan, Neil</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cunningham, Eoghan M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Potts, Stephen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McSweeney, Diarmuid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Healey, Emma</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dick, Jaimie T A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vong, Gina Y W</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Crane, Kate</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Caffrey, Joe M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lucy, Frances E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Davis, Eithne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cuthbert, Ross N</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-07-05</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>zebra mussel</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Corbicula fluminea</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract
Control strategies for established populations of invasive alien species can be costly and complex endeavours, which are frequently unsuccessful. Therefore, rapid-reaction techniques that are capable of maximising efficacy whilst minimising environmental damage are urgently required. The Asian clam (Corbicula fluminea Müller, 1774), and the zebra mussel (Dreissena polymorpha Pallas, 1771), are invaders capable of adversely affecting the functioning and biodiversity of freshwater ecosystems. Despite efforts to implement substantial population-control measures, both species continue to spread and persist within freshwater environments. As bivalve beds often become exposed during low-water conditions, this study examined the efficacy of steam-spray (≥100_°C, 350_kPa) and open-flame burn treatments (~1000_°C) to kill exposed individuals. Direct steam exposure lasting for 5_min caused 100% mortality of C. fluminea buried at a depth of 3_cm. Further, combined rake and thermal shock treatments, whereby the substrate is disturbed between each application of either a steam or open flame, caused 100% mortality of C. fluminea specimens residing within a 4-cm deep substrate patch, following three consecutive treatment applications. However, deeper 8-cm patches and water-saturated substrate reduced maximum bivalve species mortality rates to 77% and 70%, respectively. Finally, 100% of D. polymorpha specimens were killed following exposure to steam and open-flame treatments lasting for 30_s and 5_s, respectively. Overall, our results confirm the efficacy of thermal shock treatments as a potential tool for substantial control of low-water-exposed bivalves. Although promising, our results require validation through upscaling to field application, with consideration of other substrate types, increased substrate depth, greater bivalve densities, non-target and long-term treatment effects.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>