<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q97592568</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q97592568</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/ZOOKEYS.944.51395</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Trioxys liui Chou &amp; Chou, 1993 (Hymenoptera, Braconidae, Aphidiinae): an invasive aphid parasitoid attacking invasive Takecallis species (Hemiptera, Aphididae) in the Iberian Peninsula</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rakhshani, Ehsan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saval, Jose Michelena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hidalgo, Nicolas Pérez</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pons, Xavier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kavallieratos, Nickolas G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Starý, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-06-30</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Hymenoptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Braconidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hemiptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Trioxys liui</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Aphididae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Biological invasion of aphids and other insects has been increased due to long distance commercial transportation of plant material. The bamboo-aphid-parasitoid association is strictly specific and even though it does not develop interactions with the local environment it should be listed as part of the fauna of southwestern Europe. On-going research regarding aphids and their aphidiine parasitoids in Spain has yielded a new association ofTrioxys liuiChou &amp;amp; Chou, 1993 with an undescribed species ofTakecallisaphids on bamboo,Phyllostachysspp. Here we present the first association ofT. liuiwith aphids of the genusTakecallisthat attack bamboos.Trioxys liuiis known as a parasitoid ofCranaphis formosana(Takahashi, 1924) andPhyllaphoides bambusicolaTakahashi, 1921 on bamboos in China and Russia. The accidental introduction of this parasitoid species to southwestern Europe has been probably realized through transportation of contaminated bamboo plant material. In the current study, a new host association is recorded forT. liui. Its potential to invade other bamboo-associated aphids and the significance of the tritrophic bamboo-aphid-parasitoid interactions in the new environments are also discussed.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>