<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114917933</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114917933</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/F11070752</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Machinability Research of the Most Common Invasive Tree Species in Slovenia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Merhar, Miran</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bučar, Dominika Gornik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Merela, Maks</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-07-12</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive tree</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>This article investigates the quality of the machining surface of the five most common invasive tree species in Slovenia, i.e., black locust (Robinia pseudoacacia L.), boxelder maple (Acer negundo L.), horse chestnut (Aesculus hippocastanum), honey locust (Gleditsia triacanthos) and tree of heaven (Ailanthus altissima). The machining tests were made according to the American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) D1666-17 standard, where the quality of the surfaces after planing, routing and turning were evaluated with visual assessment, and the area and profile roughness parameters were also determined on selected specimens. The results showed that boxelder maple, horse chestnut and honey locust can be machined very well in all the studied operations, with the best results in routing and a little less good by turning, whereas the tree of heaven had the best quality in planing, and the worst by turning. Among all studied tree species, the black locust had the worst quality in planing, but the quality at routing was very similar to other tested species. The research also showed that there is little or no significant relationship between the qualities of the various types of machining for tested tree species.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>