<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q30391452</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q30391452</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/SREP20424</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive floating macrophytes reduce greenhouse gas emissions from a small tropical lake</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Attermeyer, K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Flury, S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jayakumar, R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fiener, P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steger, Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arya, V</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wilken, Florian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Geldern, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Premke, K</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-02-05</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>greenhouse gas</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>lake</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>macrophyte</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractFloating macrophytes, including water hyacinth (Eichhornia crassipes), are dominant invasive organisms in tropical aquatic systems and they may play an important role in modifying the gas exchange between water and the atmosphere. However, these systems are underrepresented in global datasets of greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. This study investigated the carbon (C) turnover and GHG emissions from a small (0.6_km2) water-harvesting lake in South India and analysed the effect of floating macrophytes on these emissions. We measured carbon dioxide (CO2) and methane (CH4) emissions with gas chambers in the field as well as water C mineralization rates and physicochemical variables in both the open water and in water within stands of water hyacinths. The CO2 and CH4 emissions from areas covered by water hyacinths were reduced by 57% compared with that of open water. However, the C mineralization rates were not significantly different in the water between the two areas. We conclude that the increased invasion of water hyacinths and other floating macrophytes has the potential to change GHG emissions, a process that might be relevant in regional C budgets.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>