<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110531292</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1051/KMAE/2020018</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Population dynamics and feeding ecology of the invasive Caucasian dwarf goby, Knipowitschia caucasica, in a freshwater habitat in Ukraine</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Didenko, Alexander</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Buzevych, Igor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Volikov, Yuriy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kruzhylina, Svitlana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gurbyk, Alexander</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Ukraine</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Caucasian dwarf goby</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>population dynamics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>freshwater ecology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>EDP Sciences</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Population dynamics and feeding patterns of invasive &lt;jats:italic&gt;Knipowitschia caucasica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; were studied in the littoral zone of the lower Stugna River. The abundances of this goby showed significant inter-annual and seasonal fluctuations. The studied population of &lt;jats:italic&gt;K. caucasica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; was represented by two age groups (0 and I). Fish die after their first breeding season. In total, 58 prey items were identified in the diet of &lt;jats:italic&gt;K. caucasica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; at the sampling site. The most abundant prey were copepods and cladocerans, while the most frequently encountered prey were copepods and chironomid larvae. Copepods were represented mainly by Cyclopoidae. Cladocerans included 21 taxa, among which the most abundant were &lt;jats:italic&gt;Diaphanosoma&lt;/jats:italic&gt; sp., &lt;jats:italic&gt;Acroperus harpae&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Disparalona rostrata&lt;/jats:italic&gt;; chironomids included 22 taxa, among which the most abundant was &lt;jats:italic&gt;Cricotopus sylvestris&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. The diet composition showed seasonal dynamics, where copepods predominated in January to April and in August-September, chironomid larvae were especially important in May to July, while cladocerans were most important in November-December. The relatively high diversity of both phytophilous and open-bottom-dwelling prey organisms in the stomach contents of &lt;jats:italic&gt;K. caucasica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; indicates that this species fed on a large variety of benthic habitats including among macrophytes and open areas.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>