<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111313193</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/JOF8020189</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Coffee Leaf Rust (&lt;i&gt;Hemileia vastatrix&lt;/i&gt;) from the Recent Invasion into Hawaii Shares a Genotypic Relationship with Latin American Populations</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ramírez-Camejo, Luis A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keith, Lisa M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Matsumoto, Tracie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sugiyama, Lionel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fukada, Mach</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brann, Mia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moffitt, Ariana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, Jingyu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aime, Mary Catherine</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-02-15</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Hemileia vastatrix</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Hawaii has long been one of the last coffee-producing regions of the world free of coffee leaf rust (CLR) disease, which is caused by the biotrophic fungus Hemileia vastatrix. However, CLR was detected in coffee farms and feral coffee on the island of Maui in February 2020 and subsequently on other islands of the Hawaiian archipelago. The source of the outbreak in Hawaii is not known, and CLR could have entered Hawaii from more than 50 coffee-producing nations that harbor the pathogen. To determine the source(s) of the Hawaii inoculum, we analyzed a set of eleven simple sequence repeat markers (SSRs) generated from Hawaii isolates within a dataset of 434 CLR isolates collected from 17 countries spanning both old and new world populations, and then conducted a minimum spanning network (MSN) analysis to trace the most likely pathway that H. vastatrix could have taken to Hawaii. Forty-two multilocus genotypes (MLGs) of H. vastatrix were found in the global dataset, with all isolates from Hawaii assignable to MLG 10 or derived from it. MLG 10 is widespread in Central America and Jamaica, making this region the most probable source of inoculum for the outbreak in Hawaii. An examination of global weather patterns during the months preceding the introduction of CLR makes it unlikely that the pathogen was windborne to the islands. Likely scenarios for the introduction of CLR to Hawaii are the accidental introduction of spores or infected plant material by travelers or seasonal workers, or improperly fumigated coffee shipments originating from Central America or the Caribbean islands.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>