<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q93054222</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6956869</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S10336-017-1481-4</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The impact of invasive plant management on the foraging ecology of the Warbler Finch (Certhidea olivacea) and the Small Tree Finch (Camarhynchus parvulus) on Galápagos</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Filek, Nikolaus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cimadom, Arno</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulze, Christian H</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jäger, Heinke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tebbich, Sabine</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-08-08</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Green Warbler-Finch</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Small Tree Finch</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>In recent decades, arboreal Darwin's Finches have suffered from a dramatic population decline, which has been attributed to parasitism by the invasive botfly &lt;i&gt;Philornis downsi&lt;/i&gt;. However, changes to their primary habitat caused by invasive plant species may have additionally contributed to the observed population decline. The humid cloud forest on Santa Cruz Island is a stronghold of arboreal Darwin's Finches but has been invaded by blackberry (&lt;i&gt;Rubus niveus&lt;/i&gt;). In some areas, manual control and herbicide application are used to combat this invasion, both causing a temporary removal of the entire understory. We hypothesized that the removal of the understory reduces the availability of arthropods, which are a main food source during chick rearing. We compared the foraging behaviour of Warbler Finches (&lt;i&gt;Certhidea olivacea&lt;/i&gt;) and Small Tree Finches (&lt;i&gt;Camarhynchus parvulus&lt;/i&gt;) at three study sites that varied in the degree of &lt;i&gt;R. niveus&lt;/i&gt; invasion and the length of time since the last herbicide application. We used prey attack rate and foraging success as an index for food availability and predicted a lower attack rate and foraging success in areas that had recently been sprayed with herbicides. We found that both the invasion and the management of &lt;i&gt;R. niveus&lt;/i&gt; influenced microhabitat use, foraging substrate and prey choice in both species. Contrary to our hypothesis, we did not find a lower attack rate or foraging success in the area with recent herbicide application. This may be explained by the finding that both species mainly foraged in the canopy but also used dead plant structures of the understory of the recently controlled area that resulted from the invasive plant management.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>