<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q64386112</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1071/MF07224</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Modelling wave-induced disturbance in highly biodiverse marine macroalgal communities: support for the intermediate disturbance hypothesis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>England, Phillip R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Phillips, Julia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Waring, Jason R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Symonds, Graham</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Babcock, Russell</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>Intermediate Disturbance Hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q9003976</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:Intermediate Disturbance Hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q9003976</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic science</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>seaweed</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>CSIRO Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;

As biodiversity declines globally, it is becoming increasingly important to understand the processes that create and maintain biodiverse communities. We examined whether the extraordinarily high species diversity of macroalgal communities in shallow coastal waters off south-west Western Australia is related to wave-induced physical disturbance. We used the numerical wave model SWAN to estimate the hydrodynamic forces generated by waves in bathymetrically complex coastal reefs. Oscillatory water motion at the seabed during extreme wave events was used as an index of physical disturbance in macroalgal communities. There was a significant curvilinear relationship between species diversity and disturbance index, consistent with the intermediate disturbance hypothesis (IDH). Diversity was lower at exposed offshore sites where disturbance is likely to be highest and at very sheltered sites with the least disturbance. Our results match those from some other highly diverse habitats, including rainforests, grasslands and coral reefs in which patchy, stochastic disturbance regimes have been hypothesised to prevent the development of homogeneous climax communities, promoting spatiotemporal heterogeneity and increasing total system diversity. Our results represent important evidence in support of a role for the IDH in driving diversity in marine plant communities.
&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>