<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117769055</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117769055</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/SU15075905</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ecological and Economic Impacts of Alien Invasive Yellow Flag (Iris pseudacorus L.) in China</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Xiong, Wen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Hui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wu, Zhigang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xiao, Keyan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Tao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bowler, Peter A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-03-29</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q112148709</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Iris pseudacorus</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ecological economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Non-native aquatic plants can alter the physiochemical condition of habitats and can have negative ecological and economic impacts. Thus, understanding the characteristics of non-native aquatic plant species is important as a foundation for the conservation of biodiversity and environmental management. The yellow flag (Iris pseudacorus) is an emergent aquatic plant native to Africa, northwest Asia, and Europe that has been introduced through the aquarium trade to all continents except Antarctica. This species has recently been brought into China and it has established large and widespread naturalized populations causing serious ecological and environmental problems. Unfortunately, information about the yellow flag in China is very scarce. We summarize the introduction pathways, current distribution, and ecological impacts of the yellow flag through field surveys and a review of the literature. We hope that this study can provide useful information for researchers and wetland managers involved with non-native emergent plants in China and other regions.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>