<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q113696038</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113696038</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/F13081321</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Drivers of Native Species Regeneration in the Process of Restoring a Dry Evergreen Forest from Exotic Tree Plantations in Northeastern Thailand</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Staporn, Duriya</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marod, Dokrak</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wongprom, Jetsada</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diloksumpun, Sapit</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-08-18</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>evergreen forest</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>forest restoration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>native species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Establishment of exotic plantations is one of the most effective ways to induce natural regeneration for the restoration of degraded lands, as it has the potential to improve soil properties and creates favorable microclimates. This study aims to determine the effects of stand structure and composition as well as environmental factors under the canopies of three exotic plantations in northeastern Thailand on the regeneration of native species. For each plantation, we conducted three 10 m × 150 m transect lines with fifteen 10 m × 10 m subplots along a forest remnant gradient. The canonical correspondence analysis (CCA) was used to identify the environmental factors responsible for the differences in natural regeneration among these stands. Three exotic plantations had different stand structure in terms of number of tree species, basal area, and tree density but similar dominant native tree species. Across all stands, 74 native tree species, 60 genera, and 30 families were observed. Some physical and chemical properties in the topsoil were significantly different between species but similar among stands within a species. On the other hand, differences in environmental factors such as RLI were significant among species and stands within a species. The CCA ordination identified that the soil particles, soil pH, and light intensity were key factors influencing the native species composition, which could be categorized into three groups: drought-tolerant pioneer species; light-demanding pioneer species; and shade-tolerant climax species. However, most of the climax species were incapable of regenerating and maturing along the forest edge gradient to plantation stands. To accelerate the restoration process by converting these old exotic plantations to a dry evergreen forest, further research is required to determine the appropriate canopy management and/or dominant climax species for planting beneath their canopies.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>