<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q90986443</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0224270</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>A new synthetic lure for management of the invasive giant African snail, Lissachatina fulica</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Roda, Amy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Millar, Jocelyn G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jacobsen, Chris</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Veasey, Robin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fujimoto, Lenny</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hara, Arnold</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McDonnell, Rory J</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-10-29</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Lissachatina fulica</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Synthetic chemical lures mimicking pheromones or food attractants are essential tools in eradication programs for invasive species. However, their uses in programs aiming to control or eradicate terrestrial gastropods are largely unexplored. The goal of this study was to find a synthetic attractant that could aid in the eradication or management of the giant African snail (Lissachatina fulica). Field studies in Hawaii showed that a commercial papaya-flavored oil attracted snails. Analysis of the odor profile of the oil identified a total of 22 chemicals, which comprised &gt; 98% of the volatile compounds emitted by the oil. A synthetic blend was reconstructed that mirrored the release rates of the papaya oil odors. In laboratory and field bioassays, the reconstructed blend, applied to cotton wicks as water and canola oil or water and mineral emulsions, attracted more snails than the water and oil emulsion control wicks. Field studies in Hawaii and Florida showed that the reconstructed blend in an oil emulsion was not attractive to non-target species such as butterflies or bees. The snails were attracted from distances &gt; 1 m and entered traps baited with the attractant emulsion. When tested in the South Florida giant African snail eradication program, direct ground application of the reconstructed papaya-flavored oil emulsion increased the number of snails killed by over 87% compared to water emulsion controls. Integrating tactics using the synthetic papaya oil attractant into control measures should increase the effectiveness of eradication and management programs.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>