<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114063704</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1177/109258721201700203</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Comparing Interpretive Methods Targeting Invasive Species Management at Cumberland Island National Seashore</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sharp, Ryan L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larson, Lincoln R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Green, Gary T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tomek, Sara</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012-11-15</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://journals.sagepub.com/page/policies/text-and-data-mining-license</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>SAGE Publications</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Interpretation designed to increase public understanding and appreciation of environmental issues can provide support for management actions in protected areas, but the relative impact of different interpretive strategies on public awareness and attitudes has not been adequately explored. The purpose of this research was to compare the effects of two interpretive programs (a non-personal, visual-based flyer and an interpersonal, audio-based talk) relative to a control group on visitors’ knowledge of, attitudes toward, and support for invasive species management at Cumberland Island National Seashore, Georgia. In general, the interpretive talk appeared to be more effective than the flyer at increasing awareness and generating support for invasive species management. Although visitors exposed to each of the treatments displayed greater knowledge of invasive species, effects on attitudes and management preferences were minimal. Future research examining the effects of interpretive media on public awareness of and support for controversial management decisions could therefore explore mechanisms for maximizing the impact of interpretive programming on visitors’ attitudes and preferences.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>