<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110758170</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1139/CJFAS-2018-0346</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Prediction of ecological impact of two alien gobiids in habitat structures of differing complexity</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gebauer, Radek</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Veselý, Lukáš</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vanina, Tatyana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Buřič, Miloš</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kouba, Antonín</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Drozd, Bořek</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-11</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://www.nrcresearchpress.com/page/about/CorporateTextAndDataMining</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>habitat structure</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Canadian Science Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt; Rapid expansion of round goby (Neogobius melanostomus) and western tubenose goby (Proterorhinus semilunaris) beyond their native ranges calls for urgent management action, particularly in localities with high introduction possibility of the species. We used a comparative functional response (FR) approach to forecast invader ecological impact. We compared their foraging efficiency in three habitat structures: sand, coarse gravel, and coarse gravel with an artificial plant. Both Neogobius melanostomus and Proterorhinus semilunaris showed type II FR in all habitats. Interspecific comparison showed similar handling times in both the gravel and gravel with artificial plant habitats, suggesting similar per capita impact. Intraspecific comparison showed significantly lower handling times of both predators on gravel substrates. Therefore, their ecological impact in such an environment could be higher. Neogobius melanostomus showed higher attack rates on sandy substrates compared with Proterorhinus semilunaris, while no significant differences were observed on other substrates. Our results highlight the importance of interacting factors in management of ecosystems with multiple invaders, as the elimination of invasive Neogobius melanostomus may lead to utilization of the empty niche by alien Proterorhinus semilunaris with similar ecological impact. &lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>