<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q35921646</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q35921646</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/SREP20384</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Responses of soil nitrogen fixation to Spartina alterniflora invasion and nitrogen addition in a Chinese salt marsh</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Huang, Jingxin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xu, Xiao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Min</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nie, Ming</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Qiu, Shiyun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Qing</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Quan, Zhexue</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xiao, Ming</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Bo</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-02-12</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>salt marsh</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Spartina alterniflora</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractBiological nitrogen fixation (BNF) is the major natural process of nitrogen (N) input to ecosystems. To understand how plant invasion and N enrichment affect BNF, we compared soil N-fixation rates and N-fixing microbes (NFM) of an invasive Spartina alterniflora community and a native Phragmites australis community in the Yangtze River estuary, with and without N addition. Our results indicated that plant invasion relative to N enrichment had a greater influence on BNF. At each N level, the S. alterniflora community had a higher soil N-fixation rate but a lower diversity of the nifH gene in comparison with the native community. The S. alterniflora community with N addition had the highest soil N-fixation rate and the nifH gene abundance across all treatments. Our results suggest that S. alterniflora invasion can increase soil N fixation in the high N-loading estuarine ecosystem and thus may further mediate soil N availability.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>