<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q113205978</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113205978</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/F13020273</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Non-Native Forest Tree Species in Europe: The Question of Seed Origin in Afforestation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alizoti, Paraskevi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bastien, Jean-Charles</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chakraborty, Debojyoti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klisz, Marcin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kroon, Johan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Neophytou, Charalambos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schueler, Silvio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Van Loo, Marcela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Westergren, Marjana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konnert, Monika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andonovski, Vlatko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andreassen, Kjell</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brang, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brus, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cvjetković, Branislav</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Đodan, Martina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fernández, Manuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frýdl, Josef</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Karlsson, Bo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keser, Zsolt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kormutak, Andrej</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lavnyy, Vasyl</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maaten, Tiit</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mason, Bill</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mihai, Georgeta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Monteverdi, Cristina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perić, Sanja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petkova, Krasimira</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Popov, Emil Borissov</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rousi, Matti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stojnić, Sran Milenko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tsvetkov, Ivaylo</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-02-09</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>afforestation</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Non-native forest tree species have been introduced in Europe since the 16th century, but only in the second half of the 20th century the significance of the seed source origin for their economic use was recognized, resulting in the establishment of numerous provenance trials at a national, regional, European and International level, as those led by IUFRO. Breeding programs have also been launched in the continent for the most economically important species. Aim of this work is the formulation of provenance recommendations for planting of five non-native tree species in Europe (Douglas fir, grand fir, Sitka spruce, lodgepole pine and black locust), based on the information obtained from twenty countries, in the frame of the EU FP-1403 NNEXT Cost Action. The survey revealed that official and non-official national recommendations, based on provenance research results, have been elaborated and followed at a different level and extend for the above five species, but only for Douglas fir recommendations exist in almost all the participating to the survey countries. The compilation of provenance recommendations across Europe for each species is presented in the current work. Besides the recommended introduced seed sources, European seed sources are also preferred for planting, due to ease of access and high availability of forest reproductive material. European breeding programs yielding genetic material of high productivity and quality constitute currently the seed source of choice for several species and countries. Consolidation of trial data obtained across countries will allow the joint analysis that is urgently needed to draw solid conclusions, and will facilitate the development of ‘Universal-Response-Functions’ for the species of interest, rendering possible the identification of the genetic material suitable for global change. New provenance trial series that will test seed sources from the entire climatic range of the species, established in sites falling within and outside the environmental envelopes of their natural ranges, are urgently needed to pinpoint and understand the species-specific climate constraints, as well as to correlate functional traits to the seed origin and the environmental conditions of the test sites, so that the selection of suitable forest reproductive material of non-native tree species in the face of climate change can be feasible.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>