<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q113704357</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113704357</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.2478/ENVIRON-2021-0021</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The current status of the plant invasions in Belarus</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dubovik, Dmitry V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sauchuk, Siarhei S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zavialova, Liudmyla V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-12-01</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>plant invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Walter de Gruyter GmbH</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract
               This article provides a review of the current status of plant invasions in Belarus. As a result of this research into the alien flora between 2008 and 2020 a list of 52 invasive plant species that threaten biodiversity, human health, and economic has been compiled. About 300 taxa of non-native plants are currently classified as potentially invasive. The list of invasive plant species has been proposed in this article in accordance with trends in the invasive processes is the basis for the monitoring and management of plant invasions in Belarus. The preliminary data from the previous field seasons showed a significant increase in the population abundance and distribution of Swida alba, Rudbeckia laciniata and Artemisia abrotanum. Enrichment of the flora occurs due to the introduction of aggressive plants. Hybridization between native and alien plant species leads to the appearance of hybrids, which often have an invasive potential, and can invade not only disturbed habitats but also natural plant communities. The invasive properties, expansion, and aggressive behavior of these invasive plants of the alien flora of Belarus has led to significant, often irreversible, changes in the natural vegetation and vegetation cover. Invasive species such as Solidago canadensis, S. gigantea, Echynocystis lobata, Impatiens glandulifera are marked by rapid expansion over past decades, and Heracleum sosnowskyi, Solidago canadensis, S. gigantea, Echinocystis lobata, Impatiens parviflora, Acer negundo, Robinia pseudoacacia, Bidens frondosa, have invaded more recently.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>