<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q115268228</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q115268228</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.5194/WE-18-91-2018</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Genetic diversity and differentiation of invasive &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Acacia longifolia&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; in Portugal</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vicente, Sara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Máguas, Cristina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trindade, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-05-24</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Acacia longifolia</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Copernicus GmbH</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract. Acacia longifolia is an aggressive invader worldwide. This
species was brought to Portugal by the forestry services and is now
found throughout the country with very strong ecological and social
impacts. Although several ecological and physiological studies have
been carried out, molecular studies in this species are
sparse. Particularly, genetic variability evaluation in invasive
ranges clearly deserves more attention. The aim of this study was to
evaluate the genetic diversity and the genetic differentiation among
populations of the alien invasive A._longifolia under
different Mediterranean conditions. For that we studied three sandy
dune populations along the Portuguese coast: Osso da Baleia
(mesomediterranean), Pinheiro da Cruz and Vila Nova de Milfontes
(termomediterranean). All sampled acacia plants were located
underneath a_pine forest, with the exception of the latter case
study, where we also sampled in a_diversified habitat conditions
associated with the margins of agriculture fields. According to the
historical records, it was also possible to compare acacia samples
from original plantations and recently invaded areas. We have used
two molecular markers – inter-simple sequence repeats (ISSR) and
microsatellites (SSR). ISSR analysis showed that
A._longifolia populations at all sampled locations have
similar levels of diversity and a_relatively low differentiation
(ΦPT=0.135). However, samples tended to cluster
according to the regional (macro-scale) collection
site. Microsatellites confirmed this low differentiation
pattern. Our results indicate that differences in phenology and
reproductive success observed during a_previous study cannot be
accounted for by genetic diversity and differentiation
alone. Furthermore, our results taken together with historical
information of A._longifolia suggest a_single original
introduction and a_subsequent acclimation process.
                    </dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>