<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114730983</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114730983</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/F13020178</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The Box Tree Moth: An Invasive Species Severely Threatening Buxus Natural Formation in NW Italy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ferracini, Chiara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pogolotti, Cristina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mancardi, Paolo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Miglio, Michela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bonelli, Simona</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barbero, Francesca</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-01-24</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>(1) The box tree moth (BTM), Cydalima perspectalis Walker, represents one of the recent examples of exotic insect pests native to Asia accidentally introduced in Europe by the nursery trade. In Europe, BTM develops on Buxus sempervirens L., causing significant damage to ornamental and natural plants. (2) Basic aspects of BTM biology were investigated at three sites in the NW Alps, where B. sempervirens occurs on rocky slopes, forming a protected habitat. In 2019–2021, we evaluated: (i) the seasonal flight activity with sex pheromone traps, (ii) the fecundity and the effects of food on the egg load, (iii) the potential adaptation of BTM on native secondary host plants, and (iv) the recruitment of natural enemies. (3) Our results revealed the presence of two generations per year. The number of mature eggs increased in fed adults and was higher in females of the first generation. No evidence of BTM shift on secondary plants was found in either laboratory or natural conditions, and no significant occurrence of natural enemies was recorded, except for one pupa of the tachinid Pseudoperichaeta nigrolineata. (4) Our findings provide valuable information to address and timely plan management strategies to preserve B. sempervirens as an essential component of rare forest ecosystems.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>