<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q34720671</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3646020</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0062591</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>RsmA regulates Aspergillus fumigatus gliotoxin cluster metabolites including cyclo(L-Phe-L-Ser), a potential new diagnostic marker for invasive aspergillosis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sekonyela, Relebohile</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Palmer, Jonathan M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bok, Jin-Woo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jain, Sachin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berthier, Erwin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Forseth, Ry</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schroeder, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keller, Nancy P</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2013-05-06</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>Aspergillus fumigatus</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aspergillosis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Basic leucine zipper (bZIP) type transcription factor</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Basic leucine zipper (bZIP) type transcription factor involved in regulation of secondary metabolism</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Dimeric basic leucine zipper (bZIP) proteins are conserved transcriptional enhancers found in all eukaryotes. A recently reported and novel function for bZIPs is association of these proteins with secondary metabolite production in filamentous fungi. In particular a Yap-like bZIP termed RsmA (restorer of secondary metabolism A) was identified in Aspergillus nidulans that positively regulates the carcinogen sterigmatocystin. To assess for conserved function for RsmA, we examined a role of this protein in secondary metabolism in the pathogen A. fumigatus. RsmA was found to positively regulate gliotoxin where overexpression (OE) of rsmA led to 2-100 fold increases of twelve gli cluster metabolites in culture medium including the newly identified gli metabolite cyclo(L-Phe-L-Ser). Lungs from both wild type and OErsmA infected mice contained gliotoxin (2.3 fold higher in OErsmA treatment) as well as the gliotoxin precursor cyclo(L-Phe-L-Ser) (3.2 fold higher in OErsmA treatment). The data here presents a conserved role for RsmA in secondary metabolite cluster activation and suggests cyclo(L-Phe-L-Ser) may serve as an alternative marker for diagnosis of invasive aspergillosis.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>