<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q58571980</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3389/FCIMB.2018.00377</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Genotyping of Aspergillus fumigatus in Formalin-Fixed Paraffin-Embedded Tissues and Serum Samples From Patients With Invasive Aspergillosis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Groot, Theun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hagen, Ferry</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vreuls, Willem</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Verweij, Paul E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chowdhary, Anuradha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meis, Jacques F</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-10-23</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>immunology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>infectious disease</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive aspergillosis</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Frontiers Media SA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive aspergillosis (IA) is a deep tissue infection with a high mortality occurring mostly in immunocompromised patients. To investigate the pathology of patients with IA it may be important to determine the genotype of the invasive isolate of &lt;i&gt;Aspergillus&lt;/i&gt;, however available tissues for study are often formalin fixed paraffin embedded (FFPE). Although DNA has been successfully isolated from such tissues for species identification, genotyping of &lt;i&gt;Aspergillus&lt;/i&gt; species on such tissues has not yet been performed. In this study we aimed to determine the genotype of &lt;i&gt;Aspergillus fumigatus&lt;/i&gt; in FFPE tissue and serum samples from five patients with invasive aspergillosis using nine highly polymorphic short tandem repeat (STR&lt;i&gt;Af&lt;/i&gt;) loci. FFPE lung and bronchial biopsies from all patients were successfully typed. By comparing the latter result with non-FFPE materials from non-sterile samples such as sputum, bronchoalveolar lavage and lung abscess, we found identical genotypes within three patients, while the two other patients had a dominant genotype shared among all sample types. Genotyping of serum samples was successful in two serum samples with galactomannan ratios of 4 and 5.6, but failed in serum samples with galactomannan levels &lt;0.5. In addition, testing a subset of these materials with the AsperGenius multiplex qPCR assay, we did not find azole resistance mutations. With this STR&lt;i&gt;Af&lt;/i&gt; assay, &lt;i&gt;A. fumigatus&lt;/i&gt; from FFPE tissue and serum was successfully genotyped, allowing retrospective examination of &lt;i&gt;A. fumigatus&lt;/i&gt; in culture negative patients with IA.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>