<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q37313053</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S00134-008-1339-6</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Management of invasive candidiasis and candidemia in adult non-neutropenic intensive care unit patients: Part II. Treatment</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Guery, Benoit</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arendrup, Maiken C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Auzinger, Georg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Azoulay, Elie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sá, Márcio Borges</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Johnson, Elizabeth M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Müller, Eckhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Putensen, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rotstein, Coleman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sganga, Gabriele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Venditti, Mario</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Crespo, Rafael Zaragoza</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kullberg, Bart Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2008-10-30</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>intensive care unit</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>candidiasis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>candidemia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive candidiasis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;h4&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;Invasive candidiasis and candidemia are frequently encountered in the nosocomial setting particularly in the intensive care unit (ICU).&lt;h4&gt;Objective and methods&lt;/h4&gt;To review the current management of invasive candidiasis and candidemia in non-neutropenic adult ICU patients based on a review of the literature and an European expert panel discussion.&lt;h4&gt;Results and conclusions&lt;/h4&gt;Empiric and directed treatment for invasive candidiasis are predicated on the hemodynamic status of the patient. Unstable patients may benefit from broad-spectrum antifungal agents, which can be narrowed once the patient has stabilized and the identity of the infecting species is established. In stable patients, a more classical approach using fluconazole may be satisfactory provided that the patient is not colonized with fluconazole resistant strains or there has been recent past exposure to an azole (&lt;30 days). In contrast, pre-emptive therapy is based on the presence of surrogate markers.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>