<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q120626381</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q120626381</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S10340-023-01653-1</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Tracing the dispersal route of the invasive Japanese beetle Popillia japonica</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Strangi, Agostino</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paoli, Francesco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nardi, Francesco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shimizu, Ken</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kimoto, Troy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Iovinella, Immacolata</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bosio, Giovanni</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roversi, Pio Federico</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carapelli, Antonio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marianelli, Leonardo</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-06-26</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Japanese beetle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive beetle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractThe Japanese beetle, Popillia japonica, is a highly polyphagous Scarabaeidae native to Japan that colonized North America and Azores in the last century and has recently invaded Italy and Switzerland. Considering its economic impact on the horticulture and turfgrass industries, this species was ranked within the EU priority pests list in 2019. According to the EU Convention on Biological Diversity, the identification of invasion routes is a pivotal aspect in an effective management program aimed at controlling invasive alien species. To reconstruct the source of introductions of this pest, we investigated the genetic variability of P. japonica in its native and invaded areas worldwide by analyzing 9 microsatellite loci and two mitochondrial genes, COX I and CytB. In its native area, P. japonica is structured into two populations: one in the southern and another in the northern-central region of Japan. A limited area within central Japan was identified as the putative source of the North American outbreak. Moreover, the ABC inference and phylogeographic reconstruction suggest that two European populations originated from two independent introductions. The Azores Islands outbreak occurred approximately 50_years ago and originated from the southeastern region of North America (For simplicity, in this paper North America refers to Canada and the USA), while the second introduction, more recently, occurred in Italy and Switzerland and originated from northeastern region of North America.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>