<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114730666</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114730666</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/SU14073719</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Prickly Pear (Opuntia spp.) as an Invasive Species and a Potential Fodder Resource for Ruminant Animals</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sipango, Nkosomzi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ravhuhali, Khuliso Emmanuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sebola, Nthabiseng Amenda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hawu, Onke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mabelebele, Monnye</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mokoboki, Hilda Kwena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moyo, Bethwell</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-03-22</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Worldwide, the invasiveness of Opuntia spp. and its impact on various ecosystem services has been recognised especially in semi-arid areas where rainfall is erratic. The semi-arid environments are the habitats of plants which have adapted to be able to grow in severe hot and dry regions. Opuntia spp. normally thrives in conditions of high temperatures, low rainfall, saline soils and it can also adapt and survive in severely degraded soils which have a limited nutrients supply. Its positive impact includes its recognised value as livestock fodder. Opuntia’s adaptability to harsh conditions, high dry matter yield, palatability and significant levels of energy, as well as its availability at a low cost during the dry season, decreases the use of expensive supplements and conventional diets in many areas. There is a need to understand the importance of this invasive Opuntia species when incorporated in animal diets. As a part of its control measures, the use of livestock in controlling the spread of Opuntia may assist in reducing its abundance and invasiveness while at the same time providing a consistent supply of forage during the dry season. Information on its nutritive value, incorporating the species in animal diets and the means to control it must be well understood to recognise the species’ contribution to an ecosystem.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>