<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q42032541</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0007485307005068</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Impact of an exotic parasitoid on Plutella xylostella (Lepidoptera: Plutellidae) population dynamics, damage and indigenous natural enemies in Kenya.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>B, Löhr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>R, Gathu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>C, Kariuki</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>J, Obiero</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>G, Gichini</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2007-08-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://www.cambridge.org/core/terms</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kenya</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Plutella xylostella</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Lepidoptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>population dynamics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Plutellidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press (CUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:italic&gt;Diadegma semiclausum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Hellén) (Hymenoptera: lchneumonidae), an exotic diamondback moth parasitoid, was released in two pilot areas (Werugha in Coast Region and Tharuni in Central Province) in Kenya. Fifteen month before release, observations on the diamondback moth, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Plutella xylostella&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Linnaeus), and local natural enemy population dynamics and pest damage were initiated in both areas and continued for three years after release. The &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. xylostella&lt;/jats:italic&gt; population was bimodal with higher records during dry seasons. At Werugha, the peak population of &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. xylostella&lt;/jats:italic&gt; was 16.8 per plant (October 2001); at Tharuni it was 12.8 (February 2002). Populations at Werugha declined from three months after release and decreased from 5.4 per plant (before release) to 0.8 (year 3 after release). Concurrently, average damage (1.9 to 1.5) (on a 0–5 scale), proportion of attacked plants (72 to 31%) and proportion of plants in damage group &gt;2 (plants with head damage) decreased (21.4 to 5.3%), while total parasitism increased from 14.4 (before) to 52.5% (year 3 after release, 90% due to &lt;jats:italic&gt;D. semiclausum&lt;/jats:italic&gt;). At Tharuni, &lt;jats:italic&gt;D. semiclausum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; was only recovered 3 months after release. Average populations of &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. xylostella&lt;/jats:italic&gt; declined from 5.9 per plant (before release) to 2.4 (year 3 after release) and damage scores from 2.3 to 1.7. The proportion of plants in damage group &gt;2 declined from 39.7 to 4.5% while overall parasitism increased from 4.2 to 40.6% (98.3% by &lt;jats:italic&gt;D. semiclausum&lt;/jats:italic&gt;). Four species of indigenous parasitoids (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Diadegma mollipla&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Holmgren), &lt;jats:italic&gt;Oomyzus sokolowskii&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Kurdjumov)&lt;jats:italic&gt;, Apanteles&lt;/jats:italic&gt; sp. and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Itoplectis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; sp., all primary parasitoids) were almost completely displaced by &lt;jats:italic&gt;D. semiclausum&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. Possible reasons for the different parasitoid development between the two release areas and the displacement of the indigenous species are discussed.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>