<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q64109985</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q64109985</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-019-40733-0</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Seed germination ecology of Alexandra palm (Archontophoenix alexandrae) and its implication on invasiveness</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wen, Bin</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-03-11</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Archontophoenix alexandrae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasiveness</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>seed germination</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractBiological invasions are occurring worldwide, causing enormous economic and ecological damage. Early detection and prediction of invasiveness are the most effective measures to reduce its damage. The Alexandra palm (Archontophoenix alexandrae) is a prolific seeder and an alien species widely planted in tropical China. To help understand the invasion risks posed by this species, lab and field experiments on seed germination were conducted. Results show that the seeds only germinate within a temperature range of 20–30_°C and are sensitive to desiccation and high temperature, with seedling inhibition at 35_°C and −0.8_MPa. Complete viability loss was observed after desiccation to water content of 0.17–0.21_g/g or heat treatment for 30_minutes at 60_°C and above. However, appropriate habitats such as the rainforest understory, forest gaps, forest edges, and a rubber plantation are present in Xishuangbanna. Seeds are also frequently consumed by animals; therefore, there is a high potential for Alexandra palm to become an invasive species in Xishuangbanna. Currently, the main barrier to invasion in Xishuangbanna is likely to be the need for seed dispersal into suitable moist, partly shaded, habitats. Understanding the requirements for germination of the Alexandra palm can better inform management strategies for the control of this species.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>