<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114645493</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114645493</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1051/BIOCONF/20213800068</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Adventive and invasive plant species of natural ecosystems in the Republic of Khakassia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lagunova, E. G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ankipovich, E. S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shaulo, D. N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-07-02</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>EDP Sciences</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>In this study, 56 adventive species have been identified in Khakas flora to date. In terms of the introduction method, xenophytes dominate; this group is composed of 44 species, which is 78.6% of all the adventive species under study. The ergasiophyte group consists of 12 species (21.4%). According to the naturalization degree, we identified three groups: epecophytes, agriophytes, and ephemerophytes. The epecophyte group is in the lead and consists of 21 species (37.5%). The agriophytes are represented by 19 invasive species (33.9%). The ephemerophyte group is composed of 16 species (28.6%). Thus, the ratios of the synanthropic-plant groups defined according to the introduction method and naturalization degree indicate that most of these adventive plants have been introduced unintentionally and successfully established themselves on a territory new to them. The adventive fraction of natural ecosystems in Khakas flora contains 20 species included in the report “The Black Book of the Flora of Siberia” [1].</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>