<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111160152</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111160152</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S10530-020-02313-6</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>When management meets science: adaptive analysis for the optimization of the eradication of the Northern raccoon (Procyon lotor)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mazzamuto, Maria Vittoria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Panzeri, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bisi, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wauters, L. A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Preatoni, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martinoli, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-07-21</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>raccoon</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>species eradication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractThe EU Regulation no.1143/2014 on invasive species requires the EU Member States to respond promptly and efficiently in eradicating the invasive alien species listed as species of Union concern. The Northern raccoon (Procyon lotor) was introduced in Northern Italy along the river Adda and we carried out its eradication campaign between 2016 and 2019. We used an integrated approach of camera traps and live traps. A standardized approach to the camera trap survey (2904 camera trap-nights) revealed that the detectability of raccoons (0.27_±_0.07 SD) increased in the proximity of the river and their occupancy (0.15_±_0.09 SD) was higher in urban areas. These results allowed us to increase the trapping success whilst reducing the effort. During the captures, systematic collection of catch and effort data allowed to estimate population size (65_±_7.8 raccoons) and thus to have a continuous update on how far the campaign was from the complete eradication of the species, allowing to adjust the trapping effort accordingly. We captured 69 raccoons (7279 cage trap nights) thanks to both systematic trapping and opportunistic activation of traps following stakeholders’ reports. Stakeholders supported the campaign and some of them played an important role in reporting sightings, signs, and allowing access to their private land. Camera trap data also allowed us to make a Rapid Eradication Assessment that estimated an eradication probability of 99% after 6_months without detections. We finally give indications for future control campaigns on the species to increase removal success, reducing the effort.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>