<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q113697298</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113697298</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3389/FPLS.2022.897678</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Environment-Driven Changes in the Functional Traits of Milk Thistle [Silybum marianum (L). Gaertn.] Along an Altitudinal Gradient in the Semi-Arid Environment: Perspective on Future Plant Invasion</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Khan, Nasrullah</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ullah, Rafi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alamri, Saud S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alwasel, Yasmeen A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>AL-Hashimi, Abdulrahman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Abdel-Maksoud, Mostafa A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Okla, Mohammad K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>AbdElgawad, Hamada</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-06-27</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>functional trait</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Silybum marianum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>plant invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Frontiers Media SA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The elevation is an important gradient across which the environmental variables and plant traits vary and is considered as a barrier to the recent global problem of plant invasion. However, certain invasive plants show plasticity traits to adapt and cope with the changes across the elevation. Silybum marianum (S. marianum) is one such invasive species widely spread in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan. Therefore, this study investigates the traits plasticity and invasive behaviors of this plant species across the elevation gradient. Plant functional traits (PFTs) and environmental variables were recorded in forty different low, middle, and high elevation sites. The plant shows a decrease in plant functional traits, i.e., above-ground plant height/plant, leaf length/leaf, leaf width/leaf, leaf dry weight/plant, vegetative dry weight/plant, and number of capitula/plant having the significance of p &amp;lt; 0.05. In contrast, the dry reproductive weight does not change significantly with elevation, while the root length increases across the elevation. The soil and environmental variables such as organic matter, lime percentage, and latitude significantly affected the PFTs. The importance value index of the species was also related to elevation and diversity indices, i.e., species richness, Shannon–Wiener diversity index, and evenness index, indicating that the invasion has strong effects on diversity. This study concludes that S. marianum has traits plasticity across the elevation and affects community diversity. Further investigation is required to understand the invasion and diversity parameters in a better way.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>