<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110757877</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110757877</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/W13233459</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Trophic Niche Overlap between Invasive and Indigenous Fish in a Northwest Reservoir of China</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wei, Jie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nie, Zhulan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ji, Fenfen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Qiu, Longhui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shen, Jianzhong</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-12-06</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>trophic niche</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The Kizil reservoir in the Tarim River basin is an important habitat for the native Schizothoracinae fish (including Aspiorhynchus laticeps, Schizothorax biddulphi, Schizothorax eurystomus, Schizothorax intermedius and Schizothorax barbatus). Unfortunately, these species are threatened by many exotic fish, such as Ctenopharyngodon idellus, Silurus asotus. As an isolated habitat, the Kizil reservoir is an ideal area for studying biological invasions. However, the impact of invasive species on indigenous species in this reservoir remains unknown. In this study, the niche width and niche overlap between invasive and indigenous species in Kizil reservoir were studied based on stable isotope analysis. The results showed that niche width of two invasive species, S. asotus and C. idellus, was larger than that of native fish species, which confirmed the hypotheses that successful invaders have larger niche width. The niche overlap analysis showed that the two invasive species had high niche overlap with native fish species, which meant that there might be intensive interspecific competitions between them. The invasion of non-native species could be the main reason for the decrease of native species in the Kizil reservoir.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>