<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q102051024</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q102051024</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/INSECTS11110773</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Effects of Urbanization on Plant-Pollinator Interactions in the Tropics: An Experimental Approach Using Exotic Plants</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zakardjian, Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Geslin, Benoît</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mitran, Valentin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Franquet, Evelyne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jourdan, Hervé</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-11-09</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>pollinator</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Land-use changes through urbanization and biological invasions both threaten plant-pollinator networks. Urban areas host modified bee communities and are characterized by high proportions of exotic plants. Exotic species, either animals or plants, may compete with native species and disrupt plantpollinator interactions. These threats are heightened in insular systems of the Southwest Pacific, where the bee fauna is generally poor and ecological networks are simplified. However, the impacts of these factors have seldom been studied in tropical contexts. To explore those questions, we installed experimental exotic plant communities in urban and natural contexts in New Caledonia, a plant diversity hotspot. For four weeks, we observed plantpollinator interactions between local pollinators and our experimental exotic plant communities. We found a significantly higher foraging activity of exotic wild bees within the city, together with a strong plantpollinator association between two exotic species. However, contrary to our expectations, the landscape context (urban vs. natural) had no effect on the activity of native bees. These results raise issues concerning how species introduced in plantpollinator networks will impact the reproductive success of both native and exotic plants. Furthermore, the urban system could act as a springboard for alien species to disperse in natural systems and even invade them, leading to conservation concerns.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>