<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111741033</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111741033</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://jhr.pensoft.net/article/76620/download/pdf/</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/JHR.89.76620</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Inclusion of an alien species in the host range of the Neotropical parasitoid Hymenoepimecis bicolor (Brullé, 1846) (Hymenoptera, Ichneumonidae)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>O. Gonzaga, Marcelo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pádua, Diego Galvão</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Quero, Adilson</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-02-28</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hymenoptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Ichneumonidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>In this study we report the first case of an introduced alien host spider species being parasitized and manipulated by an ichneumonid wasp. Hymenoepimecis bicolor, previously described parasitizing exclusively Trichonephila clavipes (Araneidae), was observed parasitizing the European species Cyrtophora citricola (Araneidae) in southeastern Brazil. The cocoon web built by the parasitized spider is composed of a reduced horizontal sheet, which maintains the radial structure. The reduced number of radii and spirals probably reduce the chances of insect interception by these modified structures. In addition, the density of supporting threads is apparently very different between normal and modified webs. The cocoon web spun by C. citricola lacks the protective barrier structure usually observed in cocoon webs spun by parasitized females of T. clavipes. Our observations are in agreement with several predictions of the ecdysteroid hypothesis and represent an interesting opportunity for further investigation of interactions between these parasitoids and their spider hosts.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>