<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q95825807</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q95825807</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/CANCERS12051297</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Tspan8 Drives Melanoma Dermal Invasion by Promoting ProMMP-9 Activation and Basement Membrane Proteolysis in a Keratinocyte-Dependent Manner</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kharbili, Manale El</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cario-Andre, Muriel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Béchetoille, Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pain, Catherine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boucheix, Claude</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Degoul, Francoise</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Masse, Ingrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berthier-Vergnes, Odile</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-05-21</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>keratinocyte</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Melanoma is the most aggressive skin cancer with an extremely challenging therapy. The dermal-epidermal junction (DEJ) degradation and subsequent dermal invasion are the earliest steps of melanoma dissemination, but the mechanisms remain elusive. We previously identified Tspan8 as a key actor in melanoma invasiveness. Here, we investigated Tspan8 mechanisms of action during dermal invasion, using a validated skin-reconstruct-model that recapitulates melanoma dermal penetration through an authentic DEJ. We demonstrate that Tspan8 is sufficient to induce melanoma cells’ translocation to the dermis. Mechanistically, Tspan8+ melanoma cells cooperate with surrounding keratinocytes within the epidermis to promote keratinocyte-originated proMMP-9 activation process, collagen IV degradation and dermal colonization. This concurs with elevated active MMP-3 and low TIMP-1 levels, known to promote MMP-9 activity. Finally, a specific Tspan8-antibody reduces proMMP-9 activation and dermal invasion. Overall, our results provide new insights into the role of keratinocytes in melanoma dermal colonization through a cooperative mechanism never reported before, and establish for the first time the pro-invasive role of a tetraspanin family member in a cell non-autonomous manner. This work also displays solid arguments for the use of Tspan8-blocking antibodies to impede early melanoma spreading and therefore metastasis.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>