<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q37481074</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q37481074</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3892369</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1002/ECE3.875</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Incest versus abstinence: reproductive trade-offs between mate limitation and progeny fitness in a self-incompatible invasive plant</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pierson, Jennifer C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Swain, Stephen M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Young, Andrew G</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2013-11-18</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractPlant mating systems represent an evolutionary and ecological trade‐off between reproductive assurance through selfing and maximizing progeny fitness through outbreeding. However, many plants with sporophytic self‐incompatibility systems exhibit dominance interactions at the S‐locus that allow biparental inbreeding, thereby facilitating mating between individuals that share alleles at the S‐locus. We investigated this trade‐off by estimating mate availability and biparental inbreeding depression in wild radish from five different populations across Australia. We found dominance interactions among S‐alleles increased mate availability relative to estimates based on individuals that did not share S‐alleles. Twelve of the sixteen fitness variables were significantly reduced by inbreeding. For all the three life‐history phases evaluated, self‐fertilized offspring suffered a greater than 50% reduction in fitness, while full‐sib and half‐sib offspring suffered a less than 50% reduction in fitness. Theory indicates that fitness costs greater than 50% can result in an evolutionary trajectory toward a stable state of self‐incompatibility (SI). This study suggests that dominance interactions at the S‐locus provide a possible third stable state between SI and SC where biparental inbreeding increases mate availability with relatively minor fitness costs. This strategy allows weeds to establish in new environments while maintaining a functional SI system.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>