<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117043568</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117043568</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S11756-023-01336-3</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The relationship between Invasive Alien Solanum elaeagnifolium Cav. characters and impacts in different habitats</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Balah, Mohamed Abdelaziz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hassany, Whaby Mohamed</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-02-06</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q112148709</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Solanum elaeagnifolium</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractInvasive alien plants are one of the most serious threats to agriculture. The growth traits of Solanum elaeagnifolium Cav. in crops and their demographics in invaded vs non-invaded communities were examined. The majority of S. elaeagnifolium germination was observed in the spring compared to the summer. Five stages were distinguished, which started with a short time of seedling and juvenile stages, extended flowering, and fruiting stages, and seed dispersion in the winter season. An increase in shoots/roots ratio, leaf area ratio and leaf mass fraction during growth with the varied rate was proved. The accumulation coefficient of dry mass exceeded 0.93 and was significant (P_&gt;_0.001) with great variability within plant parts, and stage intervals. While the high growth rate is influenced by the stages and habitats. The recipient communities are affected negatively by S. elaeagnifolium invasion which is associated with lower diversity, richness, and evenness vs non-invaded communities. High similarities were found in the invaded area and communities. Finally, high and varied growth and plasticity of S. elaeagnifolium characterized their invasion behavior via different habitats. There were suitable determinants indices of diversity that can be used in the comparison between invaded and non-invaded communities. This knowledge may be useful for use in agro-environment protection and to improve the management methods of invasive alien species.
</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>