<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111155182</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3389/FMARS.2021.680787</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Trophic, Chemo-Ecological and Sex-Specific Insights on the Relation Between Diplodus sargus (Linnaeus, 1758) and the Invasive Caulerpa cylindracea (Sonder, 1845)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Miccoli, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mancini, Emanuele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boschi, Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Provenza, Francesca</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lelli, Veronica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tiralongo, Francesco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Renzi, Monia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Terlizzi, Antonio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bonamano, Simone</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marcelli, Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-06-16</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Caulerpa cylindracea</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Frontiers Media SA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Biological invasions result in negative and unpredictable impacts on oceans worldwide. Non-indigenous macrophytes often synthesize secondary metabolites for defensive purposes and increased competition efficiency: this is the case of &lt;jats:italic&gt;Caulerpa cylindracea&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, which has entered the Mediterranean Sea in 1990 and competed against local flora and fauna since. It was demonstrated that the white seabream &lt;jats:italic&gt;Diplodus sargus&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (i) has included the algae into its diet, (ii) is subject to the peculiar Abnormally Tough Specimen (ATS) condition post-cooking, and (iii) suffers physiological and behavioral disturbances from caulerpin, one of the three major algal secondary metabolites. This paper confirms a feeding relationship between the fish and the algae, quantifies caulerpin accumulation in the liver, suggests a possible mollusk- and echinoderm-driven biomagnification, and highlights the fact that all ATS specimens were males. Multivariate analyses on a multi-biomarker panel reveals differential correlations to key cellular processes such as oxidative stress, metabolism, neurotoxicity, and lipid peroxidation as well as to condition indexes.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>