<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117043538</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117043538</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S11273-022-09902-3</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Phragmites australis invasion and herbicide-based control changes primary production and decomposition in a freshwater wetland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Yuckin, Sarah Jennifer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Howell, Graham</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Robichaud, Courtney D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rooney, Rebecca C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-12-29</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Phragmites australis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>herbicide</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractWetlands are important global carbon sinks, an increasingly important ecosystem service._Invasive plants can disrupt wetland carbon budgets, although efforts to suppress invasive plants may also have unintended effects. InvasivePhragmites australissubsp.australis(European common reed) produces extensive monocultures that displace resident plant communities. In Long Point (Ontario, Canada), a glyphosate-based herbicide was used to control over 900_ha ofP. australis. We determined how this ongoing management, and different environmental conditions, influence net primary productivity and decomposition rates. We compared above- and below-ground biomass, belowground:aboveground biomass ratios, standing dead stems, and litter in un-treatedP. australisstands, in herbicide-treated areas, and in reference vegetation. We also conducted a reciprocal transplant experiment to measure the decomposition rates of plant litter. One-year post-treatment, control efforts dramatically reduced aboveground biomass (122_g/m2_±_133 SD) compared to un-treatedP. australis(1254_g/m2_±_449 SD) and reference habitat (821_g/m2_±_335 SD). An interaction between the plant community of the site and water depth predicted litter decomposition rates, with litter loss ranging from 5.75 to 74.65% across all species, and submerged litter decomposing faster. These results emphasize that secondary treatment, such as rolling, burning, or cutting, encourages the decomposition of deadP. australisstems, opening up space for the recovery of native plants. While herbicide-treated sites had low biomass immediately following treatment, aquatic vegetation began rapidly colonizing treated areas, suggesting that plant community recovery may restore the wetland carbon uptake in subsequent years.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>