<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111827174</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111827174</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.2478/ENVIRON-2021-0023</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive alien plant species in Romania of European Union concern</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sîrbu, Culi_ă</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Anastasiu, Paulina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Urziceanu, Mihaela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Camen-Comănescu, Petronela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sîrbu, Ioana-Minodora</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Popa, Ana-Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ioja, Cristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gavrilidis, Athanasios A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oprea, Adrian</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-01-10</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Romania</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Walter de Gruyter GmbH</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract
               An assessement of the alien plants of Romania was conducted which considered the requirements of Regulation 1143/2014 of the European Union (EU). Thus, available data about the presence, invasiveness, distribution, pathways of introduction and their known impact in the territory of Romania were analysed. We found that of 36 plant species of EU concern, four are already established in Romania and widespread, at least locally or regionally: Ailanthus altissima, Asclepias syriaca, Elodea nuttallii and Impatiens glandulifera. For Humulus scandens there are some reports, but its presence and status require confirmation. Heracleum sosnowskyi and Ludwigia peploides are confirmed for only one location for each species. The presence of Cabomba caroliniana and Myriophyllum aquaticum in Romania is not confirmed. Most of the records are intentional introductions for ornamental purposes. Regarding their invasiveness, given the geographical origin and history of invasion in warmer climate regions (e.g., tropical, subtropical), many of the species listed as being of EU concern do not currently constitute a real threat to Romania, for the time being, but may do in a climate change scenario for the 2070s. Data about the impact of alien plant species and their management in Romania are scattered or completely missing. Coordinated institutional efforts are needed to increase the efficiency of the management of alien species at national and local level. These efforts should include: enhancing the legislation and the capacity of public institutions to manage invasive species, increasing the research interest in the science of this topic and promoting real measures to mitigate, control and remove alien plants.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>