<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114730817</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114730817</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/LAND11040550</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Pathways towards the Sustainable Management of Woody Invasive Species: Understanding What Drives Land Users’ Decisions to Adopt and Use Land Management Practices</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Adoyo, Beatrice</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schaffner, Urs</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mukhovi, Stellah</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kiteme, Boniface</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mbaabu, Purity Rima</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eckert, Sandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Choge, Simon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ehrensperger, Albrecht</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-04-08</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>sustainable management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Sustainable land management (SLM) practices are key for achieving land degradation neutrality, but their continued implementation lag behind the progression of various forms of land degradation. While many scholars have assessed the drivers of SLM uptake for restoring land affected by desertification, drought, and floods (SDG 15.3 and partly SDG 2.4), little is known about the implication of SLM implementation on invasive alien species (IAS) management. This study aimed at understanding the challenges and proposing solutions for the uptake of SLMs with respect to the management of the invasive tree, Prosopis juliflora, in Baringo County, Kenya. Data were collected with semi-structured questionnaires, the responses were coded into themes, and c-coefficient tables were used to determine code linkages. Our results show that the availability of incentives is the main motivation for invasion management. Thus, management efforts have often focused on private parcels, while communally shared lands tended to be neglected despite their vulnerability to invasion. We conclude that sustainable IAS management lies at a landscape scale, and thus the national IAS management strategies should adopt a collective approach by empowering local actors to engage in SLM implementation.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>