<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q37652378</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q37652378</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5317032</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/SREP42625</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The interaction between the proliferating macroalga Asparagopsis taxiformis and the coral Astroides calycularis induces changes in microbiome and metabolomic fingerprints</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aires, Tania</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Serrão, Ester A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Engelen, Aschwin H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomas, Olivier P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pérez, Thierry</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-02-20</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>microbiome</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Asparagopsis taxiformis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Astroides calycularis</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractMediterranean Sea ecosystems are considered as hotspots of biological introductions, exposed to possible negative effects of non–indigenous species. In such temperate marine ecosystems, macroalgae may be dominant, with a great percentage of their diversity represented by introduced species. Their interaction with temperate indigenous benthic organisms have been poorly investigated. To provide new insights, we performed an experimental study on the interaction between the introduced proliferative red alga Asparagopsis taxiformis and the indigenous Mediterranean coral Astroides calycularis. The biological response measurements included meta–barcoding of the associated microbial communities and metabolomic fingerprinting of both species. Significant changes were detected among both associated microbial communities, the interspecific differences decreasing with stronger host interaction. No short term effects of the macroalga on the coral health, neither on its polyp activity or its metabolism, were detected. In contrast, the contact interaction with the coral induced a change in the macroalgal metabolomic fingerprint with a significant increase of its bioactivity against the marine bacteria Aliivibrio fischeri. This induction was related to the expression of bioactive metabolites located on the macroalgal surface, a phenomenon which might represent an immediate defensive response of the macroalga or an allelopathic offense against coral.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>