<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114918227</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114918227</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/BIOLOGY11101527</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive Urban Mammalian Predators: Distribution and Multi-Scale Habitat Selection</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Miller, Kim F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wilson, Deborah J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartley, Stephen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Innes, John G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fitzgerald, Neil B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Miller, Poppy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heezik, Yolanda</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-10-19</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>habitat selection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>urban invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>A barrier to successful ecological restoration of urban green spaces in many cities is invasive mammalian predators. We determined the fine- and landscape-scale habitat characteristics associated with the presence of five urban predators (black and brown rats, European hedgehogs, house mice, and brushtail possums) in three New Zealand cities, in spring and autumn, in three green space types: forest fragments, amenity parks, and residential gardens. Season contributed to variations in detections for all five taxa. Rodents were detected least in residential gardens; mice were detected more often in amenity parks. Hedgehogs were detected least in forest fragments. Possums were detected most often in forest fragments and least often in residential gardens. Some of this variation was explained by our models. Proximity of amenity parks to forest patches was strongly associated with presence of possums (positively), hedgehogs (positively), and rats (negatively). Conversely, proximity of residential gardens to forest patches was positively associated with rat presence. Rats were associated with shrub and lower canopy cover and mice with herb layer cover. In residential gardens, rat detection was associated with compost heaps. Successful restoration of biodiversity in these cities needs extensive, coordinated predator control programmes that engage urban residents.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>