<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114939792</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114939792</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1088/1755-1315/533/1/012017</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Utilization of Invasive Alien Species (IAS) by communities around Cibodas Biosphere Reserve (CBR): a recommendation for invasive alien species management and policy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Handayani, A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hidayati, S</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-08-01</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biosphere reserve</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biosphere</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>IOP Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract
               The distribution of Invasive Alien Species (IAS) in the Cibodas Biosphere Reserve (CBR) area is enormous. Controlling IAS distribution is essential to be carried out, for the high potential threat to the native plant species. Generally, IAS species invade an open area of the forest. A review has been conducted with a literature study regarding recorded data about invasive alien species and studies about the utilization of plants by communities around CBR, especially the Gunung Gede Pangrango National Park area. The selected IAS list was further analyzed by using Index Cultural Significant (ICS). Recent studies concluded that 88 species of IAS spread out in the CBR area. On the other hand, many studies showed that IAS is widely used by the related communities in the CBR area. About 41 species out of 88 IAS were used by the communities, mainly for medicinal purposes. Utilisations of the medicinal plant were rooted in their traditional knowledge and culturally important for the communities’ livelihood. Additional input or recommendation for IAS management and policy in CBR was formulated by considering these conditions.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>