<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q59043636</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q59043636</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1155/2014/142429</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Litter Fall and Its Decomposition inSapium sebiferumRoxb.: An Invasive Tree Species in Western Himalaya</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jaryan, Vikrant</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Uniyal, Sanjay Kr.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gupta, R. C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singh, R. D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive tree</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Recognizing that high litter fall and its rapid decomposition are key traits of invasive species, litter fall and its decay inSapium sebiferumRoxb. were studied in Palampur. For this, litter traps of dimension 50 × 50 × 50cm3were placed in under-canopy and canopy gap of the species. Litter fall was monitored monthly and segregated into different components. For litter decay studies, litter bags of dimension 25 × 20cm2with a mesh size 2mm were used and the same were analyzed on a fortnightly basis. Litter fall in both under-canopy and canopy gap was highest in November (1.16Mgha1y1in under-canopy and 0.38Mgha1y1in canopy gap) and lowest during March. Litter production in under-canopy and canopy gap was 4.04Mgha1y1and 1.87Mgha1y1, respectively. These values are comparable to sal forest (1.7tCha1y1), chir pine-mixed forest (2.1tCha1y1), and mixed oak-conifer forest (2.8tCha1y1) of the Western Himalaya. The decay rate, 0.46% day1in under-canopy and 0.48% day1in canopy gap, was also fast. Owing to this the species may be able to modify the habitats to its advantage, as has been reported elsewhere.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>