<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q38801425</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q38801425</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1155/2016/1872351</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Silver Nanoparticles Affect Functional Bioenergetic Traits in the Invasive Red Sea Mussel Brachidontes pharaonis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Saggese, Ilenia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sarà, Gianluca</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dondero, Francesco</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-10-05</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>silver nanoparticle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>nanoparticle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Brachidontes pharaonis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Red Sea</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>We investigated the functional trait responses to 5nm metallic silver nanoparticle (AgNPs) exposure in the Lessepsian-entry bivalveB. pharaonis. Respiration rate (oxygen consumption), heartbeat rate, and absorption efficiency were evaluated across an 8-day exposure period in mesocosmal conditions. Basal reference values from not-exposed specimens were statistically compared with those obtained from animals treated with three sublethal nanoparticle concentrations (2μgL1, 20μgL1, and 40μgL1). Our data showed statistically significant effects on the average respiration rate ofB. pharaonis. Moreover, complex nonlinear dynamics were observed as a function of the concentration level and time. Heartbeat rates largely increased with no acclimation in animals exposed to the two highest levels with similar temporal dynamics. Eventually, a decreasing trend for absorption efficiency might indicate energetic constraints. In general, these data support the possible impact of engineered nanomaterials in marine environments and support the relevance of functional trait assessment in present and future ecotoxicological studies.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>