<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q34629338</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0950268813003075</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Human migration is important in the international spread of exotic Salmonella serovars in animal and human populations</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Iveson, J B</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bradshaw, Sidney D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>How, R A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smith, D W</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2013-12-16</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>bacteria</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>salmonellosis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>disease outbreak</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>global health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The exposure of indigenous humans and native fauna in Australia and the Wallacea zoogeographical region of Indonesia to exotic Salmonella serovars commenced during the colonial period and has accelerated with urbanization and international travel. In this study, the distribution and prevalence of exotic Salmonella serovars are mapped to assess the extent to which introduced infections are invading native wildlife in areas of high natural biodiversity under threat from expanding human activity. The major exotic Salmonella serovars, Bovismorbificans, Derby, Javiana, Newport, Panama, Saintpaul and Typhimurium, isolated from wildlife on populated coastal islands in southern temperate areas of Western Australia, were mostly absent from reptiles and native mammals in less populated tropical areas of the state. They were also not recorded on the uninhabited Mitchell Plateau or islands of the Bonaparte Archipelago, adjacent to south-eastern Indonesia. Exotic serovars were, however, isolated in wildlife on 14/17 islands sampled in the Wallacea region of Indonesia and several islands off the west coast of Perth. Increases in international tourism, involving islands such as Bali, have resulted in the isolation of a high proportion of exotic serovar infections suggesting that densely populated island resorts in the Asian region are acting as staging posts for the interchange of Salmonella infections between tropical and temperate regions.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>