<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q113204010</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113204010</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/SU14106093</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Predicting Potential Habitat Changes of Two Invasive Alien Fish Species with Climate Change at a Regional Scale</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hong, Seungbum</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jang, Inyoung</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Daegeun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Suhwan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Park, Hyun Su</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Kyungeun</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-05-17</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>climate change</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>regional scale</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Developing national-level policies related to climate change induced expansions of invasive species requires predictive modelling at a regional scale level. This study aimed to predict future changes in the habitat distributions of two major invasive alien fish species, Micropterus salmoides and Lepomis macrochirus, in South Korea. An ensemble system with multiple species distribution models was used for the prediction, and gridded water portion data from the linear-structure information on river channels inputted as habitat characteristics of freshwater ecosystem into the models. Bioclimatic variables at 20-year intervals from 2001 to 2100 were generated from predicted temperature and precipitation data under the representative concentration pathway 4.5 and 8.5 scenarios. The overall distribution probabilities of the potential habitats increased with time in both climate change scenarios, and the potential habitats were predicted to expand to upstream areas. Combined with regional ecological value information, such as biodiversity in freshwater ecosystems, these results can be an important basis for deriving regional priority information for managing alien species in climate change. Additionally, the modelling approach is highly applicable to various national-level policies for ecosystem conservation since it is not greatly restricted by spatial scales.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>