<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q52672869</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q52672869</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.7717/PEERJ.4408</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Marine exotic isopods from the Iberian Peninsula and nearby waters</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Martínez-Laiz, Gemma</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ros, Macarena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guerra-García, José M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-02-27</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Isopoda</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Iberian Peninsula</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Strait of Gibraltar</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>PeerJ</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Effective management of marine bioinvasions starts with prevention, communication among the scientific community and comprehensive updated data on the distribution ranges of exotic species. Despite being a hotspot for introduction due to numerous shipping routes converging at the Strait of Gibraltar, knowledge of marine exotics in the Iberian Peninsula is scarce, especially of abundant but small-sized and taxonomically challenging taxa such as the Order Isopoda. To fill this gap, we conducted several sampling surveys in 44 marinas and provide the first comprehensive study of marine exotic isopods from the Iberian Peninsula, the southern side of the Strait of Gibraltar (northern Africa) and the Balearic Islands. Exotic species includedIaniropsis serricaudis(first record for the Iberian Peninsula and Lusitanian marine province),Paracerceis sculpta(first record for the Alboran Sea ecoregion),Paradella dianae,Paranthura japonica(earliest record for the Iberian Peninsula) andSphaeroma walkeri. Photographs with morphological details for identification for non-taxonomic experts are provided, their worldwide distribution is updated and patterns of invasion are discussed. We report an expansion in the distribution range of all species, especially at the Strait of Gibraltar and nearby areas.Ianiropsis serricaudisandParanthura japonicaare polyvectic, with shellfish trade and recreational boating being most probable vectors for their introduction and secondary spread. The subsequent finding of the studied species in additional marinas over the years points at recreational boating as a vector and indicates a future spread. We call for attention to reduce lags in the detection and reporting of small-size exotics, which usually remain overlooked or underestimated until the invasion process is at an advanced stage.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>