<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q28604046</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1186/S12862-016-0611-6</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The Eurasian invasion: phylogenomic data reveal multiple Southeast Asian origins for Indian Dragon Lizards</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Grismer, Jesse L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulte, James A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alexander, Alana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wagner, Philipp</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Travers, Scott L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Buehler, Matt D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Welton, Luke J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brown, Rafe M</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-02-19</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>India</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>phylogenomics</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;h4&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;The Indian Tectonic Plate split from Gondwanaland approximately 120 MYA and set the Indian subcontinent on a ~ 100 million year collision course with Eurasia. Many phylogenetic studies have demonstrated the Indian subcontinent brought with it an array of endemic faunas that evolved in situ during its journey, suggesting this isolated subcontinent served as a source of biodiversity subsequent to its collision with Eurasia. However, recent molecular studies suggest that Eurasia may have served as the faunal source for some of India's biodiversity, colonizing the subcontinent through land bridges between India and Eurasia during the early to middle Eocene (~35-40 MYA). In this study we investigate whether the Draconinae subfamily of the lizard family Agamidae is of Eurasian or Indian origin, using a multi locus Sanger dataset and a novel dataset of 4536 ultraconserved nuclear element loci.&lt;h4&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;Results from our phylogenetic and biogeographic analyses revealed support for two independent colonizations of India from Eurasian ancestors during the early to late Eocene prior to the subcontinent's hard collision with Eurasia.&lt;h4&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;These results are consistent with other faunal groups and new geologic models that suggest ephemeral Eocene land bridges may have allowed for dispersal and exchange of floras and faunas between India and Eurasia during the Eocene.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>