<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q36063524</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1002/PS.4347</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Enhancing the effectiveness of biological control programs of invasive species through a more comprehensive pest management approach</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>DiTomaso, Joseph M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Van Steenwyk, Robert A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nowierski, Robert M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vollmer, Jennifer L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lane, Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chilton, Earl</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Burch, Patrick L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cowan, Phil E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmerman, Kenneth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dionigi, Christopher P</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-06-29</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/tdm_license_1</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive species are one of the greatest economic and ecological threats to agriculture and natural areas in the US and the world. Among the available management tools, biological control provides one of the most economical and long-term effective strategies for managing widespread and damaging invasive species populations of nearly all taxa. However, integrating biological control programs in a more complete integrated pest management approach that utilizes increased information and communication, post-release monitoring, adaptive management practices, long-term stewardship strategies, and new and innovative ecological and genetic technologies can greatly improve the effectiveness of biological control. In addition, expanding partnerships among relevant national, regional, and local agencies, as well as academic scientists and land managers, offers far greater opportunities for long-term success in the suppression of established invasive species. In this paper we direct our recommendations to federal agencies that oversee, fund, conduct research, and develop classical biological control programs for invasive species. By incorporating these recommendations into adaptive management strategies, private and public land managers will have far greater opportunities for long-term success in suppression of established invasive species. © 2016 Society of Chemical Industry.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>