<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q35654576</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q35654576</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4457149</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/SREP11004</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>A new strategy for controlling invasive weeds: selecting valuable native plants to defeat them</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Li, Weihua</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luo, Jianning</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tian, Xingshan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chow, Wah Soon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sun, Zhongyu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Taijie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peng, Shaolin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peng, Changlian</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2015-06-05</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive weed</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractTo explore replacement control of the invasive weed Ipomoea cairica, we studied the competitive effects of two valuable natives, Pueraria lobata and Paederia scandens, on growth and photosynthetic characteristics of I. cairica, in pot and field experiments. When I. cairica was planted in pots with P. lobata or P. scandens, its total biomass decreased by 68.7% and 45.8% and its stem length by 33.3% and 34.1%, respectively. The two natives depressed growth of the weed by their strong effects on its photosynthetic characteristics, including suppression of leaf biomass and the abundance of the CO2-fixing enzyme RUBISCO. The field experiment demonstrated that sowing seeds of P. lobata or P. scandens in plots where the weed had been largely cleared produced 11.8-fold or 2.5-fold as much leaf biomass of the two natives, respectively, as the weed. Replacement control by valuable native species is potentially a feasible and sustainable means of suppressing I. cairica.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>