<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q120096132</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q120096132</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.7717/PEERJ.15424</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Functional responses of male and female European green crabs suggest potential sex-specific impacts of invasion</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kattler, Kiara R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oishi, Elizabeth M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lim, Em G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Watkins, Hannah V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Côté, Isabelle M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-06-02</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q112148709</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Carcinus maenas</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nuttallia obscurata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive crab</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>animal behaviour</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>sexual dimorphism</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>PeerJ</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Predicting the impacts of predatory invasive species is important for prioritising conservation interventions. Functional response experiments, which examine consumption by predators in relation to prey density, are a useful way to assess the potential strength of novel predator-prey relationships. However, such experiments are often conducted without consideration of sex or only with males to reduce invasion risk. Here, we compared the functional responses of male and female European green crabs (Carcinus maenas), a global invader, feeding on varnish clams (Nuttallia obscurata) to test whether the two sexes have similar potential for impact. We also examined potential correlates of predation behaviour by measuring sex-specific movement and prey choice. Both sexes displayed a Type II hyperbolic functional response, which can destabilise prey populations at low prey densities. However, males and females exhibited some differences in foraging behaviour. Female green crabs had slightly lower attack rates, which were not linked to sex differences in movement, and slightly longer handling times, which were not linked to sex differences in prey choice. These small, non-significant differences nevertheless translated into significantly greater functional response ratios, which are used to predict the ecological impact of invasive species, for males than females. There was no difference in the proportion of clams consumed between males and females with similar crusher claw heights, but females have smaller crusher claws on average, hence they consumed a smaller proportion of clams. Repeated surveys of four populations of European green crabs established in British Columbia, Canada, showed that sex ratio is highly variable. Taken together, these results and population-level modelling suggest that trying to evaluate the potential impact of European green crabs on clam populations by sampling only males could result in overestimation, even in populations that have male-biased sex-ratios. Consumer sex might generally be an important feature to consider when using functional response experiments to forecast the impact of new invasive species, especially those with marked sexual dimorphism that affect foraging.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>