<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q52592800</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5888908</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/VE/VEY009</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The virome of Drosophila suzukii, an invasive pest of soft fruit.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Medd, Nathan C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fellous, Simon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Waldron, Fergal M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xuéreb, Anne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nakai, Madoka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cross, Jerry V</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Obbard, Darren J</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-01-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Drosophila suzukii</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;i&gt;Drosophila suzukii&lt;/i&gt; (Matsumura) is one of the most damaging and costly pests to invade temperate horticultural regions in recent history. Conventional control of this pest is challenging, and an environmentally benign microbial biopesticide is highly desirable. A thorough exploration of the pathogens infecting this pest is not only the first step on the road to the development of an effective biopesticide, but also provides a valuable comparative dataset for the study of viruses in the model family &lt;i&gt;Drosophilidae&lt;/i&gt;. Here we use a metatransciptomic approach to identify viruses infecting this fly in both its native (Japanese) and invasive (British and French) ranges. We describe eighteen new RNA viruses, including members of the Picornavirales, Mononegavirales, Bunyavirales, Chuviruses, &lt;i&gt;Nodaviridae&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Tombusviridae&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Reoviridae&lt;/i&gt;, and Nidovirales, and discuss their phylogenetic relationships with previously known viruses. We also detect 18 previously described viruses of other &lt;i&gt;Drosophila&lt;/i&gt; species that appear to be associated with &lt;i&gt;D. suzukii&lt;/i&gt; in the wild.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>