<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q59334797</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q59334797</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/OFID/OFY210.1689</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>2033. Incorporating T2Candida Testing into Rational Antifungal (AF) Management: A Successful Pilot Study of Diagnostic Stewardship (DS) Directed Toward Specific Intensive Care Unit (ICU) Patients At-Risk for Sepsis due to Invasive Candidiasis (IC)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Shields, Ryan K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Clancy, Cornelius J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marini, Rachel V</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Groetzinger, Lara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rivosecchi, Ryan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Falcione, Bonnie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pasculle, Anthony</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nguyen, Hong</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-11</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>candidiasis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>intensive care unit</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive candidiasis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract Background Blood cultures (BC) are ~50% sensitive for diagnosing IC. T2Candida (T2) detects five leading Candida spp. directly in blood and was ≥90%/90% sensitive/specific (S/Sp) for candidemia in clinical trials. Optimal use of T2 in clinical practice is unclear. We targeted T2 to specific ICU patients at-risk for IC, and implemented AF management algorithms developed with ICU teams. Methods A DS team ordered concurrent T2 and BC, and used results to guide AF in patients fulfilling pre-specified criteria for septic shock (medical ICU (MICU)), sepsis after abdominal surgery (trauma ICU), or sepsis with mechanical circulatory support (cardiothoracic ICU). We focused on groups with anticipated pre-test IC probabilities of ~3–15%. Proven IC was defined if BC+ and possible IC if BC- but a compatible clinical picture was observed. Results Seven percent (6/88) of BC in ICU patients with sepsis were Candida +. T2 and BC results are shown in the table. Using BC as gold standard, T2 S/Sp and PPV/NPV were 50%/87% and 33%/96%, respectively. Including possible IC, T2 S/Sp increased to 69%/96%, and 67% (4/6) of T2+/BC results were likely true positive; two false-positive results were for C. parapsilosis. We focused on MICU outcomes initially since 75% (66/88) of tests were performed here. Empiric AFs were discontinued in 12 patients following a T2- result; AFs were avoided in all others. Median combined days of therapy (DOT)/month for caspofungin and fluconazole as empiric or definitive treatment prior to and after introducing DS were 26 (range: 10–53) and 15 (3–32), respectively (P = 0.0047). AF consumption was decreased 47% (figure). Conclusion Targeted DS using T2 in select ICU patients with sepsis significantly reduced AF usage. 14% of patients with sepsis were diagnosed with IC using either T2+ or BC+, compared with 7% with BC+ alone, as would be expected if BC S was 50%. T2 S and T2/BC+ results were lower and higher, respectively, than previously reported, indicating that treatment decisions should be based on results of both tests. Most T2+/BC results were ascribed to possible IC.Table. Rates of T2 and BC Positive Results and Corresponding Candida Species% (n) testsCandida spp.T2+10% (9)5 CP, 4 CA/CTBC+7% (6)5 CA, 1 CPT2+/BC+3% (3)2 CA, 1 CPT2+/BC-7% (6)2 CA/CT, 4 CPT2-/BC+3% (3)3 CAT2-/BC-86% (76) Disclosures M. H. Nguyen, Merck: Grant Investigator, Research grant. Astellas: Grant Investigator, Research grant.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>