<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q38969951</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q38969951</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1914168</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1104/PP.107.098764</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>A symbiotic plant peroxidase involved in bacterial invasion of the tropical legume Sesbania rostrata</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Herder, Jeroen Den</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lievens, Sam</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rombauts, Stephane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Holsters, Marcelle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Goormachtig, Sofie</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2007-03-23</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sesbania rostrata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract
               Aquatic nodulation on the tropical legume Sesbania rostrata occurs at lateral root bases via intercellular crack-entry invasion. A gene was identified (Srprx1) that is transiently up-regulated during the nodulation process and codes for a functional class III plant peroxidase. The expression strictly depended on bacterial nodulation factors (NFs) and could be modulated by hydrogen peroxide, a downstream signal for crack-entry invasion. Expression was not induced after wounding or pathogen attack, indicating that the peroxidase is a symbiosis-specific isoform. In situ hybridization showed Srprx1 transcripts around bacterial infection pockets and infection threads until they reached the central tissue of the nodule. A root nodule extensin (SrRNE1) colocalized with Srprx1 both in time and space and had the same NF requirement, suggesting a function in a similar process. Finally, in mixed inoculation nodules that were invaded by NF-deficient bacteria and differed in infection thread progression, infection-associated peroxidase transcripts were not observed. Lack of Srprx1 gene expression could be one of the causes for the aberrant structure of the infection threads.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>