<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110757113</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S12210-021-00987-1</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Value-conflicts in the conservation of a native species: a case study based on the endangered white-clawed crayfish in Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Biasetti, Pierfrancesco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ferrante, Linda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bonelli, Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Manenti, Raoul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scaccini, Davide</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mori, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-05-11</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>indigenous species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;The future of the native European crayfish &lt;jats:italic&gt;Austropotamobius pallipes&lt;/jats:italic&gt; depends on accurate conservation management. The goal of this paper is to attempt an investigation of the major ethical conflicts that can emerge in the conservation of this endangered crayfish threatened by invasive competitors, introduced diseases, and landscape alteration. To assess this issue, we will employ the Ethical Matrix, in a version explicitly tailored for its use in conservation. The filled Ethical Matrix will highlight several potential conflicts between values such as environmental protection, social and economic interests, animal welfare, cultural and aesthetic value, etc. We will discuss these conflicts, alongside some potential mitigating strategies present in the literature. We will stress in particular the need to take into account the ethical principle of fairness when assessing the economic and recreational value of invasive species, especially concerning the unfair distribution of costs. Moreover, we will assert the importance of conservation of &lt;jats:italic&gt;A. pallipes&lt;/jats:italic&gt; both for its existence value and for its role as an umbrella and keystone species. Beyond its focus on &lt;jats:italic&gt;A. pallipes&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, the Ethical Matrix here discussed might also provide insights on the value conflicts relative to analogous in situ conservation efforts involving a native species threatened by invasive alien competitors.&lt;/jats:p&gt;
                &lt;jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:bold&gt;Graphic abstract&lt;/jats:bold&gt;&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>