<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q57062632</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q57062632</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.5194/WE-7-53-2007</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Trophic niche partitioning between two native and two exotic carnivores in SW Portugal</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Santos, M. J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pinto, B. M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Santos-Reis, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2007-05-30</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Portugal</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>niche partitioning</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>trophic niche</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Copernicus GmbH</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract. The introduction of exotic species is one of the most pervasive consequences of the increased human mobility. The most known negative effects are the decrease or extinction of natives. The common-genet, Genetta genetta, and the Egyptian mongoose, Herpestes ichneumon, were introduced in the Iberian Peninsula in the 15th and 19th centuries, respectively. The competitive exclusion principle defines that two ecologically similar species cannot coexist. Thus, some degree of partitioning has to occur in species realized niche, which can occur at the trophic level. To test this hypothesis of partitioning we compared the diet of these two exotic species with that of two native species (stone marten, Martes foina, and red fox, Vulpes vulpes). The results show a high degree of overlap (&gt;45%) between the diets of species similar in their feeding strategies (arboreal and ground feeding). Nonetheless, at the finer scale of prey consumed at the species level some differences are found between the native and exotic species. These results suggest that if coexistence is due to trophic niche partitioning it only occurs at the level of the consumed species. However, coexistence may also be due to a combination of different strategies (home-range size, time and space use) that structured the different realized niches of each species.
                    </dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>