<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q37037331</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3720011</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1155/2013/256025</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Molecular identification and susceptibility pattern of clinical Nocardia species: Emergence of Nocardia crassostreae as an agent of invasive nocardiosis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Taj-Aldeen, Saad J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Deshmukh, Anand</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Doiphode, Sanjay</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wahab, Atqah Abdul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Allangawi, Mona</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Almuzrkchi, Ahmed</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klaassen, Corné H</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meis, Jacques F</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2013-01-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nocardia crassostreae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;BACKGROUND:&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia&lt;/jats:italic&gt;species are rare, opportunistic organisms that cause disease in both immunocompetent and immunocompromised individuals.&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;OBJECTIVE: To investigate the clinical presentations of various&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia&lt;/jats:italic&gt;infections based on the 16S ribosomal RNA gene of the isolate, as well as related risk factors and susceptibility patterns to antimicrobial agents&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;METHODS: Thirteen patients with a diagnosis of nocardiosis were included in the present study. Seven&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia&lt;/jats:italic&gt;species were identified by 16S ribosomal RNA. Susceptibility testing was performed using six antimicrobial agents.&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;RESULTS: Five patients were immunocompromised, and eight were immunocompetent with predisposing factors including cystic fibrosis, tuberculosis and ophthalmic infections.&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia&lt;/jats:italic&gt;caused pulmonary infections in eight patients (61.5%), invasive systemic infections in three patients (23%) and local (ophthalmic) infections in two patients (15.4%). In the patients with pulmonary disease, nocardiosis was caused by six species (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia cyriacigeorgica&lt;/jats:italic&gt;,&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia otitidiscaviarum&lt;/jats:italic&gt;,&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia farcinica&lt;/jats:italic&gt;,&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia carnea&lt;/jats:italic&gt;,&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia testacea&lt;/jats:italic&gt;and&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia asiatica)&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. The seventh species identified in the present study was&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia crassostreae.&lt;/jats:italic&gt;&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;DISCUSSION:&lt;jats:italic&gt;N crassostreae&lt;/jats:italic&gt;is a multidrug-resistant organism that was reported to be an emerging human pathogen causing invasive nocardiosis in a patient with non-Hodgkin’s lymphoma.&lt;jats:italic&gt;N farcinica&lt;/jats:italic&gt;was isolated from blood in a patient with breast cancer. None of the&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia&lt;/jats:italic&gt;isolates were resistant to linezolid. One&lt;jats:italic&gt;N otitidiscaviarum&lt;/jats:italic&gt;isolate was a multidrug-resistant organism. All patients in the present study were treated with the appropriate antibiotics and their condition resolved without further sequelae.&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;CONCLUSIONS: The present study is the first report on&lt;jats:italic&gt;N crassostreae&lt;/jats:italic&gt;as a human pathogen. The detection of multidrug-resistant species necessitate molecular identification and susceptibility testing, and should be performed for all&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia&lt;/jats:italic&gt;infections. Nocardiosis manifests various clinical features depending on the&lt;jats:italic&gt;Nocardia&lt;/jats:italic&gt;species and underlying conditions.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>