<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q37993043</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/CID/CIS021</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Impact of treatment strategy on outcomes in patients with candidemia and other forms of invasive candidiasis: a patient-level quantitative review of randomized trials</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Andes, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Safdar, Nasia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baddley, John W</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Playford, Geoffrey</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reboli, Annette C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rex, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sobel, Jack D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pappas, Peter G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kullberg, Bart Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Group, Mycoses Study</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012-03-12</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>patient</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>candidiasis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>candidemia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive candidiasis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;h4&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;Invasive candidiasis (IC) is an important healthcare-related infection, with increasing incidence and a crude mortality exceeding 50%. Numerous treatment options are available yet comparative studies have not identified optimal therapy.&lt;h4&gt;Methods&lt;/h4&gt;We conducted an individual patient-level quantitative review of randomized trials for treatment of IC and to assess the impact of host-, organism-, and treatment-related factors on mortality and clinical cure. Studies were identified by searching computerized databases and queries of experts in the field for randomized trials comparing the effect of ≥2 antifungals for treatment of IC. Univariate and multivariable analyses were performed to determine factors associated with patient outcomes.&lt;h4&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;Data from 1915 patients were obtained from 7 trials. Overall mortality among patients in the entire data set was 31.4%, and the rate of treatment success was 67.4%. Logistic regression analysis for the aggregate data set identified increasing age (odds ratio [OR], 1.01; 95% confidence interval [CI], 1.00-1.02; P = .02), the Acute Physiology and Chronic Health Evaluation II score (OR, 1.11; 95% CI, 1.08-1.14; P = .0001), use of immunosuppressive therapy (OR, 1.69; 95% CI, 1.18-2.44; P = .001), and infection with Candida tropicalis (OR, 1.64; 95% CI, 1.11-2.39; P = .01) as predictors of mortality. Conversely, removal of a central venous catheter (CVC) (OR, 0.50; 95% CI, .35-.72; P = .0001) and treatment with an echinocandin antifungal (OR, 0.65; 95% CI, .45-.94; P = .02) were associated with decreased mortality. Similar findings were observed for the clinical success end point.&lt;h4&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h4&gt;Two treatment-related factors were associated with improved survival and greater clinical success: use of an echinocandin and removal of the CVC.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>