<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q36413369</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/J.SCITOTENV.2017.06.070</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Assessment of imaging-in-flow system (FlowCAM) for systematic ballast water management</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Romero-Martínez, Leonardo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Slooten, Cees</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nebot, Enrique</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Acevedo-Merino, Asunción</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peperzak, Louis</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-06-20</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://www.elsevier.com/tdm/userlicense/1.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>water management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>sailing ballast</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier BV</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Assessing the disinfection of ballast water and its compliance with international standards requires determining the size, viability, and concentration of planktonic organisms. The FlowCAM (Flow Cytometer and Microscope) is an Imaging Flow Cytometry designed to obtain the particle concentration, images, and quantitative morphologic information. The objective in this paper is to establish the basis for transforming the FlowCAM from being a laboratory analyzer into a tool for systematic monitoring of ballast water. The capacity of the FlowCAM was evaluated by analyzing artificial microbeads, phytoplankton monocultures, and real seawater samples. Microbead analyses reported high accuracy and precision in size and concentration measurements. Monoculture analyses showed the effect of disinfection treatments in cell appearance and growth. Low concentration and heterogeneity of particles in real seawater analyses require the comprehensive observation of images by experts. Additionally, some physical characteristics of the device must be improved. The optimization of device configuration enables the quick transferring of files and information between parties involved in ballast water management. FlowCAM may become a feasible technology for this after the device and protocols are adapted.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>