<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113904275</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S10530-022-02810-W</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Can the enemy release hypothesis explain the success of Rumex (Polygonaceae) species in an introduced range?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Costan, Cristian-Andrei</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Godsoe, William</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bufford, Jennifer L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marris, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hulme, Philip</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-05-03</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>enemy release hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q85759287</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:enemy release hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q85759287</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Polygonaceae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;The enemy release hypothesis states that introduced plants have a competitive advantage due to their release from co-evolved natural enemies (i.e., herbivores and pathogens), which allows them to spread rapidly in new environments. This hypothesis has received mixed support to date, but previous studies have rarely examined the herbivore community, plant damage, and performance simultaneously and largely ignored below-ground herbivores. We tested for enemy release by conducting large scale field surveys of insect diversity and abundance in both the native (United Kingdom) and introduced (New Zealand) ranges of three dock (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Rumex&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, Polygonaceae) species:&lt;jats:italic&gt;R. conglomeratus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;Murray (clustered dock),&lt;jats:italic&gt;R&lt;/jats:italic&gt;.&lt;jats:italic&gt;crispus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;L. (curly dock) and&lt;jats:italic&gt;R. obtusifolius&lt;/jats:italic&gt;L. (broad-leaved dock). We captured both above- and below-ground insect herbivores, measured herbivore damage, and plant biomass as an indicator for performance. In the introduced range,&lt;jats:italic&gt;Rumex&lt;/jats:italic&gt;plants had a lower diversity of insect herbivores, all insect specialists present in the native range were absent and plants had lower levels of herbivore damage on both roots and leaves. Despite this, only&lt;jats:italic&gt;R. crispus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;had greater fresh weight in the introduced range compared to the native range. This suggests that enemy release, particularly from below-ground herbivores, could be a driver for the success of&lt;jats:italic&gt;R. crispus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;plants in New Zealand, but not for&lt;jats:italic&gt;R. conglomeratus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;and&lt;jats:italic&gt;R. obtusifolius&lt;/jats:italic&gt;.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>