<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q58690085</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q58690085</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.5402/2012/193807</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>No Reproductive Interference from an Alien to a Native Species in Cerastium (Caryophyllaceae) at the Stage of Seed Production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Takakura, Koh-Ichi</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Reproductive interference</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>native species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Caryophyllaceae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Reproductive interference, adverse interspecific interaction during the mating process, has been regarded as a powerful driver of species displacement between species. Recent empirical reports have described its importance in biological invasions. This study was undertaken to test whether a rare herbaceous plant species indigenous to Japan suffered reproductive interference from an alien species of the genus Cerastium. Field observations and a transplanting experiment were conducted to ascertain the effects of coexistence with an alien species on the seed production of the native species. Results show that coexistence with the alien species did not significantly decrease seed numbers, but it significantly affected the seed weight only in field observations. In this study, the reproductive process of the native species was examined only at or before the seed production stage. Because the interspecific pollen transfer might produce hybrids with low viability or fertility, reproductive interference cannot be denied in this study. To test reproductive interference at such latter stages, additional studies should be conducted. Consequently, detection of reproductive interference demands high costs in some species. Based on these results and suggestions, the necessity of narrowing down the target species for testing of reproductive interference is discussed to elucidate the universality of reproductive interference.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>