<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q108549762</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/AFRINVERTEBR.62.62842</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Identity of parasitoid wasps (Hymenoptera, Braconidae and Eulophidae) reared from aquatic leaf-mining flies (Diptera, Ephydridae) on invasive Brazilian waterweed Egeria densa in South Africa</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Noort, Simon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smith, Rosali</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Coetzee, Julie A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-03-09</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Hymenoptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Afr. Invertebr.</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The Brazilian waterweed, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Egeria densa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Planchon, 1849 (Hydrocharitaceae), is an invasive species in South Africa where it is a host plant for the aquatic leaf-miner &lt;jats:italic&gt;Hydrellia egeriae&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Rodrigues-Júnior, 2015 (Ephydridae, Diptera). Efficacy of the biocontrol agent can potentially be affected by parasitoids. Three species of braconid parasitoid wasps were reared from puparia of &lt;jats:italic&gt;Hydrellia egeriae&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. By comparison with the type specimens, these species have been determined to be &lt;jats:italic&gt;Ademon lagarosiphonae&lt;/jats:italic&gt; van Achterberg, 2012 (Braconidae: Opiinae), &lt;jats:italic&gt;Chaenusa anervata&lt;/jats:italic&gt; van Achterberg, 2012 and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Chaenusa seminervata&lt;/jats:italic&gt; van Achterberg, 2012 (Braconidae: Alysiinae: Dacnusini), all previously recorded as parasitoids of an ephydrid dipterous aquatic leaf-miner, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Hydrellia lagarosiphon&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Deeming, 2012, on &lt;jats:italic&gt;Lagarosiphon major&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Ridley, 1886) Moss ex Wager (Hydrocharitaceae) in South Africa. The chalcidoid, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Janicharis africanus&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Gumovsky &amp;amp; Delvare, 2006 (Eulophidae), was also reared from &lt;jats:italic&gt;Hydrellia egeriae&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and is possibly a hyperparasitoid of the braconids. South Africa is a new country record for &lt;jats:italic&gt;J. africanus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. We provide comprehensive images of all species including the braconid types and illustrated identification keys to the Afrotropical species of the two braconid genera are also provided. All images and online keys are available on WaspWeb (http://www.waspweb.org).&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>