<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q104743125</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q104743125</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/JOF7010019</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>&lt;i&gt;Aspergillus fumigatus&lt;/i&gt; and Its Allergenic Ribotoxin &lt;i&gt;Asp f&lt;/i&gt; I: Old Enemies but New Opportunities for Urine-Based Detection of Invasive Pulmonary Aspergillosis Using Lateral-Flow Technology</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Davies, Genna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singh, Oski</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prattes, Juergen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hoenigl, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sheppard, Paul W</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thornton, Christopher R</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-12-31</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive pulmonary aspergillosis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Aspergillus fumigatus</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive pulmonary aspergillosis (IPA) caused by Aspergillus fumigatus is a life-threatening lung disease of immunocompromised patients. Diagnosis currently relies on non-specific chest CT, culture of the fungus from invasive lung biopsy, and detection of the cell wall carbohydrate galactomannan (GM) in serum or in BAL fluids recovered during invasive bronchoscopy. Urine provides an ideal bodily fluid for the non-invasive detection of pathogen biomarkers, with current urine-based immunodiagnostics for IPA focused on GM. Surrogate protein biomarkers might serve to improve disease detection. Here, we report the development of a monoclonal antibody (mAb), PD7, which is specific to A. fumigatus and related species in the section Fumigati, and which binds to its 18 kDa ribotoxin Asp f I. Using PD7, we show that the protein is secreted during hyphal development, and so represents an ideal candidate for detecting invasive growth. We have developed a lateral-flow device (Afu-LFD®) incorporating the mAb which has a limit of detection of ~15 ng Asp f I/mL urine. Preliminary evidence of the test’s diagnostic potential is demonstrated with urine from a patient with acute lymphoid leukaemia with probable IPA. The Afu-LFD® therefore provides a potential novel opportunity for non-invasive urine-based detection of IPA caused by A. fumigatus.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>