<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111315715</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/viewFile/2134/3555</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.11609/JOTT.2134.8.2.8538-8540</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Intrusion of devil weed Chromolaena odorata, an exotic invasive, into Kinnerasani and Eturnagaram wildlife sanctuaries, Telangana, India</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Suthari, Sateesh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kandagatla, Ramesh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Geetha, Sarede</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ragan, Ajmeera</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raju, Vatsavaya S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-02-26</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>enemy release hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q85759287</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:enemy release hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q85759287</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Chromolaena odorata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Wildlife Information Liaison Development Society</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The spread of devil weed is alarming in areas of &lt;em&gt;podu&lt;/em&gt; cultivation, on the bunds of agricultural lands, wastelands, along roadsides, tracks, forest gaps, protected areas and plantations in the two said wildlife sanctuaries. It is found invading new territories easily along the river banks and steadily destroying the riparian elements. The manual removal of this weed (mechanical method) before flowering is the effective means to mitigate the spread of the species in comparison to the biological (&lt;em&gt;Pareuchaetes pseudoinsulata, P. insulata, Actinote thalia-pyrrha&lt;/em&gt;) and chemical (Glyphosate, Triclopyrester) methods attempted. It is not trouble in its native habitat but is weedy in India for want of natural enemies to keep it under control. It is a mandate to prevent the loss of native biodiversity due to biological invasions. Conversely, there is an urgent need to devise action plans by managers of the respective wildlife sanctuaries to control and eradicate it. The local people are to be educated of its potential dangers to their farming on one hand and NTFP extraction from the local forests on the other. The Government of India has to develop a national level policy towards the control of invasive alien weeds in general and implement it at the earliest before we loose our indigenous biodiversity once for all.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>