<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111246029</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111246029</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.2298/GSF0900159O</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ecology and distribution of an invasive species Aster_lanceolatus willd. on wet habitats in Belgrade</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Obratov-Petkovic, Dragica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bjedov, Ivana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Radulovic, Stojanka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Skocajic, Dragana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Djunisijevic-Bojovic, Danijela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Djukic, Matilda</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2009-12-14</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>National Library of Serbia</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The species Aster lanceolatus occupies a significant position in the world and European lists of invasive species. Its spreading potential is a hazardous factor to the biodiversity in many countries. There are no relevant data on the wider proportion of this species in the area of Belgrade. The sites of Aster lanceolatus are annual or pioneer communities along the water courses, abandoned and neglected areas, forest margins, moist meadows. The study areas are located near a choice of water courses in Belgrade. The aim of the study was to assess the species ecology and population density, synecological interrelationships among the coenobionts of the communities in which it occurs, and also to map its the habitats. The study of population density was performed on the supplemented and partially modified 'CPS SKEW' form, applied in West European countries, by the principle of squares. The species was determined by standard floristic method, and the species location by GPS system. It was concluded that Aster lanceolatus was dominant and wild at all study sites. The individuals and populations are especially numerous on the river islands Ada Ciganlija and Veliko Ratno Ostrvo, along the stream Kumodrsaki Potok and the Danube left bank, where the number of individuals per squares is above 1300 and the degree of coverage is 100%. Its spreading potential is conditioned by the species biology, and the expansiveness by climate changes, anthropogenic impacts and the competitive interrelationships.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>