<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111423848</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.14214/SF.1321</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Composition of functional groups of ground vegetation differ between planted stands of non-native &lt;i&gt;Pinus contorta&lt;/i&gt; and native &lt;i&gt;Pinus sylvestris&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Picea abies&lt;/i&gt; in northern Sweden</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bäcklund, Sofia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jönsson, Mari</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Strengbom, Joachim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thor, Göran</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2015-05-05</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Picea abies</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pinus sylvestris</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pinus contorta</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Finnish Society of Forest Science</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;ja:p&gt;Intensified forestry increases the interest in replacing native tree species with fast growing non-native species. However, consequences for native biodiversity and ecosystem functioning are poorly understood. We compared cover and composition of major functional groups of ground vegetation between planted stands of non-native Dougl. var.  Engelm. and native conifers L. and (L.) H. Karst. in northern boreal Sweden. We quantified the ground cover of lichens, bryophytes, vascular plants and ground without vegetation (bare ground) in 96 stands covering three different age classes (15, 30 and 85 years old). Our study revealed differences in ground vegetation patterns between non-native and native managed forests, and that these differences are linked to stand age and differences in canopy cover. Total vascular plant cover increased with increasing stand age for all tree species, with  stands having higher cover than both native conifers. The ground cover of lichens was, although generally low, highest in stands of .  stands had a lower cover of vascular plants, but bare ground was more common compared with . Our results suggest that the use of  as an alternative tree species in Fennoscandian forestry will influence native ground vegetation patterns. This influence is likely to change with time and future research should consider both temporal and landscape-scale effects from shifting tree-species dominance to  and other non-native tree species.&lt;ja:italic&gt;Pinus contorta &lt;/ja:italic&gt;&lt;ja:italic&gt;latifolia&lt;/ja:italic&gt;&lt;ja:italic&gt;Pinus sylvestris &lt;/ja:italic&gt;&lt;ja:italic&gt;Picea abies &lt;/ja:italic&gt;&lt;ja:italic&gt;P. contorta&lt;/ja:italic&gt;&lt;ja:italic&gt;Pinus sylvestris&lt;/ja:italic&gt;&lt;ja:italic&gt;P. abies&lt;/ja:italic&gt;&lt;ja:italic&gt;P. contorta&lt;/ja:italic&gt;&lt;ja:italic&gt;P. contorta&lt;/ja:italic&gt;&lt;ja:italic&gt;Pinus contorta&lt;/ja:italic&gt;&lt;/ja:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>