<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114749942</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114749942</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3389/FPLS.2022.955656</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive Plants and Species Richness Impact Litter Decomposition in Riparian Zones</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hu, Xin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arif, Muhammad</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ding, Dongdong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Jiajia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He, Xinrui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Changxiao</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>litter decomposition</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>species richness</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Frontiers Media SA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Natural ecosystems generally include litter decomposition as part of the natural cycle since the material properties and the environment greatly influence the decomposition rate. The invasion of exotic plants alters the species diversity and growth characteristics of plant communities, but its impact on litter decomposition is unknown in the riparian zone. This study examines how invasive plants affect the early stages of litter decomposition and how species richness impacts them. This experiment involved a random litter mixture of exotic (Alternanthera philoxeroides and Bidens pilosa) and native species in the riparian zone of the Three Gorges Dam Reservoir in China. There were 43 species mixture types, with various species richness ranging from 1 to 6. Litterbags were placed in the hydro-fluctuation zone and terrestrial zone, where they decomposed over the course of 55 days. Invasive plants decompose rapidly compared to native plants (35.71% of the remaining mass of the invasive plant). The invasive plant A. philoxeroides has the potential to accelerate native plant decomposition (0.29 of non-added synergetic effect), but Bidens pilosa cannot. Nonetheless, species richness had little effect on the decomposition rate. These effects are dependent upon differences in chemical functional characteristics among the species. The initial traits of the plants, specifically C, N, and C/N, were significantly and linearly correlated with the loss of mixed litter mass and mixing effect strength (P &amp;lt; 0.01). In addition, submergence decomposition conditions reduce the disturbance of invasive plants and predict decomposition rates based on litter characteristics. Invasive plants can therefore impact the material cycle of an ecosystem. There is a need to examine decomposition time, which may also involve considering other factors.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>