<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q39062930</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S12281-017-0275-8</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Lateral Flow Assays for the Diagnosis of Invasive Aspergillosis: Current Status</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Heldt, Sven</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hoenigl, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-04-29</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aspergillosis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive aspergillosis</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;h4&gt;Purpose of review&lt;/h4&gt;Diagnosis during early stages of invasive aspergillosis (IA) and targeted antifungal treatment has the potential to improve survival significantly. Despite advances in the diagnostic arsenal, invasive mold infections remain difficult to diagnose-especially at early stages before typical radiological signs develop. Varying availability and time-to-results are important limitations of current approved biomarkers and molecular assays for diagnosis of IA. Here, we will give an update on the &lt;i&gt;Aspergillus&lt;/i&gt;-specific lateral-flow device (LFD) test. We further review promising findings on feasibility of point-of-care (POC) detection of urinary excreted fungal galactomannan-like antigens.&lt;h4&gt;Recent findings&lt;/h4&gt;POC LFD assays for detection of &lt;i&gt;Aspergillus&lt;/i&gt; antigens are currently in development. The &lt;i&gt;Aspergillus&lt;/i&gt;-specific LFD test, which is based on the JF5 antibody (Ab), detects an extracellular glycoprotein antigen secreted during active growth of &lt;i&gt;Aspergillus&lt;/i&gt; spp. The test has shown promising results in various studies. In addition, a monoclonal Ab476-based LFD for POC detection of urinary excreted fungal galactomannan-like antigens has been developed but needs further validation.&lt;h4&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;Important advances have been made in the development of LFD assays for IA. Most promising is the &lt;i&gt;Aspergillus&lt;/i&gt;-specific LFD test; commercial availability is still pending, however. The search for reliable POC tests for other molds, including mucorales, continues.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>