<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111320458</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0251497</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Interactions between sympatric invasive European fire ants (Myrmica rubra) and blacklegged ticks (Ixodes scapularis)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Guarnieri, Lucy D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McBride, Sara E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Groden, Eleanor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gardner, Allison M</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-05-10</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Ixodes scapularis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Myrmica rubra</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The blacklegged tick (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Ixodes scapularis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;) and the invasive European fire ant (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Myrmica rubra&lt;/jats:italic&gt;) are both expanding throughout their sympatric range in coastal New England. &lt;jats:italic&gt;Ixodes scapularis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; is the primary vector of the bacterium &lt;jats:italic&gt;Borrelia burgdorferi&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, which is the causative agent of Lyme disease, and Mount Desert Island, Maine, home to Acadia National Park, currently is affected by a high Lyme disease burden. Ticks have many natural predators, including ants, although no previous studies have investigated interactions between these two species. To test the hypothesis that the presence of &lt;jats:italic&gt;M&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;rubra&lt;/jats:italic&gt; alters &lt;jats:italic&gt;I&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;scapularis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; abundance, we collected ticks by drag-sampling at eight ant-infested sites and eight uninfested control sites in Acadia National Park. We found that nymph density was significantly higher at ant-infested sites, while larval density was significantly higher at control sites. In addition, we conducted a laboratory bioassay to measure &lt;jats:italic&gt;M&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;rubra&lt;/jats:italic&gt; aggression against &lt;jats:italic&gt;I&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;scapularis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; larvae, nymphs, and adults and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Dermacentor variabilis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; adults, and found that ant aggression was significantly higher against &lt;jats:italic&gt;D&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;variabilis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; adults than &lt;jats:italic&gt;I&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;scapularis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; adults. Our findings support the hypothesis that &lt;jats:italic&gt;M&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;rubra&lt;/jats:italic&gt; has divergent effects across &lt;jats:italic&gt;I&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;scapularis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; life stages, and we discuss possible ecological mechanisms, including optimal microclimate and predation, that could promote density of nymphs while inhibiting density of larvae.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>