<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q98198185</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q98198185</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/INSECTS11080493</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Current Distribution and Diagnostic Features of Two Potentially Invasive Asian Buprestid Species: Agrilus mali Matsumura and A. fleischeri Obenberger (Coleoptera: Buprestidae)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Volkovitsh, Mark G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kovalev, Alexey V</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Orlova-Bienkowskaja, Marina J</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-08-02</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Coleoptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Buprestidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Agrilus mali</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Our goal is to analyze the known geographical ranges and diagnostic features of two potentially invasive Asian buprestid species: the quarantine apple tree pest, Agrilus mali Matsumura, and the poplar pest A. fleischeri Obenberger. Based on the examination of museum collections and literature sources, we compiled comprehensive databases of records of the exact collecting sites for both species and generated detailed maps of their ranges. There are 51 documented localities for A. mali in the Russian Far East and East Siberia, Mongolia, China, and the Korean peninsula, and there are 53 documented localities for A. fleischeri in the Far East and Siberia, Kazakhstan, Mongolia, China, and Japan. No evidence of the presence of A. mali in Japan was found. Outbreak sites of A. mali in Xinjiang in the 2000s most likely represent the newly forming invasion areas; their proximity to the wild apple stands in the Kazakh part of the Tien Shan is a direct threat to Kazakhstan and adjacent countries. Sites damaged by A. fleischeri in Liaoning are situated within its native range; the outbreaks were likely triggered by the switch from indigenous to introduced poplars. This situation is similar to the early stages of emerald ash borer (Agrilus planipennis Fairmaire) invasion.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>