<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q118137151</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q118137151</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/SU15064833</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Collaborative Adaptive Stewardship for Invasive Alien Plants Management in South Africa</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rawat, Yashwant S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Negi, Vikram S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pant, Shreekar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bachheti, Rakesh Kumar</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-03-08</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>This study examined the knowledge of Collaborative Adaptive Stewardship (CASt) to advance Invasive Alien Plants (IAPs) management in South Africa. This concept promotes the involvement of private landowners and other stakeholders in the management and action processes, hence promoting social inclusivity, job creation, and sustainable biodiversity stewardship. It demonstrates that landowners are major stakeholders in IAPs management, thereby practising biodiversity stewardship in the 80% of privately owned lands of the country. The involvement of landowners in the management process aids in the prevention of further expansion of IAPs, the mitigation of risks (such as fire and flooding), and the maintenance of ecosystem functionality and landscape-scale connectivity. CASt fosters synergy among many stakeholders for the management of IAPs and long-term sustainable biodiversity stewardship. In South Africa, a number of landowners have entered into stewardship agreements as a result of incentives and subsidies for IAPs management. The benefits should be contingent on private landowner actions to IAPs management; this will support biodiversity stewardship. This study serves as a foundation for collaborative IAPs management and will be crucial in achieving long-term sustainability goals (e.g., economy, society and environment) to protect biodiversity and ecosystem services.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>