<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111166424</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1051/KMAE/2020041</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasion and distribution of the redclaw crayfish, Cherax quadricarinatus, in Martinique</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Baudry, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Becking, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Goût, Jean-Pierre</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arqué, Alexandre</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gan, Han Ming</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Austin, Chris M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Delaunay, Carine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smith-Ravin, Juliette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roques, Jonathan A C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grandjean, Frederic</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-12-23</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Cherax quadricarinatus</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>EDP Sciences</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The redclaw crayfish, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Cherax quadricarinatus,&lt;/jats:italic&gt; was introduced to Martinique Island for aquaculture purposes in 2004, in an attempt to revitalize the freshwater crustacean aquaculture sector. In 2015, three wild populations were discovered during an electrofishing survey on fish diversity. In 2018, a specific crayfish survey was performed at night using spotlighting and baited traps at 34 sites throughout the island. The species was mostly found in the center and northern part of the island, specifically, a total of 105 specimens were captured in eight streams and five closed water bodies. We sequenced a 491 base-pair fragment of the COI gene to understand the invasion history and pathway from the presumed source population at the Mangatal hatchery. Among the eight haplotypes found, three were dominant, of which, two occurred in the Mangatal hatchery. As crayfish are sold alive, there is a high risk of further human-mediated introductions across the island hydrographic basins. Thus, the distribution of this species could rapidly expand throughout Martinique freshwater ecosystems, with ecological impacts on native communities yet to be determined and requiring urgent investigation.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>