<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q47660649</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q47660649</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5762630</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-017-18735-7</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Responses in shoot elongation, carbohydrate utilization and growth recovery of an invasive species to submergence at different water temperatures.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ye, Xiao Qi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zeng, Bo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meng, Jin Liu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wu, Ming</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Xiao Ping</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-01-10</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractWidely distributed amphibious exotic plant species may respond plastically to water temperatures when submerged. Alternanthera philoxeroides, a highly flood-tolerant species, originates from tropical regions and has successfully invaded temperate regions. The wide distribution of this species suggests it can respond to flooding at different water temperatures. In this study, the plastic responses of A. philoxeroides plants to submergence at water temperatures of 10_°C, 20_°C and 30_°C were investigated. The A. philoxeroides plants had large pools of non-structural carbohydrates, which were readily mobilized upon submergence. Submergence hindered biomass accumulation and decreased the carbohydrate content level and respiration rate (P_&lt;_0.05). Water temperature had remarkable effects on shoot elongation, carbohydrate utilization and recovery growth. With decreasing water temperature, the respiration rate was lower and carbohydrate content decreased more slowly, but the post-submergence biomass accumulation was faster (P_&lt;_0.05), indicating a beneficial effect of low water temperature for recovery. However, high water temperatures accelerated shoot elongation (P_&lt;_0.05), which benefitted the submerged plants more if contact with air was restored. These results suggest that the species can respond to different water temperatures plastically, which may provide hints for its invasion success in regions with diverse climates.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>