<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114730846</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114730846</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/INSECTS13100877</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>A New Aculodes Species (Prostigmata: Eriophyidae) Described from an Invasive Weed by Morphological, Morphometric and DNA Barcode Analyses</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vidović, Biljana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>An_elković, Nikola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jojić, Vida</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cvrkovic, Tatjana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petanović, Radmila</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marini, Francesca</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cristofaro, Massimo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rector, Brian G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-09-27</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Eriophyidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive weed</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>A new species of eriophyoid mite, Aculodes marcelli sp. nov., was discovered on cheatgrass, Anisantha tectorum (L.) Nevski (syn. Bromus tectorum L.), an annual grass that is native to Eurasia and Northern Africa. This grass was introduced to North America near the end of the 19th century and now is widespread and associated with the observed increases in the size, frequency, and intensity of wildfires in western N. America. In this paper, A. marcelli sp. nov., is morphologically described and illustrated. Compared with other Aculodes spp., it differs based on morphology and the sequence of the mitochondrial cytochrome oxidase gene, subunit I (MT-CO1). Results of morphometric analysis showed clear differentiation between A. marcelli sp. nov., and the most similar congener, A. altamurgiensis from Taeniatherum caput-medusae. Analysis of MT-CO1 sequence divergence revealed significant levels of genetic variation (17.7%) and supported the results from the morphometric analysis; therefore, it is determined that they are two different species. Aculodes marcelli sp. nov., is a new candidate agent for classical biological control of A. tectorum.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>