<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114546898</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114546898</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.76.82776</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Risk of invasiveness of non-native fishes in the South Caucasus biodiversity and geopolitical hotspot</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mumladze, Levan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuljanishvili, Tatia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Japoshvili, Bella</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Epitashvili, Giorgi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kalous, Lukáš</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vilizzi, Lorenzo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Piria, Marina</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-10-03</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>biodiversity</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Aquatic invasions are one of the major threats for freshwater ecosystems. However, in developing countries, knowledge of biological invasions, essential for the implementation of appropriate legislation, is often limited if not entirely lacking. In this regard, the identification of potentially invasive non-native species by risk screening, followed by a full risk assessment of the species ranked as higher risk, enables decision-makers to be informed about the extent of the threats posed to the recipient (risk assessment) area. In this study, 32 non-native extant and horizon fish species were screened for their risk of invasiveness under current and predicted climate conditions for the South Caucasus – a biodiversity and geopolitical hotspot that includes the countries of Armenia, Azerbaijan and Georgia. Overall, the number of very high-risk species increased from four (12.5%) under current climate conditions to 12 (37.5%) under predicted climate conditions. The highest-risk species under both conditions included the already established gibel carp Carassius gibelio and topmouth gudgeon Pseudorasbora parva, the locally translocated pikeperch Sander lucioperca and the horizon North African catfish Clarias gariepinus. Under predicted climate conditions, a very high risk of invasiveness was predicted also for the translocated three-spined stickleback Gasterosteus aculeatus and Eurasian perch Perca fluviatilis, for the already established eastern mosquitofish Gambusia holbrooki, ruffe Gymnocephalus cernua, sharpbelly Hemiculter leucisculus and Nile tilapia Orechromis niloticus, and for the horizon pumpkinseed Lepomis gibbosus and largemouth bass Micropterus salmoides. Future research on the non-native species in the South Caucasus should be conducted both country- and region-wide and should account not only for the high biodiversity, but also for the critical geopolitical situation affecting the study area.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>