<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q61816808</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q61816808</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/INSECTS10010030</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasion Dynamics of A Termite, Reticulitermes flavipes, at Different Spatial Scales in France</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Perdereau, Elfie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baudouin, Guillaume</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chevalier, Zoé</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmermann, Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dupont, Simon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dedeine, Franck</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bagneres, Anne-Genevieve</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-01-15</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>breeding system</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>genetic structure</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social Insects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>eastern subterranean termite</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Termites are social insects that can also be major pests. A well-known problem species is the subterranean termite, Reticulitermes flavipes. It is invasive in France and is thought to have arrived from Louisiana during the 18th century. While the putative source of French populations has been identified, little is known about how the termite spread following its establishment. Here, we examined expansion patterns at different spatial scales in urban areas to clarify how R. flavipes spread in France. Based on our analyses of phylogeography and population genetics, results suggest a scenario of successive introductions into the Charente-Maritime region, on the Atlantic Coast. Two major expansion fronts formed: one that spread toward the northeast and the other toward the southeast. At the regional scale, different spatial and genetic distribution patterns were observed: there was heterogeneity in Île-de-France and aggregation in Centre-Val de Loire. At the local scale, we found that our three focal urban sites each formed a single large colony that contained several secondary reproductives. Our findings represent a second step in efforts to reconstruct termite’s invasion dynamics. They also highlight the role that may have been played by the French railway network in transporting termites over long distances.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>