<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q92571472</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q92571472</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/PLANTS8080280</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Bletilla striata (Orchidaceae) Seed Coat Restricts the Invasion of Fungal Hyphae at the Initial Stage of Fungal Colonization</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Miura, Chihiro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saisho, Miharu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yagame, Takahiro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yamato, Masahide</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kaminaka, Hironori</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-08-11</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Bletilla striata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Orchidaceae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Orchids produce minute seeds that contain limited or no endosperm, and they must form an association with symbiotic fungi to obtain nutrients during germination and subsequent seedling growth under natural conditions. Orchids need to select an appropriate fungus among diverse soil fungi at the germination stage. However, there is limited understanding of the process by which orchids recruit fungal associates and initiate the symbiotic interaction. This study aimed to better understand this process by focusing on the seed coat, the first point of fungal attachment. Bletilla striata seeds, some with the seed coat removed, were prepared and sown with symbiotic fungi or with pathogenic fungi. The seed coat-stripped seeds inoculated with the symbiotic fungi showed a lower germination rate than the intact seeds, and proliferated fungal hyphae were observed inside and around the stripped seeds. Inoculation with the pathogenic fungi increased the infection rate in the seed coat-stripped seeds. The pathogenic fungal hyphae were arrested at the suspensor side of the intact seeds, whereas the seed coat-stripped seeds were subjected to severe infestation. These results suggest that the seed coat restricts the invasion of fungal hyphae and protects the embryo against the attack of non-symbiotic fungi.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>