<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114730733</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114730733</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/PLANTS11192551</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Allelopathy and Allelochemicals of Imperata cylindrica as an Invasive Plant Species</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kato-Noguchi, Hisashi</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>allelopathy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>allelochemical</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Imperata cylindrica</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Imperata cylindrica is native to Southeast Asia and East Africa and has become naturalized in humid tropics, subtropics and warmer temperate zones of the world. The species is one of the top ten worst weeds in the worlds and is listed among the world’s top 100 worst invasive alien species. It is an aggressive colonizer and forms large monospecific stands in several countries. Possible evidence of the allelopathy of I. cylindrica has been accumulated in the literature over three decades. The extracts, leachates, root exudates, decomposing residues and rhizosphere soil of I. cylindrica were found to suppress the germination and growth of several plant species, including woody plant species, and to reduce their rhizobium nodulation and mycorrhizal colonization. Several allelochemicals, such as fatty acids, terpenoids, simple phenolics, benzoic acids, phenolic acids, phenolic aldehydes, phenylpropanoids, flavonoids, quinones and alkaloids, were also found in the extracts, leachates, root exudates and/or growth medium of I. cylindrica. These observations suggest that allelochemicals may be synthesized in I. cylindrica and released into the rhizosphere soil and surrounding environments either by the leachates, root exudation or decomposition process of plant parts, and certain allelochemicals may contribute to the alteration of the microbial community, including rhizobia and mycorrhizal fungi, suppressing the regeneration process of native plant species through the inhibition of their germination and growth. Therefore, the allelopathy of I. cylindrica may support its invasiveness, naturalization and formation of large monospecific stands. This is the first review article focusing on the allelopathy of I. cylindrica.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>