<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q97689693</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q97689693</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/IJERPH17145166</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Working towards a Co-Ordinated Approach to Invasive Mosquito Detection, Response and Control in the UK</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vaux, Alexander G C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Johnston, Colin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dallimore, Thom</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McGinley, Liz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Strode, Clare</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Murchie, Archie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Iyanger, Nalini</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pudney, Rachel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chow, Yimmy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brand, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rea, Ian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Medlock, Jolyon M</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-07-17</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive mosquito species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The United Kingdom (UK) has reported a single detection of the eggs of the invasive mosquito vector Aedes albopictus in each of the three years from 2016 to 2018, all in southeast England. Here, we report the detection of mosquito eggs on three occasions at two sites in London and southeast England in September 2019. Mosquito traps were deployed at 56 sites, in England, Scotland, Wales, and Northern Ireland, as part of a coordinated surveillance programme with local authorities, Edge Hill University, and government departments. Response to each detection was coordinated by Public Health England’s (PHE) local health protection teams, with technical support from PHE’s Medical Entomology group, and control conducted by the respective local authority. Control, including source reduction and larviciding, was conducted within a 300 metre radius of the positive site. The response followed a National Contingency Plan for Invasive Mosquitoes: Detection of Incursions. Although the response to these incidents was rapid and well co-ordinated, recommendations are made to further develop mosquito surveillance and control capability for the UK.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>