<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q91922866</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q91922866</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/CANCERS12040939</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>S100A4 is a Biomarker of Tumorigenesis, EMT, Invasion, and Colonization of Host Organs in Experimental Malignant Mesothelioma</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nader, Jolle S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guillon, Jordan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petit, Coralie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boissard, Alice</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Franconi, Florence</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lambot, Sylvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grégoire, Marc</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Verrile, Véronique</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nawrocki-Raby, Béatrice</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Birembaut, Philippe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Coqueret, Olivier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guette, Catherine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pouliquen, Daniel L</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-04-10</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>biomarker</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Recent findings suggest that S100A4, a protein involved in communication between stromal cells and cancer cells, could be more involved than previously expected in cancer invasiveness. To investigate its cumulative value in the multistep process of the pathogenesis of malignant mesothelioma (MM), SWATH-MS (sequential window acquisition of all theoretical fragmentation spectra), an advanced and robust technique of quantitative proteomics, was used to analyze a collection of 26 preneoplastic and neoplastic rat mesothelial cell lines and models of MM with increasing invasiveness. Secondly, proteomic and histological analyses were conducted on formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded sections of liver metastases vs. primary tumor, and spleen from tumor-bearing rats vs. controls in the most invasive MM model. We found that S100A4, along with 12 other biomarkers, differentiated neoplastic from preneoplastic mesothelial cell lines, and invasive vs. non-invasive tumor cells in vitro, and MM tumors in vivo. Additionally, S100A4 was the only protein differentiating preneoplastic mesothelial cell lines with sarcomatoid vs. epithelioid morphology in relation to EMT (epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition). Finally, S100A4 was the most significantly increased biomarker in liver metastases vs. primary tumor, and in the spleen colonized by MM cells. Overall, we showed that S100A4 was the only protein that showed increased abundance in all situations, highlighting its crucial role in all stages of MM pathogenesis.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>