<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114918356</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114918356</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/AGRONOMY12020423</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Accidental Introduction and Spread of Top Invasive Alien Plants in the European Union through Human-Mediated Agricultural Pathways: What Should We Expect?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Montagnani, Chiara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gentili, Rodolfo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brundu, Giuseppe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Caronni, Sarah</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Citterio, Sandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-02-08</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Alien species are among the five drivers of environmental change with the largest relative global impacts. In particular, horticulture is a major introduction pathway of alien plants, but, together with intentional introductions, plants can also be introduced and spread via human-mediated involuntary pathways as contaminants and stowaways. Recurring accidental introductions of alien plants to new areas can be the prelude to invasion on a large scale. Agriculture represents a sector that is severely impacted by invasive alien species and, at the same time, it is likely to be one of the main factors responsible of biological invasions. So, the present review highlights risks related to accidental introduction though human-mediated agricultural pathways of a politically relevant group of alien plants, invasive alien plants of Union concern (IAPUC), that are species whose prevention and management is mandatory in the European Union according to Regulation (EU) n. 1143/2014. Even if most IAPUC have been primarily introduced as economic plants, several accidental pathways related to agriculture can be identified for each one of them. The implementation of technologies and the sharing of good practices, at a wide scale and at different levels of the society, would help in overcoming several problematic issues related to the accidental transport of IAPUC.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>