<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q92874881</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q92874881</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.mdpi.com/1422-0067/20/17/4138</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/IJMS20174138</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Phylogenetically Defined Isoforms of Listeria monocytogenes Invasion Factor InlB Differently Activate Intracellular Signaling Pathways and Interact with the Receptor gC1q-R</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chalenko, Yaroslava</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chalenko, Yaroslava</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kalinin, Egor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marchenkov, Victor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sysolyatina, Elena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Surin, Alexey</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sobyanin, Konstantin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ermolaeva, Svetlana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ermolaeva, Svetlana</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-08-24</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Listeria monocytogenes</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The pathogenic Gram-positive bacterium Listeria monocytogenes has been evolving into a few phylogenetic lineages. Phylogenetically defined substitutions were described in the L. monocytogenes virulence factor InlB, which mediates active invasion into mammalian cells via interactions with surface receptors c-Met and gC1q-R. InlB internalin domain (idInlB) is central to interactions with c-Met. Here we compared activity of purified recombinant idInlB isoforms characteristic for L. monocytogenes phylogenetic lineage I and II. Size exclusion chromatography and intrinsic fluorescence were used to characterize idInlBs. Western blotting was used to study activation of c-Met-dependent MAPK- and PI3K/Akt-pathways. Solid-phase microplate binding and competition assay was used to quantify interactions with gCq1-R. Isogenic recombinant L. monocytogenes strains were used to elucidate the input of idInlB isoforms in HEp-2 cell invasion. Physicochemical parameters of idInlB isoforms were similar but not identical. Kinetics of Erk1/2 and Akt phosphorylation in response to purified idInlBs was lineage specific. Lineage I but not lineage II idInlB specifically bound gC1q-R. Antibody against gC1q-R amino acids 221–249 inhibited invasion of L. monocytogenes carrying lineage I but not lineage II idInlB. Taken together, obtained results suggested that phylogenetically defined substitutions in idInlB provide functional distinctions and might be involved in phylogenetically determined differences in virulence potential.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>