<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q28710431</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q28710431</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3514011</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/SREP00871</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ecology of cryptic invasions: latitudinal segregation among Watersipora (Bryozoa) species</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mackie, Joshua A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Darling, John A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Geller, Jonathan B</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractWatersipora is an invasive genus of bryozoans, easily dispersed by fouled vessels. We examined Cytochrome c oxidase subunit I haplotypes from introduced populations on the US Pacific coastline to investigate geographic segregation of species and/or haplotypes. In California, the W. subtorquata group fell into three major sub-groups: W. subtorquata clades A and B and W. “new sp.”. W. subtorquata clades A and B were common in southern California south of Point Conception, a recognized biogeographic boundary, whereas further north, W. subtorquata clade A and W. n. sp. were frequent. The southern California region also had colonies of a morphologically distinct species, W. arcuata, also found in southern Australia and Hawaii; COI variation indicates a common ancestral source(s) in these introductions. The distribution of Watersipora-complex lineages on different coastlines is shown to be temperature correlated. Accordingly, pre-exisitng temperature-based adaptations may play a key role in determining invasion patterns.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>