<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q118133711</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q118133711</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3391/AI.2023.18.1.103610</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Non-native species in Poyang Lake Basin: status, threats and management</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Xiong, Wen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xie, Dong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Qiang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Hui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wu, Zhigang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sun, Heying</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Tao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bowler, Peter A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-04-18</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Regional Euro-Asian Biological Invasions Centre Oy (REABIC)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Poyang Lake is the largest freshwater lake in China and sustains a high level of biodiversity in the mid-reach area of the Yangtze River watershed. Poyang Lake is also one of the most important aquaculture regions in China, and a great number of non-native species have been introduced into it. We present a current and well-documented list of the non-native species of plants, molluscs, crustaceans, fishes, reptiles, and amphibians currently found in Lake. We found that there are 103 non-native species (83 vascular plants, 12 fishes, three crustacea, two molluscs, two reptiles and one amphibian) that have invaded Poyang Lake Basin, of which 96 non-native species were introduced after 2000. The invasion rate of non-native species reached 4.36 species year-1, which is the highest invasion rate recorded in freshwater ecosystems. The primary pathways of introduction are through the ornamental trade and unintentional escapes (30 species each, respectively), followed by food (19), aquaculture (15), forage grass (four), medicinal and oil (two, respectively), and biocontrol (one). The origins of non-native species are North America (29.12%), Asia (25.24%), South America (20.38%), Africa (18.44%), Europe (5.82%) and Oceania (0.97%). Many non-native species provide significant support for the rapid development of the local economy (such as aquaculture). However, many non-native species pose a great threat to local biodiversity and societal development. More studies that include monitoring and the development of strategies for managing and eliminating non-native species in Poyang Lake are needed.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>