<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q30914695</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/J.IJPARA.2003.10.009</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasion success of Fibrillanosema crangonycis, n.sp., n.g.: a novel vertically transmitted microsporidian parasite from the invasive amphipod host Crangonyx pseudogracilis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Galbreath, Johanna G M Slothouber</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smith, Judith E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Terry, Rebecca S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Becnel, James J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dunn, Alison M</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2004-02-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://www.elsevier.com/tdm/userlicense/1.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>vertical transmission</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>species nova</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier BV</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Parasitism is known to be an important factor in determining the success of biological invasions. Here we examine Crangonyx pseudogracilis, a North American amphipod invasive in the United Kingdom and describe a novel microsporidium, Fibrillanosema crangonycis n.sp., n.g. The primary site of infection is the female gonad and the parasite is transovarially transmitted to the eggs. PCR screening reveals a female bias in the distribution of parasites (96.6% of females, N=29; 22.2% of males, N=27), which is indicative of host sex ratio distortion. The morphological and molecular characterisations of this new microsporidium place it outside all currently established genera. On the basis of these differences, we erect the new genus Fibrillanosema n.g. While F. crangonycis is morphologically identical to uncharacterised microsporidia from populations of North American amphipods, it is distinct from microsporidia found in European populations of amphipods. These data support the hypothesis that vertically transmitted parasites may be selectively retained during invasion events. Furthermore where vertical transmission is combined with host sex ratio distortion these parasites may directly enhance host invasion success through increased rates of population growth.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>