<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111248692</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1051/E3SCONF/202125703023</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Research Progress on Growth Characteristics of Invasive Plants in Different Habitats</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Zhe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yue, Ruirui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Yang</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-05-12</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>EDP Sciences</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Biological invasion generates serious threats to global biodiversity. Exotic species usually have high environmental adaptability and tolerance, which is one of the bases of their invasion. Except for biological invasion threats, other serious environmental problems like extreme cold or hot events, soil drought, saline-alkali and flood are emerging constantly on a global scale. In the background of multiple environmental problems interfering with existing habitats, exploring the growth characteristics of invasive plants in different habitats, and grasping the reasons why the invasive plants can obtain growth superiorities are in favor of propelling the understanding of their invasion mechanism. This paper gives an overview of research progress on the invasive plants’ morphological characteristics and physiological characteristics in deferent habitats, summarizes the growth specialties of invasive plants which are affected by high temperature, low temperature, drought and flood, and discusses the reasons why the invasive plants prevail in the growth competitions, which provided theoretical and realistic signification to relieve the biological invasion current status.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>