<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117804689</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117804689</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.78.87069</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>_The invasiveness of Guinea grass (Megathyrsus maximus) is characterized by habitat and differing herbivore assemblages in its native and invaded range</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rhodes, Aaron C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Plowes, Robert M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martins, Dino J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ng’Iru, Ivy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gilbert, Lawrence E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-11-11</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Megathyrsus maximus</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive range</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>A significant challenge of global change is the human-mediated movement of pasture grasses and their subsequent impact on ecosystem processes when they become invasive. We must understand invasive grass ecology and their natural enemies in native and introduced ranges to mitigate these impacts. Guinea grass (Megathyrsus maximus) is a pantropically introduced pasture grass that escapes intended areas and invades native ecosystems – threatening biodiversity and ecosystem function. The success of invasive plants has often been attributed to ecological release from stressors, including natural enemies and resource availability. Our objective was to assess Guinea grass functional traits across three different habitat types in native and invaded ranges by documenting ungulate and arthropod abundance, diversity, and feeding guilds. Guinea grass functional traits were assessed in three habitat types: grassland, riparian, and woody thickets around nitrogen-fixing Prosopis glandulosa in its introduced range in Texas, USA, and Senegalia mellifera in its native range in Kenya. We characterized Guinea grass functional traits by measuring plant height, cover, biomass, root-to-shoot ratios, and reproductive traits. We then examined the phytophagous arthropod and ungulate abundance and feeding guild diversity across the three habitat types. We hypothesized that functional trait expression related to invasiveness would be associated with Guinea grass in its introduced range. Also, we hypothesized that the abundance and diversity of phytophagous arthropods and ungulates would be lower in the invaded range. Finally, we hypothesized that Guinea grass functional traits would differ between the three habitat types, given the habitat types’ innate differences in resource availability. We found that Guinea grass was 2.5 times taller and 3.3 times more productive and covered 2.5 times more area in its invaded versus native ranges. Introduced Guinea grass had higher reproduction rates with 2.5 times more reproductive tillers, while habitat type drove vegetative reproduction with 15 times more stoloniferous establishment in wooded and riparian sites than grasslands. Texan ungulate communities were less species-rich, less functionally diverse, and less abundant than the Kenyan ungulate community. The phytophagous arthropod diversity on plants was twice as high on Kenyan Guinea grass than on Texan Guinea grass. Total arthropod family richness was nearly double, with 15 families represented in Kenya and 8 in Texas. These results suggest that Guinea grass has escaped a rich assemblage of arthropods and ungulates and likely explains some of its spread in introduced ranges. This study demonstrates how the invasive success of Guinea grass can be understood in terms of its competitive ability and interaction with natural enemies in the introduced and native ranges and may inform future biological control.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>