<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110756344</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110756344</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/PATHOGENS10101272</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Comparative Efficacy of State-of-the-Art and New Biological Stump Treatments in Forests Infested by the Native and the Alien Invasive Heterobasidion Species Present in Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pellicciaro, Martina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lione, Guglielmo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ongaro, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gonthier, Paolo</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-10-02</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>forest invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The Heterobasidion annosum species complex includes major fungal pathogens of conifers worldwide. State-of-the-art preventative stump treatments with urea or with commercial formulations of the fungal biological control agent Phlebiopsis gigantea (i.e., Rotstop®) may become no longer available or are not approved for use in many areas of Europe infested by the three native Heterobasidion species and by the North American invasive H. irregulare, making the development of new treatments timely. The efficacy of Proradix® (based on Pseudomonas protegens strain DSMZ 13134), the cell-free filtrate (CFF) of the same bacterium, a strain of P. gigantea (MUT 6212) collected in the invasion area of H. irregulare in Italy, Rotstop®, and urea was comparatively investigated on a total of 542 stumps of Abies alba, Picea abies, Pinus pinea, and P. sylvestris in forest stands infested by the host-associated Heterobasidion species. Additionally, 139 logs of P. pinea were also treated. Results support the good performances of Rotstop®, and especially of urea against the native Heterobasidion species on stumps of their preferential hosts and, for the first time, towards the invasive North American H. irregulare on stumps of P. pinea. In some experiments, the effectiveness of Proradix® and of the strain of P. gigantea was weak, whereas the CFF of P. protegens strain DSMZ 13134 performed as a valid alternative to urea and Rotstop®. The mechanism of action of this treatment hinges on antibiosis; therefore, further improvements could be possible by identifying the active molecules and/or by optimizing their production. Generally, the performance of the tested treatments is not correlated with the stump size.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>