<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q53819578</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q53819578</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S00572-018-0836-X</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Current and potential distribution of the ectomycorrhizal fungus Suillus lakei ((Murrill) A.H. Sm. &amp; Thiers) in its invasion range</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pietras, Marcin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Litkowiec, Monika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gobiewska, Joanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-05-15</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Ectomycorrhiza</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Suillus lakei is an ectomycorrhizal fungus native to North America and known in Europe, South America, and New Zealand. This contribution aims to illustrate the worldwide biogeography of S. lakei based on sporocarp records. Species distribution modeling was used to assess the suitable niche distribution of S. lakei, based on the climatic variables as well as distribution of its ectomycorrhizal partner, Douglas fir. In general, distribution of suitable niches of S. lakei greatly overlaps with the distribution of Douglas fir in North America. By spatial distribution modeling, we found that the precipitation of the coldest quarters, isothermality, and annual mean temperature are important factors influencing the potential distribution of S. lakei. Nevertheless, the most crucial factor limiting expansion of S. lakei in its invasion range is Douglas fir occurrence. This factor reached an 86.4% contribution for the S. lakei species distribution model. Additionally, we compare the aboveground and belowground presence of S. lakei based on surveys in the field. Our study shows that even extremely low abundance of ectomycorrhizas can open the possibility of using an ectomycorrhiza survey for their quantification as a good indicator of the presence of S. lakei in field conditions. Both sporocarps and ectomycorrhizas occurred only in gardens, where Douglas fir seedlings were outplanted at the beginning of the 1990s as an ornamental plant. Presumably, international trade of ornamental plants was one possible route of introduction of S. lakei to Poland.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>