<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114939794</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114939794</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1088/1755-1315/446/5/052104</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Study on the Invasion Mechanism of Alien Species through Ship Activities</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lan, Ru</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Qiao, Bing</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-02-01</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>water transport</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion mechanism</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>IOP Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract
               This paper analyzes the harm of invasion of alien species caused by ship activities, and expounds the necessity and urgency of carrying out relevant research in China. This paper summarizes the research progress at home and abroad, analyzes the research defects, and proposes that the research on the invasion mechanism of alien species caused by ship activities in China should focus on solving the major scientific problems such as the process and evolution of the invasion disaster, the interaction between the invasion and the offshore ecological environment security. In addition, it is necessary to consider the different invasion stages of alien species, such as invasion-escape period, population establishment period, latent-lag period and spread-outbreak(disaster) period. Finally, the key technologies and implementation plans to solve major scientific problems are proposed. The results show that, the interpretation of the model is generally consistent with the actual situation. Through database construction and typical species experiments, the theoretical model of alien invasion mechanism introduced by ship activities is interpreted and proved.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>