<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110759232</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110759232</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1051/KMAE/2019013</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The use of native piscivorous fishes for the eradication of the invasive Chinese Sleeper, Perccottus glenii</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rakauskas, Vytautas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Virbickas, Tomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stakėnas, Saulius</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steponėnas, Andrius</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Chinese sleeper</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>piscivory</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>EDP Sciences</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The chief aim of invasive species management is to prevent biological invasions by taking measures for suppressing or eradicating potential invaders. Biological control as a management tool is frequently implemented to reduce the population size, adverse ecological impacts, and dispersal of invasive species. The efficacy of biological control measures in managing thePerccottus gleniipopulation was assessed in four small lakes of Lithuania. The biocontrol was carried out by introducing the native piscivorous fishesEsox luciusandPerca fluviatilisinto the invaded water bodies for two successive reproductive seasons. The stocking of these fishes led to an instant reduction inP._gleniiabundances, and the outcome of the repeated stocking was complete disappearance of the species from the water bodies investigated. Our study proves that native predator fishes can be successfully used for eradicating well-establishedP._gleniipopulations in small eutrophic lakes. We hope the current study results will contribute to developing risk-commensurate methodologies for the control of invasiveP._gleniipopulations in small water bodies.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>