<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110829174</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110829174</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1051/KMAE/2020003</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Mass appearance of the Ponto-Caspian invader Pontogammarus robustoides in the River Tisza catchment: bypass in the southern invasion corridor?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Csabai, Zoltán</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Borza, Péter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rewicz, Tomasz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pernecker, Bálint</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berta, Balázs J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Móra, Arnold</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>EDP Sciences</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The river Danube is the backbone of the ‘southern invasion corridor’, one of the most important passages for the spread of Ponto-Caspian invaders in Europe. However, not all of these species used the passive or active upstream movement in the main channel to reach the upper sections and tributaries, some found detours. Mass occurrences of the Ponto-Caspian peracarid, Pontogammarus robustoides (Sars, 1894) were recorded at 17 sites along the entire Hungarian section of the River Maros, for the first time in the River Tisza catchment and also in Hungary. Those populations are found ca. 707_km upstream from the closest known and confirmed locality in the lower Danube section. We confirmed their identity by DNA barcoding and showed that all individuals fit in with the lower Danube population, thus identifying the source of this introduction. The most likely vector allowing the jump dispersal of the species is fish stocking in the Romanian section of the River Maros, which − combined with downstream drift to the Serbian Danube section and the relatively busy ship traffic between Belgrade and Vienna − might provide the opportunity to bypass the dispersal barrier represented by the unregulated Middle Danube and open the way towards Western Europe.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>