<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117804683</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117804683</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.79.86778</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>_Low genetic diversity in a widespread whistling alien: A comparison of Eleutherodactylus johnstonei Barbour, 1914 (Eleutherodactylidae) and congeners in native and introduced ranges</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leonhardt, Franziska</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aveces, Clara Arranz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Müller, Anke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Angin, Baptiste</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jegu, Mathieu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haynes, Pius</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ernst, Raffael</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-12-23</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Coqui Antillano</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Eleutherodactylidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>There is no clear empirical evidence to support the general assumption that genetic diversity favours successful invasions. Many invading species disperse and establish successfully despite low genetic diversity, a phenomenon known as the genetic paradox of biological invasion. Model systems that allow comparison of genetic patterns between exotic and native source populations are still scarce. This is particularly true for amphibians. Here we compare genetic patterns of the widely introduced Johnstone’s Whistling Frog, Eleutherodactylus johnstonei, with its successful alien congener E. antillensis and the single island endemic E. portoricensis. Genetic diversity and population differentiation in native and introduced populations of the three taxa were inferred from mitochondrial D-loop sequences (235 bp). Our results reveal that exotic populations of the two alien taxa, E. johnstonei and E. antillensis, are not only genetically impoverished due to founder effects, but that, moreover, their native range source-populations exhibit low genetic diversity and inter-population differentiation in the first place. Populations of the endemic E. portoricensis, on the other hand, are genetically more diverse and show marked inter-population differentiation. These observed genetic patterns are consistent with geological processes and invasion histories. We argue that the establishment success of the alien taxa in our model system is better explained by ecological factors and anthropogenic drivers than by genetic diversity. As these factors provide more parsimonious explanations, they should be given priority in management decisions. However, molecular studies with higher resolution are needed to fully test possible genetic and epigenetic components that could promote the invasion process.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>