<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111148618</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/TOXICS9060121</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ocean Warming May Enhance Biochemical Alterations Induced by an Invasive Seaweed Exudate in the Mussel Mytilus galloprovincialis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vieira, Hugo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rodrigues, Andreia C. M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pires, Sílvia F. S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oliveira, Jacinta M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rocha, Rui J.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Soares, Amadeu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bordalo, Maria D</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-05-31</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Mytilus galloprovincialis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>exudate</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive seaweed</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Ocean warming and biological invasions are among the most pervasive factors threatening coastal ecosystems with a potential to interact. Ongoing temperature rise may affect physiological and cellular mechanisms in marine organisms. Moreover, non-indigenous species spread has been a major challenge to biodiversity and ecosystem functions and services. The invasive red seaweed Asparagopsis armata has become successfully established in Europe. Its exudate has been considered deleterious to surrounding native species, but no information exists on its effect under forecasted temperature increase. This study evaluated the combined effects of temperature rise and A. armata exudate exposure on the native mussel Mytilus galloprovincialis. Oxidative stress, neurophysiological and metabolism related biomarkers were evaluated after a 96 h-exposure to exudate (0% and 2%) under present (20 °C) and warming (24 °C) temperature scenarios. Short-term exposure to A. armata exudate affected the oxidative stress status and neurophysiology of the mussels, with a tendency to an increasing toxic action under warming. Significant oxidative damage at protein level was observed in the digestive gland and muscle of individuals exposed simultaneously to the exudate and temperature rise. Thus, under a climate change scenario, it may be expected that prolonged exposure to the combined action of both stressors may compromise M. galloprovincialis fitness and survival.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>