<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q35252603</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q35252603</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4164352</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0075396</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Evaluating ecosystem services provided by non-native species: an experimental test in California grasslands</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stein, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hallett, Lauren M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Harpole, William Stanley</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Suding, Katharine N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2014-09-15</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>California</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ecosystem</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>grassland</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The concept of ecosystem services--the benefits that nature provides to human's society--has gained increasing attention over the past decade. Increasing global abiotic and biotic change, including species invasions, is threatening the secure delivery of these ecosystem services. Efficient evaluation methods of ecosystem services are urgently needed to improve our ability to determine management strategies and restoration goals in face of these new emerging ecosystems. Considering a range of multiple ecosystem functions may be a useful way to determine such strategies. We tested this framework experimentally in California grasslands, where large shifts in species composition have occurred since the late 1700's. We compared a suite of ecosystem functions within one historic native and two non-native species assemblages under different grazing intensities to address how different species assemblages vary in provisioning, regulatory and supporting ecosystem services. Forage production was reduced in one non-native assemblage (medusahead). Cultural ecosystem services, such as native species diversity, were inherently lower in both non-native assemblages, whereas most other services were maintained across grazing intensities. All systems provided similar ecosystem services under the highest grazing intensity treatment, which simulated unsustainable grazing intensity. We suggest that applying a more comprehensive ecosystem framework that considers multiple ecosystem services to evaluate new emerging ecosystems is a valuable tool to determine management goals and how to intervene in a changing ecosystem.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>