<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q113739889</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113739889</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1590/1519-6984.248656</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Reduced genetic diversity and the success of the invasive peacock bass (Cichliformes: Cichlidae)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Luz, S. C. S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Montes, M. A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Farias, R. S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lima, R. V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Torres, R. A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ferreira, Efrem J. G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Severi, William</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Coimbra, Maria Raquel Moura</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2024-07-02</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q112148709</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cichlidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cichla kelberi</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive fish</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>freshwater invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>FapUNIFESP (SciELO)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract Several species of Cichla successfully colonized lakes and reservoirs of Brazil, since the 1960’s, causing serious damage to local wildlife. In this study, 135 peacock bass were collected in a reservoir complex in order to identify if they represented a single dominant species or multiple ones, as several Cichla species have been reported in the basin. Specimens were identified by color pattern, morphometric and meristic data, and using mitochondrial markers COI, 16S rDNA and Control Region (CR). Overlapping morphological data and similar coloration patterns prevented their identification using the taxonomic keys to species identification available in the literature. However, Bayesian and maximum likelihood from sequencing data demonstrated the occurrence of a single species, Cichla kelberi. A single haplotype was observed for the 16S and CR, while three were detected for COI, with a dominant haplotype present in 98.5% of the samples. The extreme low diversity of the transplanted C. kelberi evidenced a limited number of founding maternal lineages. The success of this colonization seems to rely mainly on abiotic factors, such as increased water transparency of lentic environments that favor visual predators that along with the absence of predators, have made C. kelberi a successful invader of these reservoirs.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>