<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114921604</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114921604</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.22146/JPTI.46455</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Occurrence of Heavy Infestation by the Fall Armyworm Spodoptera frugiperda, a New Alien Invasive Pest, in Corn Lampung Indonesia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Trisyono, Y. Andi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Suputa, Suputa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aryuwandari, Valentina Erline Febry</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartaman, Maman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jumari, Jumari</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-07-03</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Spodoptera frugiperda</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universitas Gadjah Mada</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The fall armyworm Spodoptera frugiperda has spread and damaged corn in many African and a few Asian Countries recently. A recent outbreak (2019) of Spodoptera species in corn producing areas in the Island of Sumatra was suspected to be a new invasive species. Field observations were made on May 16, 2019 in the District of East and Central Lampung to identify the attacking Spodoptera species, and to observe and determine the damages. Based on the morphological characteristics, the Y inverted shape on the head capsule and the patterns of black spots on the abdominal segments (square and trapezoidal forms), the species was confirmed as S. frugiperda. The larvae heavily damaged the early stage of corn (approximately 2-week old) with 100% plants infested and each plant was occupied by a medium or large larva; while older corn received less damage. Larvae fed on the leaves causing defoliation before feeding on the growing point. Different damage symptoms due to S. frugiperda were compared to those of the Asian corn borer, Ostrinia furnacalis, and further discussion was made to determine the potential consequences of this new threat to the corn production in Indonesia.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>