<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q28816950</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q28816950</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5241644</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/SREP40697</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Seasonal and regional presence of hymenopteran parasitoids of Drosophila in Switzerland and their ability to parasitize the invasive Drosophila suzukii</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Knoll, Valery</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ellenbroek, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Romeis, Jörg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Collatz, Jana</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-01-18</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Hymenoptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Switzerland</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Drosophila suzukii</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractSince its introduction into Europe the invasive Drosophila suzukii has established and spread widely, thereby entering habitats populated by native Drosophila species and their natural enemies. The highly prolific D. suzukii will likely interact with these species as a competitor, host or prey. To investigate potential interactions of D. suzukii with parasitoids, a field survey was conducted across several fruit-growing regions in Switzerland in two consecutive years. Eight species of hymenopteran parasitoids were collected using D. melanogaster as sentinel hosts in field-traps. Parasitoid capture was much higher in 2015 than in 2014 and varied among regions, time of the growing season, and habitat type. Laboratory no-choice assays with the field-collected species demonstrated that the larval parasitoids Asobara tabida, Leptopilina boulardi, and L. heterotoma could not use D. suzukii for reproduction, although the latter two reduced the number of emerging D. suzukii. In contrast, the pupal parasitoids Pachycrepoideus vindemmiae, Trichopria drosophilae, Vrestovia fidenas and Spalangia erythromera all developed with D. suzukii as hosts. Regional differences between strains were generally not evident, with the exception of two T. drosophilae strains that differed in parasitization rate. Thus, native parasitoids may interact with D. suzukii and should be regarded when implementing pest control measures.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>