<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q47160596</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1242/BIO.029926</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The constant threat from a non-native predator increases tail muscle and fast-start swimming performance in Xenopus tadpoles</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mori, Tsukasa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yanagisawa, Yukio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kitani, Yoichiro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yamamoto, Goshi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Goto-Inoue, Naoko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kimura, Tadashi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kashiwagi, Keiko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kashiwagi, Akihiko</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-11-15</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>predation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>non-native predator</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The Company of Biologists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;ABSTRACT&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Predator-induced phenotypic plasticity is the ability of prey to adapt to their native predator. However, owing to environmental changes, encounters with unknown predators are inevitable. Therefore, study of prey and non-native predator interaction will reveal the primary stages of adaptive strategies in prey-predator interactions in the context of evolutionary processes. Here, Xenopus tadpoles exposed to a non-native predator, a larval salamander, showed a significant increase in body weight and tail length to body length ratio. The Tmax2 test indicated a significant enhancement of the tail muscle and decrease in the relative ventral fin height in tadpoles exposed to predation risk, leading to significantly higher average swimming speeds. The analysis of muscle-related metabolites revealed that sarcosine increased significantly in tadpoles exposed to non-native predators. Multiple linear regression analysis of the fast-start swimming pattern showed that the fast-start swimming speed was determined by the time required for a tadpole to bend its body away from the threat (C-start) and the angle at which it was bent. In conclusion, morphological changes in tadpoles were functionally adaptive and induced by survival behaviors of Xenopus tadpoles against non-native predators.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>