<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111158404</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111158404</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S00338-021-02132-8</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ecological impacts of an invasive mesopredator do not differ from those of a native mesopredator: lionfish in Caribbean Panama</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Samhouri, Jameal F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stier, Adrian C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-07-04</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q112148709</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>mesopredator</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ecological impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractThe impacts of invasive lionfish (Pterois volitans/miles) on native coral reef populations in the Western Atlantic Ocean and Caribbean Sea can be enormous. However, how much lionfish differ from native predators and whether their effects outweigh the abundant mesopredators that occupy many reefs invite continued examination. Here, we present empirical evidence from Caribbean Panama and beyond suggesting that lionfish are less abundant than native mesopredators. Furthermore, we show that their direct impacts on survivorship and size distributions of one native prey species are similar to those of a native mesopredator. These results support calls for lionfish management that considers evolving local ecological and social dynamics, including prey community composition, the roles of native mesopredators, and regional goals for conservation and fisheries. Recognition of regional context creates the potential for synergies between conservation actions aimed both at the invasion and other consequential problems such as overexploitation and climate change.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>