<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110809458</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110809458</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/CELLS10123320</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The Cellular Innate Immune Response of the Invasive Pest Insect against Involves the Release of Extracellular Traps</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Carrau, Tessa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thümecke, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Silva, Liliana M R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perez-Bravo, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gärtner, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taubert, Anja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hermosilla, Carlos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vilcinskas, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Kwang-Zin</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-11-26</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive insect</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive pest species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Drosophila suzukii is a neobiotic invasive pest that causes extensive damage to fruit crops worldwide. The biological control of this species has been unsuccessful thus far, in part because of its robust cellular innate immune system, including the activity of professional phagocytes known as hemocytes and plasmatocytes. The in vitro cultivation of primary hemocytes isolated from D. suzukii third-instar larvae is a valuable tool for the investigation of hemocyte-derived effector mechanisms against pathogens such as wasp parasitoid larvae, bacteria, fungi and viruses. Here, we describe the morphological characteristics of D. suzukii hemocytes and evaluate early innate immune responses, including extracellular traps released against the entomopathogen Pseudomonas entomophila and lipopolysaccharides. We show for the first time that D. suzukii plasmatocytes cast extracellular traps to combat P. entomophila, along with other cell-mediated reactions, such as phagocytosis and the formation of filopodia.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>