<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111322856</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111322856</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/ANTIOX10020242</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Antioxidant, Pancreatic Lipase Inhibitory, and Tyrosinase Inhibitory Activities of Extracts of the Invasive Plant &lt;i&gt;Spartina anglica&lt;/i&gt; (Cord-Grass)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Geum Jin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Park, Songhee</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Eonmi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kwon, Hyukbean</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Park, Hae-Jin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nam, Joo-Won</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roh, Seong-Soo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Choi, Hyukjae</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-02-04</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Spartina anglica</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Since 2016, the invasive halophyte Spartina anglica has been colonizing mudflats along the western coast of South Korea. In order to minimize costs on S. anglica expansion management and waste-treatment of collected biomass, the potential application of the collected biomass of S. anglica was investigated. Ethanolic extracts and subfractions thereof (hexanes, methylene chloride, ethyl acetate, 1-butanol, and water-soluble) of the aerial and belowground parts of S. anglica showed free radical-scavenging [2,2-diphenyl-1-picrylhydrazyl (DPPH), and 2,2’-azino-bis(3-ethylbenzothiazoline-6-sulfonic acid) (ABTS)], tyrosinase inhibitory, and pancreatic lipase inhibitory activities. An ethyl acetate fraction derived from aerial parts (EA-a) showed the most potent radical-scavenging and pancreatic lipase inhibitory activities, whereas tyrosinase inhibition was mainly observed in the methylene chloride soluble fractions (MC-bg) and other lipophilic fractions (ethyl acetate and hexanes layers) obtained from belowground parts. The major EA-a compound isolated and identified was 1,3-di-O-trans-feruloyl quinic acid (1) based on spectroscopic analysis, whereas the two major MC-bg compounds were identified as p-hydroxybenzaldehyde (2) and N-trans-feruloyltyramine (3). Compounds 1 and 3 scavenged both DPPH and ABTS radicals, whereas 1 and 2 inhibited pancreatic lipase activity. These results indicate that extracts and fractions of S. anglica have antioxidant, anti-obesity, and whitening properties with potential pharmaceutical, cosmeceutical, and functional food applications.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>