<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q38679742</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q38679742</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/IJMS18061124</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Translational Development and Application of (13)--d-Glucan for Diagnosis and Therapeutic Monitoring of Invasive Mycoses</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>McCarthy, Matthew W</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petraitiene, Ruta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walsh, Thomas J</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-05-24</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>carbohydrate</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive fungal infections</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive mycosis</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Early diagnosis and prompt initiation of appropriate antimicrobial therapy are crucial steps in the management of patients with invasive fungal infections. However, the diagnosis of invasive mycoses remains a major challenge in clinical practice, because presenting symptoms may be subtle and non-invasive diagnostic assays often lack sensitivity and specificity. Diagnosis is often expressed on a scale of probability (proven, probable and possible) based on a constellation of imaging findings, microbiological tools and histopathology, as there is no stand-alone assay for diagnosis. Recent data suggest that the carbohydrate biomarker (13)--d-glucan may be useful in both the diagnosis and therapeutic monitoring of invasive fungal infections due to some yeasts, molds, and dimorphic fungi. In this paper, we review recent advances in the use of (13)--d-glucan to monitor clinical response to antifungal therapy and explore how this assay may be used in the future.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>