<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q59898103</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.7287/PEERJ.PREPRINTS.26701V1</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Diversity analysis and function prediction of rhizo- and endophytic bacterial communities of Senecio vulgaris L. (Asteraceae) in an invasive range</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Cheng, Dandan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tian, Zhongsai</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Feng, Liang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xu, Lin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Hongmei</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-03-14</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>groundsel</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Asteraceae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>PeerJ</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Because increasing evidence has confirmed the importance of plant-associated bacteria for plant growth and productivity, it is believed that interactions between bacteria and alien plants play an important role in plant invasions. However, the diversity of bacterial communities associated with invasive plants is poorly understood. Therefore, we investigated the diversity of rhizo- and endophytic bacteria associated with the invasive annual plant &lt;jats:italic&gt;Senecio vulgaris&lt;/jats:italic&gt; L (Asteraceae) based on bacterial 16S rRNA gene data obtained from 57 samples of four &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. vulgaris&lt;/jats:italic&gt; populations in a subtropical mountainous area in central China. Significant differences in diversity were observed between plant compartments. Rhizosphere harbored much more bacterial OTUs and showed higher alpha diversity than the leaf and root endosphere. Bacterial community composition differed substantially between compartments and locations in relative abundance profiles, especially at phyla and family level. However, the top five phyla (Proteobacteria, Firmicutes, Bacteroidetes, Actinobacteria and Acidobacteria) comprised more than 90% of abundance in all the bacterial communities. And similar endophytic communities with a shared core set of bacteria were observed from different &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. vulgaris&lt;/jats:italic&gt; populations. According to the function prediction based on the identification and abundance information of the OTU, bacteria characterized as plant pathogens, as well as those involved in ureolysis and nitrate reduction, were rich in endophytic communities. This study reveals the microbiomes and their putative function in the invasive &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. vulgaris &lt;/jats:italic&gt;plants and is also the first step for future studies on the role of interactions between bacteria and alien plants in plant invasions.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>