<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q96437354</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0234116</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Morphological and molecular data show no evidence of the proposed replacement of endemic Pomphorhynchus tereticollis by invasive P. laevis in salmonids in southern Germany</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ros, Albert F.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Basen, Timo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Teschner, Ruben J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brinker, Alexander</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-06-16</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Changes in parasite communities might result in new host-parasite dynamics and may threaten local fish populations. This phenomenon has been suggested for acanthocephalan parasites in the river Rhine and Danube where the species Pomphorhynchus tereticollis is becoming replaced by the Ponto-Caspian P. laevis. Developing knowledge on morphologic, genetic and behavioural differences between such species is important to follow such changes. However, disagreements on the current phylogeny of these two acanthocephalan species are producing conflicts that is affecting their correct identification. This study is offering a clearer morphological and genetic distinction between these two species. As P. tereticollis is found in rhithral tributaries of the Rhine, it was questioned whether the local salmonid populations were hosts for this species and whether P. laevis was expanding into the Rhine watershed as well. In order to test for this, brown trout, Salmo trutta, and grayling, Thymallus thymallus from South-Western Germany watersheds have been samples and screened for the occurrence of acanthocephalan parasites. For the first time, both species were confirmed to be hosts for P. tereticollis in continental Europe. P. tereticollis was found to be common, whereas P. leavis was found only at a single location in the Danube. This pattern suggest either that the expansion of P. laevis through salmonid hosts into rhithral rivers has not yet occurred, or that not yet ascertained biotic or abiotic features of rhithral rivers hinder P. laevis to spread into these areas.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>