<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q104468310</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0242574</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Conceptual frameworks for understanding the acceptability and feasibility of the minimally invasive autopsy to determine cause of death: Findings from the CADMIA Study in western Kenya</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oruko, Kelvin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maixenchs, Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Phillips-Howard, Penelope</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ondire, Maureen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Akelo, Clarah</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sanz, Ariadna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ordi, Jaume</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Menéndez, Clara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bassat, Quique</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>O Odhiambo, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Munguambe, Khatia</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-12-14</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Establishing the cause of death (CoD) is critical to better understanding health and prioritizing health investments, however the use of full post-mortem examination is rare in most low and middle-income counties for multiple reasons. The use of minimally invasive autopsy (MIA) approaches, such as needle biopsies, presents an alternate means to assess CoD. In order to understand the feasibility and acceptability of MIA among communities in western Kenya, we conducted focus groups and in-depth interviews with next-of-kin of recently deceased persons, community leaders and health care workers in Siaya and Kisumu counties. Results suggest two conceptual framework can be drawn, one with facilitating factors for acceptance of MIA due to the ability to satisfy immediate needs related to interest in learning CoD or protecting social status and honoring the deceased), and one framework covering barriers to acceptance of MIA, for reasons relating to the failure to serve an existing need, and/or the exacerbation of an already difficult time.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>