<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q118143821</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q118143821</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/D15050585</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Prioritizing Management of Invasive Alien Species of EU Concern—A Northern Perspective</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jauni, Miia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huusela, Erja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Urho, Lauri</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hyvönen, Terho</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-04-22</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive alien species (IAS) represent one of the major threats to biodiversity globally. Each member state in the EU is required to compile a management plan for IAS of Union concern. This requires risk assessments to prioritize management measures consistent with the requirements of each EU member state. Here, we review the management priorities for the 88 IAS of Union concern based on the risk assessment scheme developed for Finland. Of 88 species, 52 had not been detected in Finland and 51 species were categorized as species that fail to succeed in Finland. Climatic conditions can be regarded as a major factor limiting the success of those species. Five primary management categories were recognized. Monitoring was deemed the primary management option for 30 species, prevention of entry into Finland for 30 species, prevention of escape into nature for 17 species, prevention of further spread and/or the management of areas with high biodiversity value for 4 species and eradication for 7 species. It is concluded that national management plans should consider local environmental conditions and adjust management options according to national risk assessments.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>