<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q91147561</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q91147561</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/ANI9110923</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Interactions between Invasive Monk Parakeets (Myiopsitta monachus) and Other Bird Species during Nesting Seasons in Santiago, Chile</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Briceño, Cristóbal</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sandoval-Rodríguez, Alejandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yévenes, Karina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larraechea, Matilde</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morgado, Angello</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chappuzeau, Catalina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Muñoz, Víctor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dufflocq, Pablo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olivares, Florencia</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-11-05</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Monk Parakeet</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The monk parakeet (Myiopsitta monachus) is considered to be one of the most invasive bird species because its unique ability among parrots to build their own communal nests. Currently, they are considered an invasive species in 19 countries and a pesteven in their native distributionbecause of economic losses derived from their impacts. During the reproductive seasons of 2017 and 2018, we registered interactions between invasive monk parakeets and resident bird species in Santiago, Chile. We observed agonistic and affiliative interactions, and further, we described monk parakeets’ nest occupancy by nine bird species, two invasive and seven native. For this reason, we consider that the monk parakeet is an allogenic ecosystem engineer with the potential to shape distribution and richness of sympatric species in urban environments. Our results contribute to an assessment of the implications of the monk parakeet’s ecological invasion to other synanthropic species, and raise concern of other potential impacts, such as pathogen transmission derived from these interactions.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>