<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q28742698</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q28742698</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3039963</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/IJMS12010456</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Isolation and characterization of the first microsatellite markers for the endangered relict mussel Hypanis colorata (Mollusca: Bivalvia: Cardiidae)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Popa, Oana Paula</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Iorgu, Elena Iulia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krapal, Ana Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kelemen, Beatrice Simona</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Murariu, Dumitru</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Popa, Luis Ovidiu</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2011-01-17</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>organic chemistry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>catalysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>microsatellite</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cardiidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Hypanis colorata (Eichwald, 1829) (Cardiidae: Lymnocardiinae) is a bivalve relict species with a Ponto-Caspian distribution and is under strict protection in Romania, according to national regulations. While the species is depressed in the western Black Sea lagoons from Romania and Ukraine, it is also a successful invader in the middle Dniepr and Volga regions. Establishing a conservation strategy for this species or studying its invasion process requires knowledge about the genetic structure of the species populations. We have isolated and characterized nine polymorphic microsatellite markers in H. colorata. The number of alleles per locus ranged from 4 to 28 and the observed heterozygosity ranged from 0.613 to 1.000. The microsatellites developed in the present study are highly polymorphic and they should be useful for the assessment of genetic variation within this species.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>