<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110757934</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.2174/1874401X01811010001</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Have Invasive Mysids (Mysis diluviana) Altered the Capacity of Osoyoos Lake, British Columbia to Produce Sockeye Salmon (Oncorhynchus nerka)?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hyatt, Kim D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McQueen, Donald J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ogden, Athena D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-05-31</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>sockeye salmon</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Mysis diluviana</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Bentham Science Publishers Ltd.</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:sec&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Background:&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;During 2005-13, at Osoyoos Lake, British Columbia, we investigated trophic relationships among fry of&lt;jats:italic&gt;Oncorhynchus nerka&lt;/jats:italic&gt;Walbaum (Sockeye and kokanee), a suite of limnetic planktivores including&lt;jats:italic&gt;Mysis diluviana&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, and their zooplankton prey.&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;/jats:sec&gt;&lt;jats:sec&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Objectives:&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Our goal was to quantify the impacts that a recently introduced population of&lt;jats:italic&gt;Mysis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;would have on density, growth and survival of resident age-0 Sockeye Salmon.&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;/jats:sec&gt;&lt;jats:sec&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Methods:&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Evidence of&lt;jats:italic&gt;Mysis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;impact was based on (&lt;jats:bold&gt;a&lt;/jats:bold&gt;) simple correlation analysis between various biophysical performance measures and (&lt;jats:bold&gt;b&lt;/jats:bold&gt;) production and bioenergetics models used to identify the strength of bottom-up (&lt;jats:italic&gt;i.e&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. production-driven) and top-down (&lt;jats:italic&gt;i.e.&lt;/jats:italic&gt;consumption-driven) processes.&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;/jats:sec&gt;&lt;jats:sec&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Results:&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;This nine-year study indicated that the Osoyoos Lake food web was strongly influenced by external events These included: large annual variations in river discharge, an earthen dam failure and effluent input from an Okanagan River tributary, and highly variable recruitment of&lt;jats:italic&gt;O. nerka&lt;/jats:italic&gt;fry given out-of-basin factors (harvest, marine survival) controlling adult salmon returns. Surprisingly, large annual variations in&lt;jats:italic&gt;O. nerka&lt;/jats:italic&gt;recruitment (0.63 - 7.0 million fry), did not induce significant “top-down” associations in growth, survival or subsequent production among the macro-planktivores (pelagic fish and&lt;jats:italic&gt;Mysis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;) and their zooplankton prey. A single significant correlation (p ≤ 0.05) between&lt;jats:italic&gt;O. nerka&lt;/jats:italic&gt;fry abundance and their von Bertalanffy&lt;jats:italic&gt;W&lt;/jats:italic&gt;&lt;jats:sub&gt;∞&lt;/jats:sub&gt;parameter emerged from a set of 14 potential top-down associations tested. By contrast, we identified several strongly positive “bottom-up” effects in which survival of&lt;jats:italic&gt;O. nerka&lt;/jats:italic&gt;fry was significantly associated (p ≤ 0.01) with annual variations in total zooplankton biomass,&lt;jats:italic&gt;Daphnia&lt;/jats:italic&gt;biomass and&lt;jats:italic&gt;Epischura&lt;/jats:italic&gt;biomass. Our results indicate that&lt;jats:italic&gt;Mysis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;played a dual role in the Osoyoos Lake pelagic food web. As predators, they accounted for an average (June-October) of 64% of the total prey biomass consumed by fish and&lt;jats:italic&gt;Mysis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. As prey,&lt;jats:italic&gt;Mysis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;contributed an average of 35% of the prey biomass consumed by fish. Consumption by fish and&lt;jats:italic&gt;Mysis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;together accounted for daily losses of only 4.5% of non-mysid zooplankton biomass and 34% of daily zooplankton production.&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;/jats:sec&gt;&lt;jats:sec&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;We conclude that in all years, combined prey consumption by&lt;jats:italic&gt;Mysis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;and fish was never high enough, acting alone, to reduce the availability of their potential zooplankton forage base. However, we also estimate that in the absence of&lt;jats:italic&gt;Mysis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;,&lt;jats:italic&gt;O. nerka&lt;/jats:italic&gt;fry could experience a 43% increase in their daily food intake and that fish and&lt;jats:italic&gt;Mysis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;might control their principal prey taxa when exogenous factors (&lt;jats:italic&gt;e.g.&lt;/jats:italic&gt;annual discharge) induced major reductions in zooplankton biomass. Finally, although&lt;jats:italic&gt;Mysis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;has clearly altered the energy flow pathways from plankton to fish in the Osoyoos Lake food-web, mysids have not precluded rebuilding&lt;jats:italic&gt;O. nerka&lt;/jats:italic&gt;abundance to levels at or exceeding historic maxima.&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;/jats:sec&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>