<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q35544611</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/J.MARPOLBUL.2014.12.046</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Introduction of the alien Xenostrobus securis (Bivalvia: Mytilidae) into Hong Kong, China: interactions with and impacts upon native species and the earlier introduced Mytilopsis sallei (Bivalvia: Dreissenidae).</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Morton, Brian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leung, K F</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2015-01-16</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://www.elsevier.com/tdm/userlicense/1.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Xenostrobus securis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Black-striped mussel</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>native species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Mytilidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dreissenidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier BV</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>This constitutes the first record of the Australian alien mytilid Xenostrobus securis in China. The introduction occurred prior to 2010 probably via shipping arriving at Yantian in Mirs Bay, China, close to Hong Kong. Point sources of infection could be Australia or Korea or Japan where it has similarly been introduced. Analysis of X. securis in Hong Kong shows that it tolerates a wide range of salinities from 5.4‰ to 28.7‰. Water temperatures in Hong Kong match those in its native range. In Hong Kong, X. securis co-occurs with the similarly introduced Mytilopsis sallei and a native bivalve community. The population structure of X. securis suggests a lifespan of &gt;2 years with new generations produced by conspecifics. Such a life history strategy is also exhibited by M. sallei. Now established in China, northern Asia, the Mediterranean and, most recently, the Iberian Atlantic, the invasion of other locations by X. securis seems probable.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>