<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q35761038</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4474485</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S10530-014-0824-9</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Contributions of temporal segregation, oviposition choice, and non-additive effects of competitors to invasion success of Aedes japonicus (Diptera: Culicidae) in North America</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Murrell, Ebony G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Noden, Bruce H</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Juliano, Steven A</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2015-06-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://www.springer.com/tdm</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Culicidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Aedes</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Aedes japonicus</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>oviposition</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Diptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The mosquito &lt;i&gt;Aedes japonicus&lt;/i&gt; (Diptera: Culicidae) has spread rapidly through North America since its introduction in the 1990s. The mechanisms underlying its establishment in container communities occupied by competitors &lt;i&gt;Aedes triseriatus&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Aedes albopictus&lt;/i&gt; are unclear. Possibilities include (A) temporal separation of &lt;i&gt;A. japonicus&lt;/i&gt; from other &lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt;, (B) oviposition avoidance by &lt;i&gt;A. japonicus&lt;/i&gt; of sites containing heterospecific &lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt; larvae, and (C) non-additive competitive effects in assemblages of multiple &lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt;. Containers sampled throughout the summer in an oak-hickory forest near Eureka, MO showed peak abundance for &lt;i&gt;A. japonicus&lt;/i&gt; occurring significantly earlier in the season than either of the other &lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt; species. Despite this, &lt;i&gt;A. japonicus&lt;/i&gt; co-occurred with one other &lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt; species in 53 % of samples when present, and co-occurred with both other &lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt; in 18 % of samples. In a field oviposition experiment, &lt;i&gt;A. japonicus&lt;/i&gt; laid significantly more eggs in forest edge containers than in forest interior containers, but did not avoid containers with low or high densities of larvae of &lt;i&gt;A. triseriatus&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;A. albopictus&lt;/i&gt;, or both, compared to containers without larvae. Interspecific competitive effects (measured as decrease in the index of performance, λ') of &lt;i&gt;A. triseriatus&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;A. albopictus&lt;/i&gt; alone on &lt;i&gt;A. japonicus&lt;/i&gt; larvae were not evident at the densities used, but the effect of both &lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt; combined was significantly negative and super-additive of effects of individual interspecific competitors. Thus, neither oviposition avoidance of competitors nor non-additive competitive effects contribute to the invasion success of &lt;i&gt;A. japonicus&lt;/i&gt; in North America. Distinct seasonal phenology may reduce competitive interactions with resident &lt;i&gt;Aedes&lt;/i&gt;.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>