<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110809294</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110809294</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/INSECTS12110985</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Effect of Climate Change on Introduced and Native Agricultural Invasive Insect Pests in Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Skendžić, Sandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zovko, Monika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Živković, Ivana Pajač</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lešić, Vinko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lemić, Darija</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-10-31</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive insect</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>climate change</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Climate change and invasive species are major environmental issues facing the world today. They represent the major threats for various types of ecosystems worldwide, mainly managed ecosystems such as agriculture. This study aims to examine the link between climate change and the biological invasion of insect pest species. Increased international trade systems and human mobility have led to increasing introduction rates of invasive insects while climate change could decrease barriers for their establishment and distribution. To mitigate environmental and economic damage it is important to understand the biotic and abiotic factors affecting the process of invasion (transport, introduction, establishment, and dispersal) in terms of climate change. We highlight the major biotic factors affecting the biological invasion process: diet breadth, phenological plasticity, and lifecycle strategies. Finally, we present alien insect pest invasion management that includes prevention, eradication, and assessment of the biological invasion in the form of modelling prediction tools.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>