<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q35919892</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4749237</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0148040</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Low Predictability of Colour Polymorphism in Introduced Guppy (Poecilia reticulata) Populations in Panama</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Martínez, Celestino</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chavarría, Carmen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sharpe, Diana M T</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De León, Luis Fernando</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-02-10</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>Poecilia reticulata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Colour polymorphism is a recurrent feature of natural populations, and its maintenance has been studied in a range of taxa in their native ranges. However, less is known about whether (and how) colour polymorphism is maintained when populations are removed from their native environments, as in the case of introduced species. We here address this issue by analyzing variation in colour patterns in recently-discovered introduced populations of the guppy (Poecilia reticulata) in Panama. Specifically, we use classic colour analysis to estimate variation in the number and the relative area of different colour spots across low predation sites in the introduced Panamanian range of the species. We then compare this variation to that found in the native range of the species under low- and high predation regimes. We found aspects of the colour pattern that were both consistent and inconsistent with the classical paradigm of colour evolution in guppies. On one hand, the same colours that dominated in native populations (orange, iridescent and black) were also the most dominant in the introduced populations in Panama. On the other, there were no clear differences between either introduced-low and native low- and high predation populations. Our results are therefore only partially consistent with the traditional role of female preference in the absence of predators, and suggest that additional factors could influence colour patterns when populations are removed from their native environments. Future research on the interaction between female preference and environmental variability (e.g. multifarious selection), could help understand adaptive variation in this widely-introduced species, and the contexts under which variation in adaptive traits parallels (or not) variation in the native range.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>