<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114921501</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.2298/GSF1205061G</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Influence of nitrogen form on growth of invasive species Acer negundo L. and Ailanthus altissima (Mill.) swingle</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Djukic, Matilda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Djunisijevic-Bojovic, Danijela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grbic, Mihailo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Skocajic, Dragana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Obratov-Petkovic, Dragica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bjedov, Ivana</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012-07-02</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Ailanthus altissima</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>National Library of Serbia</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Relative amounts of nutrients, especially nitrogen, the most abundant
   macro-element, and also the distribution of ammonium ions in relation to
   nitrate ions, in the soils of different ecosystems, are determined by many
   factors. The most important are: temperature, pH of substrate, accumulation
   of organic matter, presence of allelopathic compounds, degree of oxygenation,
   etc. The ability of plants to adapt to these variations influences their
   production of bio-mass, the rate of expansion in different habitats, and the
   impact on ecosystem and biodiversity. This paper analyzes the impact of
   different forms of nitrogen (NO3 - and NH4 +) on the growth of seedlings of
   invasive species Acer negundo L. and Ailanthus altissima (Mill.) Swingle. The
   results show that nitrogen nutrition only in the form of NH4 + ions
   significantly affects the reduction in shoot dry weight. Compared to the
   nutrition with both forms of nitrogen together, aerial parts of Ailanthus
   altissima were reduced by 62.5%, and leaf area by 66.7%, while Acer negundo
   seedlings had reduction in dry mass of aboveground part by 89.5%, root by
   81.2% and leaf area by 85.8%. Nutrition with nitrate form of nitrogen led to
   a proportionally small, but statistically significant decrease in dry mass of
   aboveground parts and roots as well as leaf area of Acer negundo, while in
   Ailanthus altissima seedlings, it was only the mass reduction of aboveground
   parts that was significantly influenced, so it can be assumed that this
   species is more resistant to the lack of both forms of nitrogen. The fact
   that both species produced significantly more biomass when nitrogen was
   present in both forms may be important in controlling the spread of alien
   species, or in their potential use in phytoremediation.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>