<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111161436</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111161436</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S11273-020-09720-5</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Touch too much: aquatic disinfectant and steam exposure treatments can inhibit further spread of invasive bloody-red mysid shrimp Hemimysis anomala</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Coughlan, Neil E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>O’Hara, Shane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Crane, Kate</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dick, Jaimie T. A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>MacIsaac, Hugh J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cuthbert, Ross N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-03-29</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hemimysis anomala</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractBiosecurity protocols designed to prevent further spread of invasive alien species have become a key component of invader management strategies. However, spread-prevention of invasive peracarids is especially difficult due to ineffectiveness of detection and treatment options. For instance, bloody-red mysid shrimp, Hemimysis anomala, is a high impact ecosystem-destabilising invader, which continues to spread in both Europe and North America. Here, we examine the effectiveness of two commonly used aquatic disinfectants (Virasure®/Virkon® Aquatic), and steam treatments (≥_100_°C) to kill H. anomala. Specimens were exposed to 1% disinfectant solutions for complete immersion or mist-spray treatments, both lasting 60_s. Steam exposures lasted for 10 or 30_s. All treatments caused 100% mortality of H. anomala. Accordingly, it appears that relatively brief exposures to disinfectant and steam treatments can curtail further H. anomala spread. Therefore, these treatments should be used to decontaminate all equipment, from wetsuits to boats. In particular, steam and disinfectant spray treatments may be useful for decontamination of large, complex equipment, such as vehicles, trailers, outboard motors, or live wells on fishing boats.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>