<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110756972</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110756972</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/PLANTS11030374</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Competitive Interactions between Two Non-Native Species (Alliaria petiolata [M. Bieb.] Cavara &amp; Grande and Hesperis matronalis L.) and a Native Species (Ageratina altissima [L.] R.M. King &amp; H. Rob.)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paulus, Kassandra R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marshall, Jordan M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-01-29</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Alliaria petiolata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hesperis matronalis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Ageratina altissima</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>native species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Alliaria petiolata and Hesperis matronalis are wide-ranging non-native species in North America. Ageratina altissima is native to North America but has become a concern as an invasive species in Asia. A replacement series experiment was established to quantify the competitive interactions between these three species and to rank their relative competitiveness with each other. We assessed leaf count, chlorophyll content, and aboveground biomass with comparisons between replacement series mixtures and competition species. Overall leaf count and aboveground biomass were greatest in A. altissima and chlorophyll content was lowest in A. petiolata. Chlorophyll content and aboveground biomass were lower for A. altissima in competition with A. petiolata compared to H. matronalis. Leaf count for A. petiolata was lower in competition with A. altissima compared to H. matronalis. Aboveground biomass for H. matronalis was lower in competition regardless of the species compared to monoculture. There were also negative trends in biomass for A. petiolata in competition with increasing neighbors. However, for A. altissima, the negative trend in biomass was with A. petiolata, H. matronalis did not negatively affect A. altissima biomass. Our rank order of competitiveness was A. altissima &gt; A. petiolata &gt;&gt; H. matronalis.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>