<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q28818245</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5206335</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/AOBPLA/PLW071</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Non-native populations of an invasive tree outperform their native conspecifics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hirsch, Heidi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hensen, Isabell</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wesche, Karsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Renison, Daniel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wypior, Catherina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartmann, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wehrden, Henrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive tree</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;
               &lt;jats:p&gt;Introduced plants often face new environmental conditions in their non-native ranges. To become invasive, they need to overcome several biotic and abiotic filters that may trigger adaptive changes in life-history traits, like post-germination processes. Such early life cycle traits may play a crucial role in the colonization and establishment success of invasive plants. As a previous study revealed that seeds of non-native populations of the woody Siberian elm, Ulmus pumila, germinated faster than those of native populations, we expected growth performance of seedlings to mirror this finding. Here, we conducted a common garden greenhouse experiment using different temperature and watering treatments to compare the biomass production of U. pumila seedlings derived from 7 native and 13 populations from two non-native ranges. Our results showed that under all treatments, non-native populations were characterized by higher biomass production and enhanced resource allocation to aboveground biomass compared to the native populations. The observed enhanced growth performance of non-native populations might be one of the contributing factors for the invasion success of U. pumila due to competitive advantages during the colonization of new sites.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>