<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110862207</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PNTD.0009827</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Searching for a sign of exotic Aedes albopictus (Culicidae) introduction in major international seaports on Kyushu Island, Japan</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Yang, Chao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sunahara, Toshihiko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hu, Jinping</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Futami, Kyoko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kawada, Hitoshi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Minakawa, Noboru</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-10</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Asian tiger mosquito</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Culicidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:sec id="sec001"&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Background&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;The Asian tiger mosquito,&lt;jats:italic&gt;Aedes albopictus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, has spread around the world. The migration was mainly mediated by maritime transportations. This species is known as an efficient vector for arboviruses, and it was responsible for the recent dengue outbreak in Tokyo, Japan. As the vector competence varies among geographical populations, and insecticide resistant populations have emerged, it is important to reveal their movements. The present study uses molecular techniques to search for a sign of introduction of an exotic population in three major international seaports on Kyushu Island.&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;/jats:sec&gt;&lt;jats:sec id="sec002"&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Methodology/principal findings&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Adults of&lt;jats:italic&gt;Ae&lt;/jats:italic&gt;.&lt;jats:italic&gt;albopictus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;were sampled around the international seaports of Fukuoka, Kitakyushu, and Nagasaki. Pairwise fixation indexes were estimated between the sampled populations based on 13 microsatellite markers. There was no clear genetic differentiation between distant and port populations in Kitakyushu and Nagasaki. However, the analysis found one distinct group near the container terminal in Fukuoka, which handles international freight containers mainly from adjacent countries. DNA samples were also obtained from Goto, Tsushima, Honshu, Ryukyu, Thailand, and the Philippines; and a cluster analysis and discriminant analysis revealed that the distinct group in Fukuoka did not belong to these groups. Combined with the results of phylogenetic analysis based on CO1, these results implied that this group originated from one Asian temperate region outside of Japan. Neutrality test and mismatch distribution analysis suggested that the establishment of this group was not recent.&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;/jats:sec&gt;&lt;jats:sec id="sec003"&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Conclusions/significance&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;The present study found a sign of&lt;jats:italic&gt;Ae&lt;/jats:italic&gt;.&lt;jats:italic&gt;albopictus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;introduction from a temperate region of Asia through maritime freight container transportation. The genetically distinct group found in Fukuoka likely originated from a temperate region outside of Japan. Maritime container transportation may introduce to Japan mosquitoes with greater vector competence/insecticide resistance. This is the first study to describe the spatial population structure of&lt;jats:italic&gt;Ae&lt;/jats:italic&gt;.&lt;jats:italic&gt;albopictus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;in Japan using molecular techniques.&lt;/jats:p&gt;&lt;/jats:sec&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>