<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q56774683</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1590/S1516-89132008000300025</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Introduced and cryptogenic species and their management in Paranaguá Bay, Brazil</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Neves, Carolina Somaio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rocha, Rosana Moreira</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2008-06</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Brazil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>FapUNIFESP (SciELO)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The aim of this work was to identify the introduced and cryptogenic species in encrusting and associated communities of hard substrates in Paranaguá Bay, Brazil, and to attempt to determine which of these species could negatively affect the local community to suggest management strategies for these species. At least four introduced species were found - a large number in comparison with other port surveys. These were the hydrozoan Garveia franciscana Torrey, 1902, the polychaete Polydora cornuta Bosc, 1902, the barnacles Amphibalanus reticulatus (Utinoni, 1967) and Striatobalanus amaryllis Darwin, 1854, all with potentially harmful impacts. Of the 33 cryptogenic species, four were also listed in the literature as causing negative effects. We propose the following management practices: periodic cleaning of all underwater structures, population monitoring of invasive species and potential substrates, an information database of potential sources of introduction.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>