<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q92955333</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41559-019-0851-0</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Global ecological impacts of marine exotic species</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Anton, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Geraldi, Nathan R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lovelock, Catherine E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Apostolaki, Eugenia T</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bennett, Scott</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cebrian, Just</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krause-Jensen, Dorte</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marbà, Nuria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martinetto, Paulina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pandolfi, John M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Santana-Garcon, Julia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Duarte, Carlos M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-04-08</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://www.springernature.com/gp/researchers/text-and-data-mining</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Exotic species are a growing global ecological threat; however, their overall effects are insufficiently understood. While some exotic species are implicated in many species extinctions, others can provide benefits to the recipient communities. Here, we performed a meta-analysis to quantify and synthesize the ecological effects of 76 exotic marine species (about 6% of the listed exotics) on ten variables in marine communities. These species caused an overall significant, but modest in magnitude (as indicated by a mean effect size of g &lt; 0.2), decrease in ecological variables. Marine primary producers and predators were the most disruptive trophic groups of the exotic species. Approximately 10% (that is, 2 out of 19) of the exotic species assessed in at least three independent studies had significant impacts on native species. Separating the innocuous from the disruptive exotic species provides a basis for triage efforts to control the marine exotic species that have the most impact, thereby helping to meet Aichi Biodiversity Target 9 of the Convention on Biological Diversity.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>