<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q90775630</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/PLANTS8100421</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Global Actions for Managing Cactus Invasions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Novoa, Ana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brundu, Giuseppe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Day, Michael D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Deltoro, Vicente</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Essl, Franz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Foxcroft, Llewellyn C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fried, Guillaume</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kaplan, Haylee</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kumschick, Sabrina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lloyd, Sandy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marchante, Elizabete</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marchante, Hélia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paterson, Iain D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pyšek, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Richardson, David M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Witt, Arne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmermann, Helmuth G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wilson, John R U</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-10-16</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>public engagement</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The family Cactaceae Juss. contains some of the most widespread and damaging invasive alien plant species in the world, with Australia (39 species), South Africa (35) and Spain (24) being the main hotspots of invasion. The Global Cactus Working Group (IOBC GCWG) was launched in 2015 to improve international collaboration and identify key actions that can be taken to limit the impacts caused by cactus invasions worldwide. Based on the results of an on-line survey, information collated from a review of the scientific and grey literature, expertise of the authors, and because invasiveness appears to vary predictably across the family, we (the IOBC GCWG): (1) recommend that invasive and potentially invasive cacti are regulated, and to assist with this propose five risk categories; (2) recommend that cactus invasions are treated physically or chemically before they become widespread; (3) advocate the use of biological control to manage widespread invasive species; and (4) encourage the development of public awareness and engagement initiatives to integrate all available knowledge and perspectives in the development and implementation of management actions, and address conflicts of interest, especially with the agricultural and ornamental sectors. Implementing these recommendations will require global co-operation. The IOBC GCWG aims to assist with this process though the dissemination of information and experience.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>