<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q56768126</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1614/IPSM-D-09-00015.1</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Perennial Pepperweed (Lepidium latifolium): Properties of Invaded Tidal Marshes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Reynolds, Laura K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boyer, Katharyn E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2010-08</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://www.cambridge.org/core/terms</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Lepidium latifolium</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>salt marsh</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press (CUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:italic&gt;Lepidium latifolium&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (perennial pepperweed) is recognized as a threat to wetland habitats throughout much of the western United States, but its role in tidal marshes has not been explored. Over three seasons in three regions of San Francisco Estuary (Suisun, San Pablo, and South San Francisco bays), we characterized locations in tidal marshes where monotypic stands of &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. latifolium&lt;/jats:italic&gt; are replacing the native &lt;jats:italic&gt;Sarcocornia pacifica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (pickleweed). Soils within &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. latifolium&lt;/jats:italic&gt; stands had significantly lower moisture, salinity, organic matter, and carbon : nitrogen (C : N) and higher pH than in adjacent &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. pacifica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; stands at similar elevation and distance from channels. In addition, &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. latifolium&lt;/jats:italic&gt; canopies were 2 to 3 times taller, thus increasing light reaching soils, and tended to support different insect/spider assemblages (sampled only at the Suisun site). Patterns were generally consistent across the three sites, although less pronounced for some measures at the South Bay site. Overall, these data suggest that &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. latifolium&lt;/jats:italic&gt; invasion of tidal marshes is leading to modification of both structural and functional properties, several of which might further facilitate spread of the invader; however, additional study is needed to determine cause vs. effect for several soil characteristics.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>