<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q57208663</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q57208663</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41528-018-0025-1</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Compliant lightweight non-invasive standalone “Marine Skin” tagging system</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nassar, Joanna M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Khan, Sherjeel M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Velling, Seneca J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diaz-Gaxiola, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shaikh, Sohail F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Geraldi, Nathan R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sevilla, Galo A. Torres</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Duarte, Carlos M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hussain, Muhammad M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-05-03</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractCurrent marine research primarily depends on weighty and invasive sensory equipment and telemetric network to understand the marine environment, including the diverse fauna it contains, as a function of animal behavior and size, as well as equipment longevity. To match animal morphology and activity within the surrounding marine environment, here we show a physically flexible and stretchable skin-like and waterproof autonomous multifunctional system, integrating Bluetooth, memory chip, and high performance physical sensors. The sensory tag is mounted on a swimming crab (Portunus pelagicus) and is capable of continuous logging of depth, temperature, and salinity within the harsh ocean environment. The fully packaged, ultra-lightweight (&lt;2.4g in water), and compliant “Marine Skin” system does not have any wired connection enabling safe and weightless cutting-edge approach to monitor and assess marine life and the ecosystem’s health to support conservation and management of marine ecosystems.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>