<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q64243784</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q64243784</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0212182</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Elucidating fitness components of the invasive dermestid beetle Trogoderma granarium combining deterministic and stochastic demography</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Papanikolaou, Nikos E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kavallieratos, Nickolas G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kavallieratos, Nickolas G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kondakis, Marios</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boukouvala, Maria C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nika, Erifili P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Demiris, Nikos</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-02-14</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Khapra beetle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The invasive dermestid khapra beetle, Trogoderma granarium, is an important pest of stored products that is subject to strict phytosanitary measures. In this study, we conducted a demographic analysis of this species at 30, 35 and 40째C, combining deterministic and stochastic approaches. The net reproductive rate, the intrinsic rate of increase, the finite rate of increase and the doubling time did not differ significantly between 30 and 35째C, while at 40째C we detected negative values of the intrinsic rate of increase and the doubling time. The Briere model fit the data well with respect to the intrinsic rate of increase. Females of roughly 63, 42 and 21 days old reached their maximum reproductive potential at 30, 35 and 40째C, respectively. The stochastic models of this study allowed for checking model fit and the characterization of the most suitable distribution for each component of the process. We expect these results to have bearing on the management of T. granarium since they could be combined with models related to international trade and climatic change, alerting specialists towards early detection strategies against this species.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>