<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q31944929</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/OXFORDJOURNALS.AJE.A009611</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Geocoding and linking data from population-based surveillance and the US Census to evaluate the impact of median household income on the epidemiology of invasive Streptococcus pneumoniae infections</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chen, Frederick</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Breiman, R F</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Farley, M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Plikaytis, B</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Deaver, K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cetron, S</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>1998-12-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Streptococcus pneumoniae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The emergence of drug-resistant Streptococcus pneumoniae poses new clinical challenges and may also reflect a change in the epidemiology of S. pneumoniae infections. A variety of studies have shown that drug-resistant S. pneumoniae infections are linked to antimicrobial use. It has been hypothesized that persons of high socioeconomic status are at increased risk for a drug-resistant infection because of greater access to antimicrobial drugs. To assess whether median household income is associated with increased risk of penicillin-nonsusceptible S. pneumoniae infections, the authors geocoded and linked data from population-based surveillance for invasive pneumococcal disease with data from the 1990 US Census. Among invasive pneumococcal isolates from Atlanta, Georgia, in 1994, increasing proportions of penicillin-nonsusceptible isolates were associated with higher median household incomes (chi2 for trend, 15.17; p=0.002). Despite higher rates of invasive pneumococcal disease among blacks and persons who resided within lower median household income areas, white patients in areas with higher median household income had a higher risk of being infected with strains that were not susceptible to penicillin (Wilcoxon rank sum, Z=2.66, p=0.008). These findings demonstrated the utility of geocoding and US Census data in describing the epidemiology of drug-resistant S. pneumoniae and also provided more evidence that socioeconomic factors may influence the development of drug resistance.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>