<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q38639730</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q38639730</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-017-07520-1</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Identification of a male-produced sex-aggregation pheromone for a highly invasive cerambycid beetle, Aromia bungii</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Xu, Tian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yasui, Hiroe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Teale, Stephen A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fujiwara-Tsujii, Nao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wickham, Jacob D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fukaya, Midori</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kiriyama, Satoshi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hao, Dejun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nakano, Akio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Longwa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Watanabe, Takahito</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tokoro, Masahiko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Millar, Jocelyn G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-08-04</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Aromia bungii</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>longhorn beetle</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractThe longhorned beetle Aromia bungii (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae) is a major pest of stone fruit trees in the genus Prunus, including cherries, apricots, and peaches. Its native range includes China, Korea, Mongolia, and eastern Russia, but it has recently invaded and become established in several countries in Europe, and Japan, and it has been intercepted in shipments coming into North America and Australia. Here, we report the identification of its male-produced aggregation pheromone as the novel compound (E)-2-cis-6,7-epoxynonenal. In field trials in its native range in China, and in recently invaded areas of Japan, the pheromone attracted both sexes of the beetle. Thus, the pheromone should find immediate use in worldwide quarantine surveillance efforts to detect the beetle in incoming shipments. The pheromone will also be a crucial tool in ongoing efforts to eradicate the beetle from regions of the world that it has already invaded.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>