<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q99410754</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0022149X20000759</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Evidence for enemy release in invasive common dace Leuciscus leuciscus in Ireland: a helminth community survey and systematic review</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tierney, P A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Caffrey, J M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Matthews, S M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Costantini, E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Holland, Celia</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-09-14</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://www.cambridge.org/core/terms</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>enemy release hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q85759287</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:enemy release hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q85759287</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Common dace</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press (CUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Invasive species lose parasites in the process of invasion and tend to be less parasitized than conspecifics in the native range and sympatric native species in the invasive range (enemy release). We evaluated enemy release in an invasive freshwater fish in Ireland, common dace&lt;jats:italic&gt;Leuciscus leuciscus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, using helminth parasite community surveys at the core and front of the invasive range of common dace. Furthermore, we undertook a systematic literature review of helminth infection in common dace across its native range in Great Britain and Europe and invasive range in Ireland. The helminth parasite community survey revealed that invasive common dace were infected with fewer helminth species at the invasion front than at the core. Four helminth taxa – Acanthocephala, Monogenea, Digenea and Nematoda – were present in dace at the invasion core compared to only a single helminth species (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Pomphorhynchus tereticollis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;) at the front. The systematic review revealed that invasive common dace in Ireland hosted fewer species of helminths than common dace in the native range. We report a total of three helminth species in common dace in Ireland compared to 24 in Great Britain and 84 in Continental Europe. Our results support the hypotheses that invasive populations are less parasitized than native populations and that more recently established populations host fewer parasites. However, we demonstrate that invasive species may continue to experience release from parasites long after initial invasion.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>