<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q106606439</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.64.57746</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive plant benefits a native plant through plant-soil feedback but remains the superior competitor</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Buerdsell, Sherri L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Milligan, Brook G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lehnhoff, Erik A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-01-28</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic science</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Plant soil feedback (PSF) occurs when a plant modifies soil biotic properties and those changes in turn influence plant growth, survival or reproduction. These feedback effects are not well understood as mechanisms for invasive plant species. &lt;jats:italic&gt;Eragrostis lehmanniana&lt;/jats:italic&gt; is an invasive species that has extensively colonized the southwest US. To address how PSFs may affect &lt;jats:italic&gt;E. lehmanniana&lt;/jats:italic&gt; invasion and native &lt;jats:italic&gt;Bouteloua gracilis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; growth, soil inoculant from four sites of known invasion age at the Appleton-Whittell Audubon Research Ranch in Sonoita, AZ were used in a PSF greenhouse study, incorporating a replacement series design. The purpose of this research was to evaluate PSF conspecific and heterospecific effects and competition outcomes between the invasive &lt;jats:italic&gt;E. lehmanniana&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and a native forage grass, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Bouteloua gracilis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;Eragrostis lehmanniana&lt;/jats:italic&gt;PSFs were beneficial to &lt;jats:italic&gt;B. gracilis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; if developed in previously invaded soil. Plant-soil feedback contributed to competitive suppression of &lt;jats:italic&gt;B. gracilis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; only in the highest ratio of &lt;jats:italic&gt;E. lehmanniana&lt;/jats:italic&gt; to &lt;jats:italic&gt;B. gracilis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. Plant-soil feedback did not provide an advantage to &lt;jats:italic&gt;E. lehmanniana&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in competitive interactions with &lt;jats:italic&gt;B. gracilis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; at low competition levels but were advantageous to &lt;jats:italic&gt;E. lehmanniana&lt;/jats:italic&gt; at the highest competition ratio, indicating a possible density-dependent effect. Despite being beneficial to &lt;jats:italic&gt;B. gracilis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; under many conditions, &lt;jats:italic&gt;E. lehmanniana&lt;/jats:italic&gt; was the superior competitor.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>