<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111375230</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1051/BIOCONF/20213100004</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Distribution, naturalization status, invasion history and plant communities of Impatiens glandulifera Royle (Balsaminaceae) in Siberia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ebel, Alexander</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Adamowski, Wojciech</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mikhailova, Svetlana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Verkhozina, Alla</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zykova, Elena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sheremetova, Svetlana</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-08-13</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Impatiens glandulifera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Balsaminaceae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>EDP Sciences</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;All available data on the distribution of&lt;jats:italic&gt;Impatiens glandulifera&lt;/jats:italic&gt;Royle in Siberia was analyzed. The species appeared in Siberia as an unpretentious ornamental plant around the middle of the 20th century. Cases of withdrawal from culture have been recorded since the 1970s and 1980s; mass naturalization began at the end of the 20th century. Currently, the species is common in many regions of Siberia, but the most active in the Altai Territory, the Altai Republic, Kemerovo, Novosibirsk, Tomsk and Irkutsk Regions. It is common in anthropogenic habitats; it can also often be found in suburban forests, ravines, along the banks of water bodies. It shows tolerance to habitat conditions, but is especially active in areas with a close occurrence of groundwater on humus-rich soils. The species richness of&lt;jats:italic&gt;I. glandulifera&lt;/jats:italic&gt;communities is from 10-15 to 40 species. In total, about 100 species of vascular plants were recorded in&lt;jats:italic&gt;I. glandulifera&lt;/jats:italic&gt;communities in Siberia&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>