<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q112503717</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q112503717</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/INSECTS13030276</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>First Nationwide Monitoring Program for the Detection of Potentially Invasive Mosquito Species in Austria</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bakran-Lebl, Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pree, Stefanie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brenner, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Daroglou, Eleni</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eigner, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Griesbacher, Antonia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gunczy, Johanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hufnagl, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jäger, Stefanie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jerrentrup, Hans</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocker, Lisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paill, Wolfgang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petermann, Jana S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barogh, Bita Shahi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schwerte, Thorsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Suchentrunk, Carina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wieser, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wortha, Licha N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zechmeister, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zezula, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmermann, Klaus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zittra, Carina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Allerberger, Franz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Führer, Hans-Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-03-10</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Austria</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>In Austria, only fragmented information on the occurrence of alien and potentially invasive mosquito species exists. The aim of this study is a nationwide overview on the situation of those mosquitoes in Austria. Using a nationwide uniform protocol for the first time, mosquito eggs were sampled with ovitraps at 45 locations in Austria at weekly intervals from May to October 2020. The sampled eggs were counted and the species were identified by genetic analysis. The Asian tiger mosquito Aedes albopictus was found at two sites, once in Tyrol, where this species has been reported before, and for the first time in the province of Lower Austria, at a motorway rest stop. The Asian bush mosquito Aedes japonicus was widespread in Austria. It was found in all provinces and was the most abundant species in the ovitraps by far. Aedes japonicus was more abundant in the South than in the North and more eggs were found in habitats with artificial surfaces than in (semi-) natural areas. Further, the number of Ae. japonicus eggs increased with higher ambient temperature and decreased with higher wind speed. The results of this study will contribute to a better estimation of the risk of mosquito-borne disease in Austria and will be a useful baseline for a future documentation of changes in the distribution of those species.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>