<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111321672</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/BDJ.10.E78166</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>New records in non-native vascular plants of Russian Lapland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kozhin, Mikhail N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sénnikov, Aleksandr</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-01-06</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Tracheophyta</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The non-native vascular plants of Murmansk Region (European Russia) are under active investigation towards the compilation of the first complete checklist. This work is part of the project 'Flora of Russian Lapland', which ultimately aims at the complete inventory of the taxonomy, distribution and status of vascular plant species in Murmansk Region, based on the comprehensive database of herbarium specimens, field observations and literature.&lt;/jats:p&gt;
          &lt;jats:p&gt;New territory-level records of non-native vascular plants emerged during our inventory of herbarium collections and recent fieldwork. Fourteen species (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Anthemis ruthenica&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Aruncus dioicus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Bromus commutatus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Chaerophyllum hirsutum&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Galega orientalis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Geum aleppicum&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Leonurus quinquelobatus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Lepidium densiflorum&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Levisticum officinale&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Myrrhis odorata&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Phleum phleoides&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Prunus armeniaca&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Rorippa sylvestris&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Senecio vernalis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;) are reported as new to Murmansk Region. The historical occurrences of alien plants appeared in the territory largely as contaminants (of seed or forage). In particular, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Rorippa sylvestris&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Senecio vernalis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; arrived with the forage imported during the Second World War. All recent occurrences originated by escape from confinement (ornamental purposes, horticulture, agriculture), reflecting a high diversity of the modern assortment of cultivated plants in commerce and private gardens. Regarding the invasion status, five alien species are considered casual and eight species are treated as locally established or persisting (for uncertain time). Only one species, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Galega orientalis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, is considered naturalised and capable of further spreading in the territory, although without invasive potential.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>