<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q56379541</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q56379541</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1002/ECS2.1574</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Assessing the impacts of the decline of Tsuga canadensis stands on two amphibian species in a New England forest</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Siddig, Ahmed A. H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ellison, Aaron M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mathewson, Brooks G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-11</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q112148709</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tsuga canadensis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tsuga</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>forest invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractDisturbances such as outbreaks of herbivorous insects and pathogens can devastate unique habitats and directly reduce biodiversity. The foundation tree species Tsuga canadensis (eastern hemlock) is declining due to infestation by the nonnative insect Adelges tsugae (hemlock woolly adelgid). The decline and expected elimination of hemlock from northeastern U.S. forests is changing forest structure, function, and assemblages of associated species. We assessed 10_years of changes in occupancy, detection probability, and relative abundance of two species of terrestrial salamanders, Plethodon cinereus (eastern red‐back salamander) and Notopthalmus viridescens viridescens (eastern red‐spotted newt), to the experimental removal in 2005 of T._canadensis at Harvard Forest. Salamanders were sampled under cover boards and using visual encounter surveys before (2004) and after (2005, 2013, 2014) canopy manipulations in replicate 0.81‐ha plots. In 2004, occupancy of P._cinereus was 35% lower in stands dominated by T._canadensis than that in associated mixed‐hardwood control stands, whereas detection probability and estimated abundance of P._cinereus were, respectively, 60% and 100% greater in T._canadensis stands. Estimated abundance of N._v._viridescens in 2004 was 50% higher in T._canadensis stands. Removal of the T._canadensis canopy increased occupancy of P._cinereus but significantly reduced its estimated detection probability and abundance. Estimated abundance of N._v._viridescens also declined dramatically after canopy manipulations. Our results suggest that ten years after T._canadensis loss due to either the adelgid or pre‐emptive salvage logging, and 50–70_years later when these forests have become mid‐successional mixed deciduous stands, the abundance of these salamanders likely will be &lt;50% of their abundance in current, intact T._canadensis stands. This study adds to our understanding of how forest disturbance, directly and indirectly caused by invasive species, can contribute to declines in the relative abundance of amphibians.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>