<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q35788604</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q35788604</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4583994</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0139234</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Specialist Insect Herbivore and Light Availability Do Not Interact in the Evolution of an Invasive Plant</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Zhijie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pan, Xiaoyun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Ziyan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He, Kate S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Bo</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2015-09-25</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>phenotypic plasticity hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q116193364</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:phenotypic plasticity hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q116193364</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>enemy release hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q85759287</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:enemy release hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q85759287</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q109467185</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>herbivory</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>herbivore</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Release from specialist insect herbivores may allow invasive plants to evolve traits associated with decreased resistance and increased competitive ability. Given that there may be genetic trade-off between resistance and tolerance, invasive plants could also become more tolerant to herbivores. Although it is widely acknowledged that light availability affects tolerance to herbivores, little information is available for whether the effect of light availability on tolerance differ between the introduced and native populations. We conducted a common garden experiment in the introduced range of Alternanthera philoxeroides using ten invasive US and ten native Argentinean populations at two levels of light availability and in the presence or absence of a specialist stem-boring insect Agasicles hygrophila. Plant biomass (total and storage root biomass), two allocation traits (root/shoot ratio and branch intensity, branches biomass/main stem biomass) and two functional traits (specific stem length and specific leaf area), which are potentially associated with herbivore resistance and light capture, were measured. Overall, we found that A. philoxeroides from introduced ranges had comparable biomass and tolerance to specialist herbivores, lower branch intensity, lower specific stem length and specific leaf area. Moreover, introduced populations displayed higher shade tolerance of storage root biomass and lower plastic response to shading in specific stem length. Finally, light availability had no significant effect on evolution of tolerance to specialist herbivores of A. philoxeroides. Our results suggest that post-introduction evolution might have occurred in A. philoxeroides. While light availability did not influence the evolution of tolerance to specialist herbivores, increased shade tolerance and release from specialist insects might have contributed to the successful invasion of A. philoxeroides.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>