<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q107461620</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q107461620</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOTROPICAL.15.E57403</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive plants in the Brazilian Caatinga: a scientometric analysis with prospects for conservation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pinto, Anderson Silva</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Silva Monteiro, Fernanda Kalina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ramos, Maiara Bezerra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Costa Correia Araújo, Rubenice</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Faria Lopes, Sérgio</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-11-27</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Understanding the impacts caused by invasive plant species, especially in regions where studies are scarce, is of great importance to the development of management and conservation strategies. Amongst the biomes present in Brazil, the Caatinga (Dry Tropical Forest) stands out for having had few studies dealing with biological invasions by plants and animals. An evaluation of scientific production can provide a means by which the progress of invasion-related studies can be assessed, as well as identify research gaps and provide a broad overview of the importance of invasions in this biome. Thus, the objective of this study was to perform a scientometric analysis to evaluate the development of scientific research over the years on exotic and invasive plant species in the Caatinga. We found 46 papers dealing with invasive plants in the Caatinga published over a 14-year period. The main objectives of most of the papers focused on identifying the main strategies used by plants in the process of invasion and characterising the invaded environment. A total of 28 species were cited as invasive for the Caatinga, with Prosopis juliflora (Sw.) DC., Cryptostegia madagascariensis Bojer, Calotropis procera (Aiton) W.T.Aiton and Parkinsonia aculeata L. being the most cited species. Although studies on the subject are incipient, there is already important information about the dynamics of the invasiveness of plant species in the Caatinga, which can serve as a basis for new studies, as well as for the development of management policies, based on consistent information.
          Biological invasion, dry forest, exotic species, northeast Brazil, scientometry, semi-arid</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>