<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114027322</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114027322</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/PLANTS11182366</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>A Global Review of the Woody Invasive Alien Species Mimosa pigra (Giant Sensitive Plant): Its Biology and Management Implications</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Welgama, Amali</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Florentine, Singarayer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roberts, Jason</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-09-10</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>phenotypic plasticity hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q116193364</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:phenotypic plasticity hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q116193364</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Mimosa pigra</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Populations of invasive alien plants create disruptive plant communities that are extremely adaptable, imposing severe ecological impacts on agriculture, biodiversity and human activities. To minimise these impacts, prevention and effective weed management strategies are urgently required, including the identification of satellite populations before they invade new areas. This is a critical element that allows weed management practices to become both successful and cost-effective. Mimosa pigra L. (Giant sensitive plant) is an invasive weed that has spread across various environments around the world and is considered one of the world’s top 100 most invasive plant species. Being adaptable to a wide range of soil types, in addition to its woody protective prickles and low palatability, M. pigra has quickly spread and established itself in a range of habitats. Current control methods of this species include biological, chemical and physical methods, together with attempts of integrated application. Reports suggest that integrated management appears to be the most effective means of controlling M. pigra since the use of any single method has not yet proved suitable. In this regard, this review synthesises and explores the available global literature and current research gaps relating to the biology, distribution, impacts and management of M. pigra. The contribution of this work will help guide land managers to design appropriate and sustainable management programs to control M. pigra.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>