<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q22675958</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q22675958</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4525028</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/ZOOKEYS.514.9925</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>An Asiatic Chironomid in Brazil: morphology, DNA barcode and bionomics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Amora, Gizelle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamada, Neusa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fusari, Lívia Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andrade-Souza, Vanderly</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2015-07-27</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Brazil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>bionomics</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>In most freshwater ecosystems, aquatic insects are dominant in terms of diversity; however, there is a disproportionately low number of records of alien species when compared to other freshwater organisms. The Chironomidae is one aquatic insect family that includes some examples of alien species around the world. During a study on aquatic insects in Amazonas state (Brazil), we collected specimens of Chironomidae that are similar, at the morphological level, to Chironomuskiiensis Tokunaga and Chironomusstriatipennis Kieffer, both with distributions restricted to Asia. The objectives of this study were to provide morphological information on this Chironomus population, to investigate its identity using DNA barcoding and, to provide bionomic information about this species. Chironomus DNA barcode data were obtained from GenBank and Barcode of Life Data Systems (BOLD) and, together with our data, were analyzed using the neighbor-joining method with 1000 bootstrap replicates and the genetic distances were estimated using the Kimura-2-parameter. At the morphological level, the Brazilian population cannot be distinguished either from Chironomusstriatipennis or Chironomuskiiensis, configuring a species complex but, at the molecular level our studied population is placed in a clade together with Chironomusstriatipennis, from South Korea. Bionomic characteristics of the Brazilian Chironomus population differ from the ones of Chironomuskiiensis from Japan, the only species in this species complex with bionomic information available. The Brazilian Chironomus population has a smaller size, the double of the number of eggs and inhabits oligotrophic water, in artificial container. In the molecular analysis, populations of Chironomusstriatipennis and Chironomuskiiensis are placed in a clade, formed by two groups: Group A (which includes populations from both named species, from different Asiatic regions and our Brazilian population) and Group B (with populations of Chironomuskiiensis from Japan and South Korea). Genetic distance between the Brazilian population and specimens in Group A suggests that it was recently introduced in Brazil, and that its country of origin is probably South Korea.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>