<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q27323989</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PPAT.1004385</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Age-dependent enterocyte invasion and microcolony formation by Salmonella</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Kaiyi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dupont, Aline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Torow, Natalia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gohde, Frederik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leschner, Sara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lienenklaus, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weiss, Siegfried</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brinkmann, Melanie M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kühnel, Mark</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hensel, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fulde, Marcus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hornef, Mathias W</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2014-09-11</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The coordinated action of a variety of virulence factors allows Salmonella enterica to invade epithelial cells and penetrate the mucosal barrier. The influence of the age-dependent maturation of the mucosal barrier for microbial pathogenesis has not been investigated. Here, we analyzed Salmonella infection of neonate mice after oral administration. In contrast to the situation in adult animals, we observed spontaneous colonization, massive invasion of enteroabsorptive cells, intraepithelial proliferation and the formation of large intraepithelial microcolonies. Mucosal translocation was dependent on enterocyte invasion in neonates in the absence of microfold (M) cells. It further resulted in potent innate immune stimulation in the absence of pronounced neutrophil-dominated pathology. Our results identify factors of age-dependent host susceptibility and provide important insight in the early steps of Salmonella infection in vivo. We also present a new small animal model amenable to genetic manipulation of the host for the analysis of the Salmonella enterocyte interaction in vivo.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>