<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110809451</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110809451</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/INSECTS12050471</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Biological and Host Range Characteristics of (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae), a Candidate Biological Control Agent of Invasive spp. (Onagraceae) in the USA</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Reddy, Angelica M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pratt, Paul D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grewell, Brenda J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Harms, Nathan E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cibils-Stewart, Ximena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walsh, Guillermo Cabrera</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Faltlhauser, Ana</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-05-19</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Coleoptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Onagraceae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Exotic water primroses (Ludwigia spp.) are aggressive invaders in aquatic ecosystems worldwide. To date, management of exotic Ludwigia spp. has been limited to physical and chemical control methods. Biological control provides an alternative approach for the management of invasive Ludwigia spp. but little is known regarding the natural enemies of these exotic plants. Herein the biology and host range of Lysathia flavipes (Boheman), a herbivorous beetle associated with Ludwigia spp. in Argentina and Uruguay, was studied to determine its suitability as a biocontrol agent for multiple closely related target weeds in the USA. The beetle matures from egg to adult in 19.9 ± 1.4 days at 25 °C; females lived 86.3 ± 35.6 days and laid 1510.6 ± 543.4 eggs over their lifespans. No-choice development and oviposition tests were conducted using four Ludwigia species and seven native plant species. Lysathia flavipes showed little discrimination between plant species: larvae aggressively fed and completed development, and the resulting females (F1 generation) oviposited viable eggs on most plant species regardless of origin. These results indicate that L. flavipes is not sufficiently host-specific for further consideration as a biocontrol agent of exotic Ludwigia spp. in the USA and further testing is not warranted.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>