<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q46712337</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/J.MICRON.2015.05.016</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Managing of Procambarus clarkii by X-ray sterilisation of males: Cytological damage to gonads</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Piazza, Federica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aquiloni, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peruzza, Luca</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Manfrin, Chiara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Simi, Sara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marson, Lorena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Edomi, Paolo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Giulianini, Piero G</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2015-05-30</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://www.elsevier.com/tdm/userlicense/1.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Procambarus clarkii</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier BV</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Procambarus clarkii is an invasive alien species spreading worldwide. It is therefore mandatory to find new methods to manage this species since traditional techniques are not sufficient for this purpose. The present study investigates gonad damage induced by different doses of ionising irradiation: 20, 40 and 60 Gy. Testis were analysed after 10 and 30 days by means of light, scanning and transmission electron microscopy. Control unirradiated testes present an acinar structure with a well-defined germinative cells maturation from the distal proliferative zone to the proximal stalk of the lobes whilst, in irradiated testes, induced apoptosis of germinative and accessory cells and a high level of vacuolisation inside the acini were identified, progressively increasing in accordance to Gy dosage and time after exposure. We determined the dose of 40 Gy as the best compromise: it causes an extensive damage to germinative tissues without affecting crayfish vitality, differing from 60 Gy. From an applicative point of view, this dose reduces the efforts, in terms of cost and time, for the application of SMRT.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>