<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q54977092</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q54977092</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41467-018-04096-W</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive alien pests threaten the carbon stored in Europe's forests.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Seidl, Rupert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klonner, Günther</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rammer, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Essl, Franz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moreno, Adam</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Neumann, Mathias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dullinger, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-04-24</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>forest invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractForests mitigate climate change by sequestering large amounts of carbon (C). However, forest C storage is not permanent, and large pulses of tree mortality can thwart climate mitigation efforts. Forest pests are increasingly redistributed around the globe. Yet, the potential future impact of invasive alien pests on the forest C cycle remains uncertain. Here we show that large parts of Europe could be invaded by five detrimental alien pests already under current climate. Climate change increases the potential range of alien pests particularly in Northern and Eastern Europe. We estimate the live C at risk from a potential future invasion as 1027 Tg C (10% of the European total), with a C recovery time of 34 years. We show that the impact of introduced pests could be as severe as the current natural disturbance regime in Europe, calling for increased efforts to halt the introduction and spread of invasive alien species.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>