<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110663898</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110663898</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.62.52934</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>A framework for prioritising present and potentially invasive mammal species for a national list</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bertolino, Sandro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ancillotto, Leonardo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bartolommei, Paola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Benassi, Giulia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Capizzi, Dario</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gasperini, Stefania</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lucchesi, Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mori, Emiliano</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scillitani, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sozio, Giulia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Falaschi, Mattia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ficetola, Gentile Francesco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cerri, Jacopo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Genovesi, Piero</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carnevali, Lucilla</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loy, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Monaco, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-10-15</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive mammal</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The European Union (EU) has recently adopted a regulation on invasive alien species that foresees the possibility of developing lists of species of National Concern. We developed a prioritisation process for alien mammals already established in Italy, but not yet included in the EU list (n = 6 species) and a systematic horizon-scanning procedure to obtain ranked lists for those species that are already introduced worldwide or traded in Italy (n = 213). Experts were asked to score these species, by evaluating their likelihood of establishment and spread and the magnitude of their potential impacts on biodiversity, economy, human-health and society. The manageability of each species was also evaluated, both for the proritisation and the horizon-scanning processes. We produced five lists that ranked species according to their potential spread and impacts and their manageability. These will allow policy-makers to select outputs according to a balance between risk assessment and risk management, establishing priorities for alien species management at the national level.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>