<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q56440912</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q56440912</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.5586/ASBP.2015.028</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Current state, habitat and potential invasiveness of Montia linearis (Douglas ex Hook.) Greene in Poland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dembicz, Iwona</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kozub, ukasz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zaniewski, Piotr T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>habitat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasiveness</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Polish Botanical Society</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Montia linearis&lt;/em&gt; is a vascular plant originating from western North America. The expansion of this species has been observed for several decades. For the first time &lt;em&gt;M. linearis&lt;/em&gt; was found in Europe in 1989. Further six populations were documented by 2004 within the continent: three in Poland, two in Denmark and one in Hungary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apart from discovering a new population of &lt;em&gt;M. linearis&lt;/em&gt;, we confirmed two out of the three previously known localities of the species in Poland. All the currently known populations of &lt;em&gt;M. linearis&lt;/em&gt; occupied predominantly meadow habitats, especially intensively managed sites. Some individuals were also found in disturbed sites with bare soil. The studied species inhabited soils of various types with broad range of fertility as well as humidity. &lt;em&gt;Montia linearis&lt;/em&gt; populations reached densities up to 87 individuals per 0.04 m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;. The number of seeds produced by an individual was between 10 and 55 in 90% of the studied specimens, however much more fertile specimens were also observed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the previously presented hypothesis of &lt;em&gt;M. linearis&lt;/em&gt; dispersal with rail transport seemed not to be well supported, the connection between the &lt;em&gt;M. linearis&lt;/em&gt; presence and cattle husbandry is considered. It is possible that the species can be transferred with living animals or manure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The species was able to survive for at least 26 years within once inhabited site. Further spread of &lt;em&gt;M. linearis&lt;/em&gt; within Europe is highly probable. The aim of the study is to: (i) describe the current state of populations of &lt;em&gt;M. linearis&lt;/em&gt; in Poland, (ii) provide information on habitat preferences and biology of the species, (iii) assess the invasiveness potential of &lt;em&gt;M. linearis&lt;/em&gt; in Poland.&lt;/p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>