<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q100504527</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/AOBPLA/PLAA045</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>A native annual forb locally excludes a closely related introduced species that co-occurs in oak-savanna habitat remnants</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Johnson, Jens C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Williams, Jennifer L</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-08-25</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Despite the ubiquity of introduced species, their long-term impacts on native plant abundance and diversity remain poorly understood. Coexistence theory offers a tool for advancing this understanding by providing a framework to link short-term individual measurements with long-term population dynamics by directly quantifying the niche and average fitness differences between species. We observed that a pair of closely related and functionally similar annual plants with different origins-native &lt;i&gt;Plectritis congesta&lt;/i&gt; and introduced &lt;i&gt;Valerianella locusta&lt;/i&gt;-co-occur at the community scale but rarely at the local scale of direct interaction. To test whether niche and/or fitness differences preclude local-scale long-term coexistence, we parameterized models of competitor dynamics with results from a controlled outdoor pot experiment, where we manipulated densities of each species. To evaluate the hypothesis that niche and fitness differences exhibit environmental dependency, leading to community-scale coexistence despite local competitive exclusion, we replicated this experiment with a water availability treatment to determine if this key limiting resource alters the long-term prediction. Water availability impacted population vital rates and intensities of intraspecific versus interspecific competition between &lt;i&gt;P. congesta&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;V. locusta&lt;/i&gt;. Despite environmental influence on competition our model predicts that native &lt;i&gt;P. congesta&lt;/i&gt; competitively excludes introduced &lt;i&gt;V. locusta&lt;/i&gt; in direct competition across water availability conditions because of an absence of stabilizing niche differences combined with a difference in average fitness, although this advantage weakens in drier conditions. Further, field data demonstrated that &lt;i&gt;P. congesta&lt;/i&gt; densities have a negative effect on &lt;i&gt;V. locusta&lt;/i&gt; seed prediction. We conclude that native &lt;i&gt;P. congesta&lt;/i&gt; limits abundances of introduced &lt;i&gt;V. locusta&lt;/i&gt; at the direct-interaction scale, and we posit that &lt;i&gt;V. locusta&lt;/i&gt; may rely on spatially dependent coexistence mechanisms to maintain coexistence at the site scale. In quantifying this competitive outcome our study demonstrates mechanistically how a native species may limit the abundance of an introduced invader.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>