<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114730840</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114730840</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/JMSE9111205</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Protecting Biodiversity from Invasive Alien Species by Improving Policy Instruments in Greece: The INVALIS Project Action Plan</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Roussos, Orfeas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kapetanopoulou, Christina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petza, Dimitra</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-11-01</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>biodiversity</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The Protecting European Biodiversity from Invasive Alien Species (INVALIS) project objective is to improve policies for protecting biodiversity from invasive alien species (IAS), by bringing together seven partners from seven countries and supporting policy measures for prevention, early detection, and control of IAS in their respective territories. The project is funded by the Interreg Europe program. The learning process of the INVALIS project consisted of various experience-exchanging activities among the project partners (interregional workshops, site visits, etc.), as well as among stakeholders at a regional level. This exchange of experiences led to the drafting of regional Action Plans by each partner. The INVALIS Action Plan of Greece is based on an analysis of the current situation of IAS management in Greece, and the transfer of good practices and conclusions derived from the exchange of experiences. Gaps in IAS management were identified mainly in the areas of raising public awareness of IAS and networking among IAS stakeholders. As a result, three actions were proposed to address these deficits: initiating a project on education and raising awareness about IAS, creating a web portal on these species, and establishing an IAS management working group. These actions will contribute towards improving specific policy instruments in Greece.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>