<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q37550196</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q37550196</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5206634</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/SREP39745</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Population genetics of the Manila clam (Ruditapes philippinarum) introduced in North America and Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Cordero, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Delgado, Marina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, Baozhong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ruesink, Jennifer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saavedra, Carlos</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Ruditapes philippinarum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>population genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractGlobally, the Manila clam (Ruditapes philippinarum) stands as the second most important bivalve species in fisheries and aquaculture. Native to the Pacific coast of Asia, it is now well-established in North America and Europe, where its on-going management reflects local economic interests. The historic record of transfers spans the 20th century and suggests sequential movement from Japan to North America, as a hitch-hiker on oysters, and then intentional introduction in Europe, but global genetic data are missing. We have studied mitochondrial DNA and microsatellite markers in nine populations from Asia, North America and Europe. The results from the two types of markers indicated a good concordance of present-day genetic structure with the reported history of clam transfers across continents, and no evidence of relevant concealed introductions from continental Asia in Europe and North America. However, European populations showed a loss of genetic variability and significant genetic differentiation as compared to their American counterparts. Our study shows that in spite of the increasing ease for species to spread out of their native range, in the case of the Manila clam this has not resulted in new invasion waves in the two studied continents.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>