<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117804680</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117804680</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.79.94283</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>_Spreading of the cup plant (Silphium perfoliatum) in northern Bavaria (Germany) from bioenergy crops</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ende, L. Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lauerer, Marianne</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-12-23</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Silphium perfoliatum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive species can be the cause of severe problems for biodiversity, economy and human health. The cup plant (Silphium perfoliatum) is native to eastern North America and is increasingly cultivated in Germany as a new bioenergy crop. Its growth characteristics and autecology do not exclude a possible invasive potential. However, there are hardly any studies on this to date. In this study, habitat requirements for spontaneous colonization and establishment of the cup plant were investigated. Therefore, a 15 m radius around eleven cup plant fields in northern Bavaria (Germany) was examined. Data on cup plant colonization, habitat type, vegetation structure, ground cover, and further site conditions using the Ellenberg indicator values were collected and analyzed by logistic regression models. Spontaneously colonized cup plants were found in a wide range of habitats. Open habitats and human settlement areas were particularly suitable, especially field margins and agricultural paths. A portion of open soil of about 25% was preferentially colonized. Cup plants occurred predominantly within the first few meters of the field margin and increasingly around cup plant fields that have existed for a longer period. Favorable for the development of stems and thus for flowering, fruiting and establishing are warmer sites with a high herb layer. Individual plants that had developed a stem persist for several years and increased their stem number over time. The number of stem-developing individuals also increased over time. Thus, there exist an enormous potential for spread in the future. However, an invasive potential could not be confirmed based on the present study, because a threat of biodiversity was not proven.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>