<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q112503585</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q112503585</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/INSECTS13020217</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Genetic Differences among Established Populations of Aromia bungii (Faldermann, 1835) (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae) in Japan: Suggestion of Multiple Introductions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tamura, Shigeaki</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shoda-Kagaya, Etsuko</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-02-22</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>beetles</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>longhorn beetle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Aromia bungii</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>multiple introductions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>established population</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Aromia bungii (Faldermann) (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae) is an invasive pest, damaging Rosaceae trees (particularly Prunus) in Japan and Europe. The establishment of this beetle in Japan was first detected in 2012, and subsequently, it has rapidly expanded its distribution. Currently, Japanese populations of A. bungii are widely distributed in six non-contiguous regions. In this study, we compared the nucleotide sequences of mitochondrial cytochrome oxidase subunit 1 of the populations in these six regions in Japan to examine whether multiple introductions or human-mediated long-distance dispersal have contributed to the non-contiguous distribution of A. bungii. Seven haplotypes were detected from Japanese populations, and one of these was identical to a sequence deposited from China. One to two haplotypes were detected in each region, suggesting a genetic bottleneck. Detected haplotypes differed between introduced regions, although two regions shared a single haplotype. These results suggest that multiple independent introductions of A. bungii have contributed to its non-contiguous distribution in Japan. Quarantine measures for wood-packing materials in trade need to be strengthened to prevent the establishment of further populations of A. bungii.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>