<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111160283</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111160283</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S10530-020-02436-W</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Negative impacts of invasive predators used as biological control agents against the pest snail Lissachatina fulica: the snail Euglandina ‘rosea’ and the flatworm Platydemus manokwari</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gerlach, Justin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barker, Gary M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bick, Cindy S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bouchet, Philippe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brodie, Gilianne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Christensen, Carl C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Collins, Timothy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Coote, Trevor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cowie, Robert H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fiedler, G. Curt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Griffiths, Owen L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Florens, F. B. Vincent</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hayes, Kenneth A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Jaynee</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meyer, Jean-Yves</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meyer, Wallace M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Richling, Ira</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Slapcinsky, John D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winsor, Leigh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yeung, Norine W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-12-19</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q112148709</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Lissachatina fulica</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Platydemus manokwari</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractSince 1955 snails of theEuglandina roseaspecies complex andPlatydemus manokwariflatworms were widely introduced in attempted biological control of giant African snails (Lissachatina fulica) but have been implicated in the mass extinction of Pacific island snails. We review the histories of the 60 introductions and their impacts onL. fulicaand native snails. Since 1993 there have been unofficial releases ofEuglandinawithin island groups. Only three officialP. manokwarireleases took place, but new populations are being recorded at an increasing rate, probably because of accidental introduction. Claims that these predators controlledL. fulicacannot be substantiated; in some cases pest snail declines coincided with predator arrival but concomitant declines occurred elsewhere in the absence of the predator and the declines in some cases were only temporary. In the Hawaiian Islands, although there had been some earlier declines of native snails, theEuglandinaimpacts on native snails are clear with rapid decline of many endemic Hawaiian Achatinellinae following predator arrival. In the Society Islands, Partulidae tree snail populations remained stable untilEuglandinaintroduction, when declines were extremely rapid with an exact correspondence between predator arrival and tree snail decline.Platydemus manokwariinvasion coincides with native snail declines on some islands, notably the Ogasawara Islands of Japan, and its invasion of Florida has led to mass mortality ofLiguusspp. tree snails. We conclude thatEuglandinaandP. manokwariare not effective biocontrol agents, but do have major negative effects on native snail faunas. These predatory snails and flatworms are generalist predators and as such are not suitable for biological control.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>