<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110663922</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.61.53256</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Eat and be eaten: trophic interactions of the introduced frog Scinax quinquefasciatus in anthropogenic environments in Galápagos</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moretta-Urdiales, M. Mar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ernst, Raffael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pontón-Cevallos, José</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bermúdez, Rafael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jäger, Heinke</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-10-08</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>trophic interaction</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;While the Galápagos Archipelago is known for its endemic flora and fauna, many introduced species have also become naturalised there, especially on the human-inhabited islands. The only amphibian species known to have established on the islands, the Fowler’s snouted treefrog (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Scinax quinquefasciatus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;), is thought to have arrived about two decades ago. Since then, this treefrog has substantially extended its range to the islands of Santa Cruz and Isabela. Our study explores the potential influence of this introduced amphibian on native trophic systems on Santa Cruz and identifies potential antagonists likely to control larval frog populations. To understand the impact of &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. quinquefasciatus&lt;/jats:italic&gt; as a predator of local invertebrate fauna, we performed a stomach-content analysis of 228 preserved adult specimens from seven different localities on Santa Cruz. Of the 11 macroinvertebrate orders recorded, Lepidoptera constituted more than 60% of the contents. We also identified active predators of &lt;jats:italic&gt;S. quinquefasciatus&lt;/jats:italic&gt; tadpoles: larvae of the endemic diving beetle (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Thermonectus basillarus galapagoensis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;). To determine the efficiency of this predator, we conducted predator-prey experiments in ex situ conditions. Tadpole predation was highest after first exposure to the predator and significantly decreased over time. Our experimental results demonstrate that although &lt;jats:italic&gt;T. b. galapagoensis&lt;/jats:italic&gt; larvae are effective tadpole predators, their feeding saturation rates are likely inadequate for frog population control. Our findings provide the first baseline data necessary to make informed ecological impact assessments and monitoring schemes on Santa Cruz for this introduced treefrog.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>