<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q58158298</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1139/FACETS-2017-0041</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Enemy escape: A general phenomenon in a fragmented literature?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mlynarek, Julia J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moffat, Chandra E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Edwards, Sara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Einfeldt, Anthony L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heustis, Allyson</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Johns, Rob</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>MacDonnell, Mallory</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pureswaran, Deepa S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Quiring, Dan T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shibel, Zoryana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heard, Stephen B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-09</dc:date>
  <dc:subject>enemy release hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q85759287</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:enemy release hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q85759287</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Canadian Science Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Many populations are thought to be regulated, in part, by their natural enemies. If so, disruption of this regulation should allow rapid population growth. Such “enemy escape” may occur in a variety of circumstances, including invasion, natural range expansion, range edges, suppression of enemy populations, host shifting, phenological changes, and defensive innovation. Periods of relaxed enemy pressure also occur in, and may drive, population oscillations and outbreaks. We draw attention to similarities among circumstances of enemy escape and build a general conceptual framework for the phenomenon. Although these circumstances share common mechanisms and depend on common assumptions, enemy escape can involve dynamics operating on very different temporal and spatial scales. In particular, the duration of enemy escape is rarely considered but will likely vary among circumstances. Enemy escape can have important evolutionary consequences including increasing competitive ability, spurring diversification, or triggering enemy counteradaptation. These evolutionary consequences have been considered for plant–herbivore interactions and invasions but largely neglected for other circumstances of enemy escape. We aim to unite the fragmented literature, which we argue has impeded progress in building a broader understanding of the eco-evolutionary dynamics of enemy escape.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>