<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111170624</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/JIPM/PMAA024</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasion Biology and Management of Sweetpotato Whitefly (Hemiptera: Aleyrodidae) in China</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Guo, Chen-liang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhu, Yong-zhe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Youjun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keller, Michael A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, Tong-Xian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chu, Dong</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-11-17</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hemiptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Aleyrodidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;The sweetpotato whitefly, Bemisia tabaci Gennadius (Hemiptera: Aleyrodidae), is a broadly invasive pest of great economic significance to agricultural and horticultural systems in the world. Bemisia tabaci contains more than 44 cryptic species, among which B. tabaci Middle East Asia Minor 1 (MEAM1) and Mediterranean (MED) are the most invasive and destructive, and have spread to many countries. Research on B. tabaci cryptic species increased dramatically in China following the introduction of MEAM1 in the middle-late 1990s. Our report discussed significant advances over the past two decades to understand the invasive genetics of B. tabaci in China. We reviewed the main findings including changes in the cryptic species composition and invasion characteristics of B. tabaci, also summarizing the factors that affect the displacement of dominant cryptic species. Finally, the integrated management of B. tabaci in China was discussed. We hope that this review can stimulate interest in and deepen understanding of B. tabaci, which will lay a foundation for further research in this field.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>