<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110745069</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.7717/PEERJ.11185</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Identification problems of travelling snail species-new exotic introductions to tropical greenhouses in Gothenburg, Sweden (Gastropoda: Achatinellidae, Strobilopsidae, Helicarionidae)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Richling, Ira</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Proschwitz, Ted</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Achatinellidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Helicarionidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Strobilopsidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>PeerJ</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Three previously unreported species of tropical land snails were found in the greenhouses of the Gothenburg (Göteborg) Botanical Garden and the Public Science Center Universeum in Gothenburg. For &lt;jats:italic&gt;Tornatellides&lt;/jats:italic&gt; cf. &lt;jats:italic&gt;boeningi&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Schmacker &amp; Boettger, 1891) and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Ovachlamys fulgens&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Gude, 1900&lt;/jats:italic&gt;) this is the first observed occurrence in a European greenhouse, while &lt;jats:italic&gt;Discostrobilops hubbardi&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Brown, 1861&lt;/jats:italic&gt;) was first reported very recently in the Vienna Botanical garden. &lt;jats:italic&gt;Tornatellides&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Discostrobilops&lt;/jats:italic&gt; seem to be spread with orchid culture and trade. Identification of the &lt;jats:italic&gt;Tornatellides&lt;/jats:italic&gt; species proved extremely difficult and a genetic sequence-based approach completely failed due to the unavailability of reference data. This was unexpected considering the importance of these introduced species in horticultural trade. A broader assessment of available sequence data for genetic identification based on COI or 16S for other snail species reported from horticultural facilities showed that such reference data in GenBank are still scarce and only for a limited number of species this approach would support identification.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>