<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q35077189</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/J.MARENVRES.2013.12.007</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasion success and development of benthic assemblages: effect of timing, duration of submersion and substrate type</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vaz-Pinto, F</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prestes, Afonso</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alvaro, N V</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Neto, Ana Isabel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martins, G M</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2013-12-17</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>timing of biotic invasions</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier BV</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Several studies have suggested that communities associated with artificial substrata support more non-indigenous species (NIS) than natural habitats, and may function as corridors for their expansion. Our study focused on the role of substrate type, timing and duration of submersion as determinants of fouling assemblage. We used plates made of basalt, concrete or fibreglass, to assess early, i.e., 3 months, and late, i.e., 12 months, succession in benthic communities. To assess spatial and temporal variability of the results, sampling was performed at 2 locations and the experiment was repeated in two seasons of the year. Our results showed that the timing and duration of submersion affected the number and percent cover of natives and NIS, as well as assemblage composition. Moreover, the present study showed no support for the hypothesis that marine NIS are more abundant on artificial substrata, as neither of the two artificial substrata tested supported a greater number of NIS compared to basalt (the natural substratum). Overall, fibreglass presented the most different benthic assemblage composition, supporting the fact that the extent and nature of the observed differences varied not only between natural and artificial substrata, but also according to the type of artificial habitat considered. Thus, our results are in agreement with previous studies that stated that appropriate strategies for environmental management should integrate ecological assessment in order to maintain natural patterns of distribution and abundance of organisms, scales of variability and relevant ecological processes.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>