<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q34129662</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1603/EN11063</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>No evidence for enemy release during range expansion of an evergreen tree in northern Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Skou, Anne-Marie T</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Markussen, Bo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sigsgaard, Lene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kollmann, Johannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2011-10-01</dc:date>
  <dc:subject>enemy release hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q85759287</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:enemy release hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q85759287</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>range expansion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Plant distributions are dynamic but the role of plant-insect interactions in controlling range dynamics is not well understood. Enemy release, for example could facilitate plant range expansion under climate change. We conducted a transplant experiment with the evergreen tree Ilex aquifolium L. in both the historical and the expanding range in Denmark to study possible effects of geographical position, small-scale distance, and plant types on presence and performance of the monophagous insect leaf-miner Phytomyza ilicis Curtis. The leaf miner was present in the entire range of I. aquifolium in Denmark, and there were no differences in emergence success depending on geographical position. Small-scale distance to existing adult plants influenced the activity of the insect on the transplants, and oviposition density was negatively correlated with distance to adult plants. Plant type had an effect on leaf miner feeding, oviposition and mining, and the native provenance of I. aquifolium supported higher densities than two cultivars. There was no evidence that enemy release facilitates the current range expansion of I. aquifolium.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>