<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q113201751</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113201751</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/BDJ.10.E81941</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The current status of invasive alien insect species in South Korea</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Dayeong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Min-Ji</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Heejo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ban, Young-Gyu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Dong Eon</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-07-13</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>disturbance hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q115794757</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:disturbance hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q115794757</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>South Korea</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>We investigated the identity and distribution of the invasive alien insect species inhabiting Korean ecosystems, targeting 3,249 locations in nine regions between 2015 and 2018. In natural ecosystems, we identified 63 species in 43 families and nine orders of invasive alien insect species, respectively. We observed that the order Hemiptera exhibited the highest species diversity with 20 species. Gyeonggi-do was where the highest number of invasive alien insect species were identified (45 species). Species richness analysis revealed that Jeju-do showed the highest Dominance Index (0.8), whereas Gyeongsangnam-do had the highest Diversity Index (2.8). Corythucha marmorata (Hemiptera: Tingidae), Lycorma delicatula (Hemiptera: Fulgoridae), Ophraella communa (Coleoptera: Chrysomeridae), Metcalfa pruinosa (Say) (Hemiptera: Flatidae) and Pochazia shantungensis (Hemiptera: Ricaniidae) were distributed in more than 300 locations of the country. Invasive alien insect species inhabited the roadsides (31.3%), farmlands (18.3%) and parks (16.6%). In this study, we list the invasive alien insect species in Korean ecosystems and provide a basis for selecting primary management target species.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>