<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111320292</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111320292</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/TOXICS10020043</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Co-Exposure with an Invasive Seaweed Exudate Increases Toxicity of Polyamide Microplastics in the Marine Mussel &lt;i&gt;Mytilus galloprovincialis&lt;/i&gt;</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rodrigues, Filipa G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vieira, Hugo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Campos, Diana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pires, Sílvia F S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rodrigues, Andreia C. M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Silva, Ana L Patrício</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Soares, Amadeu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oliveira, Jacinta M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bordalo, Maria D</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-01-18</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>exudate</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Mytilus galloprovincialis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive seaweed</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>co-exposure</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Plastic pollution and invasive species are recognised as pervasive threats to marine biodiversity. However, despite the extensive on-going research on microplastics’ effects in the biota, knowledge on their combination with additional stressors is still limited. This study investigates the effects of polyamide microplastics (PA-MPs, 1 mg/L), alone and in combination with the toxic exudate from the invasive red seaweed Asparagopsis armata (2%), after a 96 h exposure, in the mussel Mytilus galloprovincialis. Biochemical responses associated with oxidative stress and damage, neurotoxicity, and energy metabolism were evaluated in different tissues (gills, digestive gland, and muscle). Byssus production and PA-MP accumulation were also assessed. Results demonstrated that PA-MPs accumulated the most in the digestive gland of mussels under PA-MP and exudate co-exposure. Furthermore, the combination of stressors also resulted in oxidative damage at the protein level in the gills as well as in a significant reduction in byssus production. Metabolic capacity increased in both PA-MP treatments, consequently affecting the energy balance in mussels under combined stress. Overall, results show a potential increase of PA-MPs toxicity in the presence of A. armata exudate, highlighting the importance of assessing the impact of microplastics in realistic scenarios, specifically in combination with co-occurring stressors, such as invasive species.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>