<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114921492</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114921492</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.2298/PIF1904183R</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Allelopathic effects of invasive weed species Abutilon theophrasti Medik., Ambrosia artemisiifolia L., Datura stramonium L. and Xanthium strumarium L. on tomato</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Radivojevic, Ljiljana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saric-Krsmanovic, Marija</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gajic-Umiljendic, Jelena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Santric, Ljiljana</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-07-02</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>allelopathy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Ambrosia artemisiifolia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Datura stramonium</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Abutilon theophrasti</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Xanthium strumarium</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive weed</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>National Library of Serbia</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abutilon theophrasti Medik, Ambrosia artemisiifolia L., Datura stramonium L.
   and Xanthium strumarium L. are four well-known invasive weed species that
   are widespread in many crops. Laboratory experiments were conducted to
   evaluate the allelopathic effects of decomposition products of these four
   invasive weeds on seed germination and early seedling growth of tomato. The
   results of the study showed that decomposition products obtained from A.
   theophrasti, A. artemisiifolia, D. stramonium and X. strumarium had
   different allelopathic impacts on germination and seedling growth of tomato.
   The degree of inhibition or stimulation depended on weed species and type of
   decomposition product. Root decomposition products of all species except X.
   strumarium decreased the early growth of tomato (2-37%). X. strumarium had
   only stimulating effect on early growth of tomato (1-86%). Also, the results
   showed that leaves of the other three invasive weed species had stimulating
   effects on early growth of tomato (1-53%). Hence, the allelopathic potential
   of X. strumarium, as well as the leaf decomposition products of the other
   three invasive weed species could be used to develop an appropriate
   technology to improve tomato production.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>