<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q106606436</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q106606436</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.64.55597</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Distribution of alien tetrapods in the Iberian Peninsula</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ascensão, Fernando</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>D'Amico, Marcello</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martins, Ricardo C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rebelo, Rui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barbosa, A. Márcia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bencatel, Joana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barrientos, Rafael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Abellán, Pedro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tella, José L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cardador, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Anadón, José D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carrete, Martina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Murgui, Enrique</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fernandes, Pedro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Santos, Sara M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mira, António</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luz Mathias, Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tiago, Patrícia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Casabella, Eduardo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reino, Luís</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paulo, Octávio S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pereira, Henrique M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Capinha, César</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-01-11</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic science</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>We present a dataset that assembles occurrence records of alien tetrapods (amphibians, reptiles, birds and mammals) in the Iberian Peninsula, a coherent biogeographically unit where introductions of alien species have occurred for millennia. These data have important potential applications for ecological research and management, including the assessment of invasion risks, formulation of preventive and management plans, and research at the biological community level on alien species. This dataset summarizes inventories and data sources on the taxonomy and distribution of alien tetrapods in the Iberia Peninsula, comprising known locations from published literature, expert knowledge and citizen science platforms. An expert-based assessment process allowed the identification of unreliable records (misclassification or natural dispersion from native range), and the classification of species according to their status of reproduction in the wild. Distributional data was harmonized into a common area unit, the 10 × 10 km Universal Transverse Mercator (UTM) system (n = 6,152 cells). The year of observation and/or year of publication were also assigned to the records. In total, we assembled 35,940 unique distribution records (UTM × species × Year) for 253 species (6 amphibians, 16 reptiles, 218 birds and 13 mammals), spanning between 1912 and 2020. The species with highest number of distribution records were the Mediterranean painted frog Discoglossus pictus (n = 59 UTM), the pond slider Trachemys scripta (n = 471), the common waxbill Estrilda astrild (n = 1,275) and the house mouse Mus musculus (n = 4,043), for amphibians, reptiles, birds and mammals, respectively. Most alien species recorded are native to Africa (33%), followed by South America (21%), Asia (19%), North America (12%) and Oceania (10%). Thirty-six species are classified by IUCN as threatened in their native range, namely 2 Critically Endangered (CR), 6 Endangered (EN), 8 Vulnerable (VU), and 20 species Near Threatened (NT). Species maps are provided in DataSet1, as well R code and GIS layers to update them as new records are obtained.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>