<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111166408</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1051/KMAE/2020032</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Occurrence of two exotic decapods,Macrobrachium nipponense(de Haan, 1849) andProcambarus virginalisLyko, 2017, in Ukrainian waters</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Son, Mikhail</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morhun, Halyna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>O. Novitskyi, Roman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sidorovskyi, Serhii</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kulyk, Maryna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Utevsky, Serge Y.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-10-26</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Macrobrachium nipponense</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>EDP Sciences</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;New information on the occurrence of two alien decapod crustaceans,&lt;jats:italic&gt;Macrobrachium nipponense&lt;/jats:italic&gt;and&lt;jats:italic&gt;Procambarus virginalis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, was summarized for Ukraine. The invasive potential of both species was estimated in the context of local environmental and socio-economic issues. Their history as non-native species is marked by the early use of alien decapods as a natural resource by local residents. Both intentional and unintentional introductions occurred for&lt;jats:italic&gt;M. nipponense&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, while the ornamental trade was an important source of non-native&lt;jats:italic&gt;P. virginalis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. New records of&lt;jats:italic&gt;M. nipponense&lt;/jats:italic&gt;and&lt;jats:italic&gt;P. virginalis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;from open freshwater habitats in the Odesa and Kharkiv provinces suggest continuing expansion of these decapods. We conducted a molecular phylogenetic analysis of&lt;jats:italic&gt;COI&lt;/jats:italic&gt;sequences, which confirmed morphological identifications of invasive&lt;jats:italic&gt;M. nipponense&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. This reinforces the presumed pathway of this species, including its pathway from China to south-western Ukraine.&lt;jats:italic&gt;Procambarus fallax&lt;/jats:italic&gt;was found to be paraphyletic in relation to&lt;jats:italic&gt;P. virginalis&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, which was probably caused by analyzing only one mitochondrial gene, which could be impacted by the recent emergence of the latter species.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>