<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111158980</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3389/FENVS.2021.735509</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Low Benthic Oxygen and High Internal Phosphorus-Loading are Strongly Associated With the Invasive Macrophyte Nitellopsis obtusa (starry stonewort) in a Large, Polymictic Lake</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Harrow-Lyle, Tyler J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kirkwood, Andrea E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-08-19</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Nitellopsis obtusa</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive macrophyte</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Frontiers Media SA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Lake Scugog is an important headwater to the Trent Severn-Waterway in Ontario, Canada. In recent years, notable ecosystem-level changes have occurred coinciding with the emergence of the non-native invasive charophyte &lt;jats:italic&gt;Nitellopsis obtusa&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. Despite &lt;jats:italic&gt;N. obtusa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; arriving in North America in the early 1970s, studies documenting the impact of &lt;jats:italic&gt;N. obtusa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; on invaded ecosystems are scarce. Given the increasing dominance of &lt;jats:italic&gt;N. obtusa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in inland waters of the Great Lakes basin, we investigated the ecosystem-level impacts of &lt;jats:italic&gt;N. obtusa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in Lake Scugog over a 3-year period. We show for the first time a strong association between &lt;jats:italic&gt;N. obtusa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; occurrence and biomass with benthic anoxia in this shallow, polymictic lake. Benthic dissolved oxygen concentrations were significantly lower (&lt;jats:italic&gt;p&lt;/jats:italic&gt;-value &amp;lt; 0.001) at sites with &lt;jats:italic&gt;N. obtusa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; compared to sites without &lt;jats:italic&gt;N. obtusa&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. Additionally, &lt;jats:italic&gt;N. obtusa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; biomass was a negative predictor of near-bed oxygen concentration (&lt;jats:italic&gt;R&lt;/jats:italic&gt;&lt;jats:sup&gt;2&lt;/jats:sup&gt; = 0.59, &lt;jats:italic&gt;p&lt;/jats:italic&gt;-value &amp;lt; 0.001). Knowing that anoxia can promote the internal loading of phosphorus, we measured soluble reactive phosphorus (SRP) in the pore-water of sediments at each site, and found &lt;jats:italic&gt;N. obtusa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; biomass explained 90% of sediment pore-water SRP (&lt;jats:italic&gt;R&lt;/jats:italic&gt;&lt;jats:sup&gt;2&lt;/jats:sup&gt; = 0.90, &lt;jats:italic&gt;p&lt;/jats:italic&gt;-value &amp;lt; 0.001). These notable associations between &lt;jats:italic&gt;N. obtusa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and key lake elements indicates that &lt;jats:italic&gt;N. obtusa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; may be acting as an ecosystem engineer in invaded lakes by altering the biogeochemical fate of oxygen and phosphorus.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>