<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q92618758</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S00134-019-05599-W</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>ESICM/ESCMID task force on practical management of invasive candidiasis in critically ill patients</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Martin-Loeches, Ignacio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Antonelli, Massimo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cuenca-Estrella, Manuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dimopoulos, George</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Einav, Sharon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De Waele, Jan J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Garnacho-Montero, Jose</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kanj, Souha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Machado, Flavia R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Montravers, Philippe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sakr, Yasser</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sanguinetti, Maurizio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Timsit, Jean-Francois</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bassetti, Matteo</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-03-25</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://www.springer.com/tdm</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>candidiasis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive candidiasis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>INTRODUCTION:The term invasive candidiasis (IC) refers to both bloodstream and deep-seated invasive infections, such as peritonitis, caused by Candida species. Several guidelines on the management of candidemia and invasive infection due to Candida species have recently been published, but none of them focuses specifically on critically ill patients admitted to intensive care units (ICUs). MATERIAL AND METHODS:In the absence of available scientific evidence, the resulting recommendations are based solely on epidemiological and clinical evidence in conjunction with expert opinion. The task force used the GRADE (Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development, and Evaluation) approach to evaluate the recommendations and assign levels of evidence. The recommendations and their strength were decided by consensus and, if necessary, by vote (modified Delphi process). Descriptive statistics were used to analyze the results of the Delphi process. Statements obtaining &gt; 80% agreement were considered to have achieved consensus. CONCLUSIONS:The heterogeneity of this patient population necessitated the creation of a mixed working group comprising experts in clinical microbiology, infectious diseases and intensive care medicine, all chosen on the basis of their expertise in the management of IC and/or research methodology. The working group's main goal was to provide clinicians with clear and practical recommendations to optimize microbiological diagnosis and treatment of IC. The Systemic Inflammation and Sepsis and Infection sections of the European Society of Intensive Care Medicine (ESICM) and the Critically Ill Patients Study Group of the European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases (ESCMID) therefore decided to develop a set of recommendations for application in non-immunocompromised critically ill patients.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>