<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q34479482</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1603/EC12096</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Impact of insecticides on the invasive Halyomorpha halys (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae): analysis of insecticide lethality</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leskey, Tracy C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Doo-Hyung</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Short, Brent D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wright, Starker E</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012-10-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>insecticide</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>brown marmorated stink bug</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hemiptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pentatomidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The efficacy of 37 insecticide treatments against adult Halyomorpha halys (Stål) was established based on exposure to 18-h old dry insecticide residue in laboratory bioassays. Individual adult H. halys were exposed to an insecticide residue for 4.5 h and then monitored daily for survivorship over a 7-d period. The proportion of dead and moribund insects was used as an estimate of overall insecticide efficacy against H. halys immediately after the exposure period and over the 7-d trial. Among all materials evaluated, 14 insecticides exhibited increasing efficacy, in which the percentage of dead and moribund insects (used as a measure of insecticide efficacy) increased by &gt; 10% after 7 d. By contrast, insecticide efficacy values of eight insecticides declined by &gt; 10% (based on recovery of adults from a moribund state) over the 7-d period with most belonging to the pyrethroid class. In this study, the efficacy value of neonicotinoid, acetamiprid, showed the greatest decline from 93 to 10% over 7 d. A lethality index (scale of 0-100) was developed to compare insecticides based on quantifying the immediate and longer-term effects of insecticide exposure on H. halys. Among all materials evaluated, dimethoate, malathion, bifenthrin, methidathion, endosulfan, methomyl, chlorpyrifos, acephate, fenpropathrin, and permethrin yielded the highest values (&gt; 75) because of a high degree of immediate mortality with very little recovery. Our results provide baseline information regarding potential of candidate insecticides against adult H. halys and highlight the need to consider longer-term effects in establishing overall efficacy ratings against this invasive species.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>