<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q56654556</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/J.MARPOLBUL.2018.03.023</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Non-native marine bryozoans (Bryozoa: Gymnolaemata) in Brazilian waters: Assessment, dispersal and impacts</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Miranda, Adélia A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Almeida, Ana C.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vieira, Leandro M</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-03-21</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://www.elsevier.com/tdm/userlicense/1.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier BV</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Bryozoa is a phylum of aquatic invertebrates widely distributed around the world, including harbor areas. They have association to artificial structures as main mechanism of dispersal, including ships, which facilitates their introduction to new environments. The detection of exotic species is important to prevent new introductions and to propose management strategies of marine areas. Thus, after analyzing and discussing local and global criteria of exotic species, an account of exotic bryozoans from Brazil is presented, including 12 classified as exotic (six established and six detected) and 17 classified as potentially exotic (cryptogenic). Three species have been reported causing economic or environmental impacts worldwide. Of those, Membraniporopsis tubigera is known to cause economic impacts on the Brazilian coast. Hull fouling is the main dispersal mechanism for exotic bryozoans. The lacking of reliable data did not allow inferring on the exotic status on some fouling bryozoan species in Brazil.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>