<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q60487900</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.7287/PEERJ.PREPRINTS.27334V1</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasion of an inconspicuous ambrosia beetle and fungus may alter wood decay in Southeastern North America</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hulcr, Jiri</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Skelton, James</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Johnson, Andrew J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, You</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jusino, Michelle A</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-11-09</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>PeerJ</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:bold&gt;Background&lt;/jats:bold&gt;. Ambrosia beetles include well-known invasive pests, but most species established in non-native areas do not cause any significant impact. Here we report the recent invasion and rapid spread of &lt;jats:italic&gt;Ambrosiodmus minor&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in the Southeastern US.&lt;/jats:p&gt;
        &lt;jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:bold&gt;Methods&lt;/jats:bold&gt;: We used a combination of a multi-year survey, literature data on fungal symbionts from the beetle mycangia and in vitro bioassays of fungal competition, and extensive field observations of wood colonization patterns.&lt;/jats:p&gt;
        &lt;jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:bold&gt;Results&lt;/jats:bold&gt;. In less than seven years, &lt;jats:italic&gt;A. minor&lt;/jats:italic&gt; abundance has increased many-fold in Florida. The beetle is associated with an aggressive wood-rot fungus &lt;jats:italic&gt;Flavodon ambrosius&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. Joint colonization of wood by &lt;jats:italic&gt;A. minor&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. ambrosius&lt;/jats:italic&gt; results in extensive white rot (lignin removal). The invasion of this symbiosis may impact an ecosystem function previously considered not influenced by non-native ambrosia beetles: wood decay. We suggest monitoring of the impact of this invasion on native wood-inhabiting organisms, biomass degradation and the carbon cycle throughout the region.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>