<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q28834476</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q28834476</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4839042</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S10886-016-0678-Y</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Seasonal Changes Affect Root Prunasin Concentration in Prunus serotina and Override Species Interactions between P. serotina and Quercus petraea</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Robakowski, Piotr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bielinis, Ernest</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stachowiak, Jerzy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mejza, Iwona</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bułaj, Bartosz</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-03</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>phenotypic plasticity hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q116193364</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:phenotypic plasticity hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q116193364</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q109467185</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Quercus petraea</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Prunus serotina</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biotic interaction</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The allocation of resources to chemical defense can decrease plant growth and photosynthesis. Prunasin is a cyanogenic glycoside known for its role in defense against herbivores and other plants. In the present study, fluctuations of prunasin concentrations in roots of Prunus serotina seedlings were hypothesized to be: (1) dependent on light, air temperature, and humidity; (2) affected by competition between Prunus serotina and Quercus petraea seedlings, with mulching with Prunus serotina leaves; (3) connected with optimal allocation of resources. For the first time, we determined prunasin concentration in roots on several occasions during the vegetative season. The results indicate that seasonal changes have more pronounced effects on prunasin concentration than light regime and interspecific competition. Prunus serotina invested more nitrogen in the synthesis of prunasin under highly restricted light conditions than in higher light environments. In full sun, prunasin in roots of Prunus serotina growing in a monoculture was correlated with growth and photosynthesis, whereas these relationships were not found when interspecific competition with mulching was a factor. The study demonstrates that prunasin concentration in Prunus serotina roots is the result of species-specific adaptation, light and temperature conditions, ontogenetic shift, and, to a lesser extent, interspecific plant-plant interactions.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>