<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110829533</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.15421/2017_142</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The invaders as natural biondicators using the example invasive amphipod Gmelinoides fasciatus (Stebbing, 1899) in the Moscow River Basin: the suggestion of G. lacustris/G. fasciatus bioindication pair</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Marin, I. N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-12-27</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>drainage basin</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Gmelinoides fasciatus</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oles Honchar Dnipropetrovsk National University</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The article presents data on the study of the diversity of crustacean communities in the Moscow-river basin. Two most common are two species of amphipods, invasive species Gmelinodes fasciatus and the native species Gammarus lacustris, were detected and studies during the study. However, the number of one of the most important bioindicator species of crustaceans, Asellus aquaticus found in our samples is insufficient for quantitative conclusions. At the same time, population of G. fasciatus can be characterized as stable at all studied stations and the species can be used as bioindicator of the natural condition of the river flowing within the Moscow City. The species seems to be significantly less sensitive to environment conditions and especially anthropogenic pollution than the native amphipod species G. lacustris and can successfully replace A. aquaticus as bioindicator species in the area where the latter species is absent. Thus, a new bioindicator pair Gammarus lacustris / Gmelinoides fasciatus is suggested for using in estimation water pollution In European part of the Russian Federation and adjacent areas.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>