<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q118126128</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q118126128</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3389/FPLS.2022.1020621</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Influence of multiple global change drivers on plant invasion: Additive effects are uncommon</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Yang, Bin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cui, MiaoMiao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Du, YiZhou</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ren, GuangQian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Jian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, CongYan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, GuanLin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dai, ZhiCong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rutherford, Susan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wan, Justin S. H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Du, DaoLin</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-11-14</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>plant invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Frontiers Media SA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive plants threaten biodiversity and cause huge economic losses. It is thought that global change factors (GCFs) associated with climate change (including shifts in temperature, precipitation, nitrogen, and atmospheric CO2) will amplify their impacts. However, only few studies assessed mixed factors on plant invasion. We collated the literature on plant responses to GCFs to explore independent, combined, and interactive effects on performance and competitiveness of native and invasive plants. From 176 plant species, our results showed that: (1) when native and invasive plants are affected by both independent and multiple GCFs, there is an overall positive effect on plant performance, but a negative effect on plant competitiveness; (2) under increased precipitation or in combination with temperature, most invasive plants gain advantages over natives; and (3) interactions between GCFs on plant performance and competitiveness were mostly synergistic or antagonistic. Our results indicate that native and invasive plants may be affected by independent or combined GCFs, and invasive plants likely gain advantages over native plants. The interactive effects of factors on plants were non-additive, but the advantages of invasive plants may not increase indefinitely. Our findings show that inferring the impacts of climate change on plant invasion from factors individually could be misleading. More mixed factor studies are needed to predict plant invasions under global change.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>