<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q93166277</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7161574</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.7717/PEERJ.8889</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Epiphytic fungi induced pathogen resistance of invasive plant Ipomoea cairica against Colletotrichum gloeosporioides</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Xu, Hua</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhu, Minjie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Shaoshan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ruan, Weibin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xie, Can</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-04-13</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Ipomoea cairica</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Colletotrichum gloeosporioides</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>PeerJ</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:sec&gt;
               &lt;jats:title&gt;Background&lt;/jats:title&gt;
               &lt;jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:italic&gt;Ipomoea cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (L.) Sweet is a destructive invasive weed in South China but rarely infected with pathogens in nature. Its pathogen resistance mechanism is largely unknown at present. Some non-pathogenic isolates of &lt;jats:italic&gt;Fusarium oxysporum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Fusarium fujikuroi&lt;/jats:italic&gt; are prevalent on many plant species and function as pathogen resistance inducers of host plants. The objective of the present research is to investigate whether the symbiosis between the both fungi and &lt;jats:italic&gt;I. cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; is present, and thereby induces pathogen resistance of &lt;jats:italic&gt;I. cairica.&lt;/jats:italic&gt;&lt;/jats:p&gt;
            &lt;/jats:sec&gt;
            &lt;jats:sec&gt;
               &lt;jats:title&gt;Methods&lt;/jats:title&gt;
               &lt;jats:p&gt;Through field investigation, we explored the occurrence rates of &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. fujikuroi&lt;/jats:italic&gt; on leaf surfaces of &lt;jats:italic&gt;I. cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; plants in natural habitats and compared their abundance between healthy leaves and leaves infected with &lt;jats:italic&gt;Colletotrichum gloeosporioides&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, a natural pathogen. With artificial inoculation, we assessed their pathogenicity to &lt;jats:italic&gt;I. cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and studied their contribution of pathogen resistance to &lt;jats:italic&gt;I. cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; against &lt;jats:italic&gt;C. gloeosporioides.&lt;/jats:italic&gt;&lt;/jats:p&gt;
            &lt;/jats:sec&gt;
            &lt;jats:sec&gt;
               &lt;jats:title&gt;Results&lt;/jats:title&gt;
               &lt;jats:p&gt;We found that &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. fujikuroi&lt;/jats:italic&gt; were widely epiphytic on healthy leaf surfaces of &lt;jats:italic&gt;I. cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in sunny non-saline&lt;jats:italic&gt;,&lt;/jats:italic&gt; shady non-saline and sunny saline habitats. Their occurrence rates reached up to 100%. Moreover, we found that the abundance of &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. fujikuroi&lt;/jats:italic&gt; on leaves infected with &lt;jats:italic&gt;C. gloeosporioides&lt;/jats:italic&gt; were significantly lower than that of healthy leaves. With artificial inoculation, we empirically confirmed that &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. fujikuroi&lt;/jats:italic&gt; were non-pathogenic to &lt;jats:italic&gt;I. cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. It was interesting that colonization by&lt;jats:italic&gt; F. fujikuroi&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; alone and a mixture of both fungi resulted in a reduction of &lt;jats:italic&gt;C. gloeosporioides&lt;/jats:italic&gt; infection to &lt;jats:italic&gt;I. cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; accompanied by lower lesion area to leaf surface area ratio, increased hydrogen peroxide (H&lt;jats:sub&gt;2&lt;/jats:sub&gt;O&lt;jats:sub&gt;2&lt;/jats:sub&gt;) concentration and salicylic acid (SA) level relative to the control. However, &lt;jats:italic&gt;NPR1&lt;/jats:italic&gt; expression, chitinase and β-1,3-glucanase activities as well as stem length and biomass of &lt;jats:italic&gt;I. cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; plant only could be significantly improved by &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and a mixture of both fungi but not by &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. fujikuroi&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. In addition, as compared to colonization by &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and a mixture of both fungi,&lt;jats:italic&gt; F. fujikuroi&lt;/jats:italic&gt; induced significantly higher jasmonic acid (JA) level but significantly lower β-1,3-glucanase activity in leaves of &lt;jats:italic&gt;I. cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; plants. Thus, our findings indicated the symbiosis of epiphytic fungi&lt;jats:bold /&gt;&lt;jats:italic&gt;F. fujikuroi&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; induced systemic resistance of &lt;jats:italic&gt;I. cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; against&lt;jats:italic&gt; C. gloeosporioides&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; played a dominant role in inducing pathogen resistance of &lt;jats:italic&gt;I. cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. Its presence alleviated the antagonism of the JA signaling on SA-dependent β-1,3-glucanase activity and enabled&lt;jats:italic&gt; I. cairica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; plants to maintain relatively higher level of resistance against &lt;jats:italic&gt;C. gloeosporioides.&lt;/jats:italic&gt;&lt;/jats:p&gt;
            &lt;/jats:sec&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>