<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114001254</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114001254</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.33002/NR2581.6853.040308</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ecosystem Approach in Dealing with Invasive Alien Species: International, European and Ukrainian Experience of Legal Regulation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Suietnov, Yevhenii</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tulina, Elbis</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-09-30</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>The Grassroots Institute</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>This article is devoted to highlighting the international, European and Ukrainian experience encompassing legal regulation dealing with the invasive alien species that represent the second largest threat to global biodiversity, right after habitat destruction. It has been proved that, at the international level, primarily within the framework of the Convention on Biological Diversity, the ecosystem approach is recognized as the basis in dealing with such species. It is also gradually being reflected in the regulatory framework of the European Union. The provisions of the EU on nature protection and the relevant regulations of the European Commission define invasive species, which are prohibited from activities that may contribute to their dissemination in the environment. In the Ukrainian environmental law, a positive trend towards the recognition of the ecosystem approach in dealing with invasive alien species is observed primarily among national strategic documents, while in current national environmental legislation, these issues are regulated fragmentarily and inconsistently, which indicates the need for its early reform.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>