<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110625963</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110625963</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/D11090164</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Potential Invasion Risk of Pet Traded Lizards, Snakes, Crocodiles, and Tuatara in the EU on the Basis of a Risk Assessment Model (RAM) and Aquatic Species Invasiveness Screening Kit (AS-ISK)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kopecký, Oldřich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bílková, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamatová, Veronika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kazovická, Dominika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konrádová, Lucie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kunzová, Barbora</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Slaměníková, Jana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Slanina, Ondřej</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Šmídová, Tereza</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zemancová, Tereza</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-09-13</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasiveness</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ecological invasion risk</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion risk analysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>risk assessment model</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Because biological invasions can cause many negative impacts, accurate predictions are necessary for implementing effective restrictions aimed at specific high-risk taxa. The pet trade in recent years became the most important pathway for the introduction of non-indigenous species of reptiles worldwide. Therefore, we decided to determine the most common species of lizards, snakes, and crocodiles traded as pets on the basis of market surveys in the Czech Republic, which is an export hub for ornamental animals in the European Union (EU). Subsequently, the establishment and invasion potential for the entire EU was determined for 308 species using proven risk assessment models (RAM, AS-ISK). Species with high establishment potential (determined by RAM) and at the same time with high potential to significantly harm native ecosystems (determined by AS-ISK) included the snakes Thamnophis sirtalis (Colubridae), Morelia spilota (Pythonidae) and also the lizards Tiliqua scincoides (Scincidae) and Intellagama lesueurii (Agamidae).</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>