<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111373128</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.5586/ASBP.2015.039</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The spread of Impatiens parviflora DC. in Central European oak forests – another stage of invasion?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Reczyńska, Kamila</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Świerkosz, Krzysztof</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dajdok, Zygmunt</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2015-12-10</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Impatiens parviflora</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Polish Botanical Society</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;In this study, we examine the pattern of occurrence of &lt;em&gt;Impatiens parviflora&lt;/em&gt; in Central European oak forests over time and its ecological requirements within these types of communities. Research was based on phytosociological data collected in 3776 relevés. A modified TWINSPAN algorithm were used to distinguish the groups of oak forests. The ecological preferences of the &lt;em&gt;I. parviflora&lt;/em&gt; and studied communities as well as differences between invaded and non-invaded vegetation plots were analyzed using mean weighted Ellenberg indicator values (EIVs). Finally, both the temporal pattern of &lt;em&gt;I. parviflora&lt;/em&gt; participation and changes in its coverage in the studied communities were analyzed. Our study confirmed a high adaptability of this species with respect to temperature, moisture, soil reaction and nutrients and determined its broad ecological optimum in oak forests. However, it also revealed both a greater sensitivity of some communities within Central European oak forests to the invasion of &lt;em&gt;I. parviflora&lt;/em&gt; and differences in habitat conditions between invaded and non-invaded vegetation plots. This suggests that the habitat niche of &lt;em&gt;I. parviflora&lt;/em&gt; within oak forests is not accidental. The analysis of temporal changes in the frequency of &lt;em&gt;I. parviflora&lt;/em&gt; confirmed a 20% increase in relevés over the last 50 years. However, we did not identify any statistically significant rise in the coverage of &lt;em&gt;I. parviflora&lt;/em&gt; in oak forests specifically during the studied period.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>