<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q55619537</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6031701</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/PHYTOKEYS.101.25057</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Wandering throughout South America: Taxonomic revision of Tradescantia subg. Austrotradescantia (D.R.Hunt) M.Pell. (Commelinaceae)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>O. O. Pellegrini, Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-06-27</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>Commelinales</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tradescantia fluminensis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tradescantieae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tradescantiinae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tradescantia hertweckii</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Commelinaceae</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>I present the first taxonomic revision for T. subg. Austrotradescantia, based on extensive field, cultivation and herbaria studies. I accept 13 species, three of them (i.e. &lt;i&gt;T. atlantica&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;T. hertweckii&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;T. tucumanensis&lt;/i&gt;) being described as new in the present study. I provide an identification key to the species, distribution maps, descriptions, comments, conservation assessments and illustrations for all species. The troublesome weed &lt;i&gt;T. fluminensis&lt;/i&gt; has its specific limits clarified and its native range is presented so it can serve as a basis to better understanding its ecological requirements and to help control it throughout its invasive range. Furthermore, I highlight that &lt;i&gt;T. mundula&lt;/i&gt;, a commonly neglected species closely related to &lt;i&gt;T. fluminensis&lt;/i&gt;, might also represent a troublesome weed. &lt;i&gt;Tradescantia mundula&lt;/i&gt; has been widely introduced in cultivation under the name &lt;i&gt;T. albiflora&lt;/i&gt; and seems to have also escaped from cultivation. However, due to the hitherto poorly understood specific limits of &lt;i&gt;T. fluminensis&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;T. mundula&lt;/i&gt; has been treated as a mere cultivar of &lt;i&gt;T. fluminensis&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;s.s.&lt;/i&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>