<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q56395425</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q56395425</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.7717/PEERJ.5332</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Herbivore biocontrol and manual removal successfully reduce invasive macroalgae on coral reefs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Neilson, Brian J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wall, Christopher B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mancini, Frank T</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gewecke, Catherine A</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-08-08</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>coral reef</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>herbivory</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biocontrol</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>herbivore</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>seaweed</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive macroalga</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>PeerJ</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive macroalgae pose a serious threat to coral reef biodiversity by monopolizing reef habitats, competing with native species, and directly overgrowing, and smothering reef corals. Several invasive macroalgae (Eucheuma clade E, Kappaphycus clade A and B, Gracilaria salicornia, and Acanthophora spicifera) are established within Kāne‘ohe Bay (O‘ahu, Hawai‘i, USA), and reducing invasive macroalgae cover is a coral reef conservation and management priority. Invasive macroalgae control techniques, however, are limited and few successful large-scale applications exist. Therefore, a two-tiered invasive macroalgae control approach was designed, where first, divers manually remove invasive macroalgae (Eucheuma and Kappaphycus) aided by an underwater vacuum system (“The Super Sucker”). Second, hatchery-raised juvenile sea urchins (Tripneustes gratilla), were outplanted to graze and control invasive macroalgae regrowth. To test the effectiveness of this approach in a natural reef ecosystem, four discrete patch reefs with high invasive macroalgae cover (15–26%) were selected, and macroalgae removal plus urchin biocontrol (treatment reefs, n_=_2), or no treatment (control reefs, n_=_2), was applied at the patch reef-scale. In applying the invasive macroalgae treatment, the control effort manually removed ∼19,000 kg of invasive macroalgae and ∼99,000 juvenile sea urchins were outplanted across to two patch reefs, totaling ∼24,000 m2 of reef area. Changes in benthic cover were monitored over 2 years (five sampling periods) before-and-after the treatment was applied. Over the study period, removal and biocontrol reduced invasive macroalgae cover by 85% at treatment reefs. Our results show manual removal in combination with hatchery raised urchin biocontrol to be an effective management approach in controlling invasive macroalgae at reef-wide spatial scales and temporal scales of months to years.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>