<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q56996858</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q56996858</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1155/2011/737298</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Variation in Specificity of Soil-Borne Pathogens from a Plant's Native Range versus Its Nonnative Range</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>O. Reinhart, Kurt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Van der Putten, Wim H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tytgat, Tom</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Clay, Keith</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>exotic range</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Existing theory for invasive nonnative species emphasizes the role of escaping specialist enemies. A useful approach is to reciprocally transplant enemies in a controlled and common experiment to quantify the interaction specificity of enemies from plant's native and nonnative ranges. Quantitative measures of interaction specificity, from two experiments with three host genotypes (Belgium, Louisiana, and Pennsylvania) and 37Pythiumisolates (10 Europe and 27 USA), revealed thatPythiumpathogens from populations ofPrunus serotinain its native range were not host genotype specific whilePythiumpathogens from its nonnative range vary with host genotype. This study provides empirical evidence suggesting thatPythiumfrom the nonnative range are either preadapted to or are actively adapting to this host. Although only for a single pathosystem, this study illustrates the importance of understanding enemy impact and host-specificity to assess whether an invader has escaped its natural enemies.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>