<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q33442006</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q33442006</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4221027</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0111433</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Lights, cameracitizen science: assessing the effectiveness of smartphone-based video training in invasive plant identification</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Starr, Jared</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schweik, Charles M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bush, Nathan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fletcher, Lena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Finn, Jack</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fish, Jennifer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bargeron, Charles T</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2014-11-05</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>smartphone</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>citizen science</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The rapid growth and increasing popularity of smartphone technology is putting sophisticated data-collection tools in the hands of more and more citizens. This has exciting implications for the expanding field of citizen science. With smartphone-based applications (apps), it is now increasingly practical to remotely acquire high quality citizen-submitted data at a fraction of the cost of a traditional study. Yet, one impediment to citizen science projects is the question of how to train participants. The traditional "in-person" training model, while effective, can be cost prohibitive as the spatial scale of a project increases. To explore possible solutions, we analyze three training models: 1) in-person, 2) app-based video, and 3) app-based text/images in the context of invasive plant identification in Massachusetts. Encouragingly, we find that participants who received video training were as successful at invasive plant identification as those trained in-person, while those receiving just text/images were less successful. This finding has implications for a variety of citizen science projects that need alternative methods to effectively train participants when in-person training is impractical.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>