<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114728730</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114728730</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.76.80215</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>_Threats to UK freshwaters under climate change: Commonly traded aquatic ornamental species and their potential pathogens and parasites</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Guilder, James</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Copp, Gordon H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thrush, Mark A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stinton, Nicholas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Murphy, Debbie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Murray, Joanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tidbury, Hannah J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-10-03</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>climate change</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ornamental trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquarium species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The aquatic ornamental industry, whilst providing socio-economic benefits, is a known introduction pathway for non-native species, which if invasive, can cause direct impacts to native species and ecosystems and also drive disease emergence by extending the geographic range of associated parasites and pathogens and by facilitating host-switching, spillover and spill-back. Although current UK temperatures are typically below those necessary for the survival and establishment of commonly-traded tropical, and some sub-tropical, non-native ornamental species, the higher water temperatures predicted under climate-change scenarios are likely to increase the probability of survival and establishment. Our study aimed primarily to identify which of the commonly-traded non-native ornamental aquatic species (fish and invertebrates), and their pathogens and parasites, are likely to benefit in terms of survival and establishment in UK waters under predicted future climate conditions. Out of 233 ornamental species identified as traded in the UK, 24 were screened, via literature search, for potential parasites and pathogens (PPPs) due to their increased risk of survival and establishment under climate change. We found a total of 155 PPPs, the majority of which were platyhelminths, viruses and bacteria. While many of the identified PPPs were already known to occur in UK waters, PPPs currently absent from UK waters and with zoonotic potential were also identified. Results are discussed in the context of understanding potential impact, in addition to provision of evidence to inform risk assessment and mitigation approaches.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>