<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111322112</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111322112</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PCBI.1009660</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Modeling CRISPR gene drives for suppression of invasive rodents using a supervised machine learning framework</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Champer, Samuel E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oakes, Nathan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sharma, Ronin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>García-Díaz, Pablo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Champer, Jackson</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Messer, Philipp W</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-12-29</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive rodent</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive rodent populations pose a threat to biodiversity across the globe. When confronted with these invaders, native species that evolved independently are often defenseless. CRISPR gene drive systems could provide a solution to this problem by spreading transgenes among invaders that induce population collapse, and could be deployed even where traditional control methods are impractical or prohibitively expensive. Here, we develop a high-fidelity model of an island population of invasive rodents that includes three types of suppression gene drive systems. The individual-based model is spatially explicit, allows for overlapping generations and a fluctuating population size, and includes variables for drive fitness, efficiency, resistance allele formation rate, as well as a variety of ecological parameters. The computational burden of evaluating a model with such a high number of parameters presents a substantial barrier to a comprehensive understanding of its outcome space. We therefore accompany our population model with a meta-model that utilizes supervised machine learning to approximate the outcome space of the underlying model with a high degree of accuracy. This enables us to conduct an exhaustive inquiry of the population model, including variance-based sensitivity analyses using tens of millions of evaluations. Our results suggest that sufficiently capable gene drive systems have the potential to eliminate island populations of rodents under a wide range of demographic assumptions, though only if resistance can be kept to a minimal level. This study highlights the power of supervised machine learning to identify the key parameters and processes that determine the population dynamics of a complex evolutionary system.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>