<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117046455</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117046455</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/D14121101</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Streamlining Agroecological Management of Invasive Plant Species: The Case of Solanum elaeagnifolium Cav</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tataridas, Alexandros</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kanatas, Panagiotis</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Travlos, Ilias</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-12-11</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Solanum elaeagnifolium</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>agroecology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The increased demand for the adoption of sustainable practices to protect agroecosystems is challenged by the introduction and dominance of invasive plant species (IPS). The management of IPS requires a direct response from farmers and policy makers and is often associated with the adoption of practices that have negative ecological impacts. Solanum elaeagnifolium Cav. (silverleaf nightshade) is a noxious IPS posing a serious threat to agriculture and the environment. The increased resistance to the biotic and abiotic stress factors caused by high phenotypic plasticity, dense trichomes, and spines allow the weed to adapt to many habitats, rendering several herbicides ineffective. If an early detection and eradication fails, multiple management strategies should be adopted to mitigate a further dispersal. Herbicides should be applied before or during flowering to prevent the formation of berries and the production of seeds. Precision agriculture tools, such as decision support systems, can be exploited to reduce the herbicide input. Soil tillage should be avoided to prevent clonal reproduction. Mowing is an effective tool to prevent the setting of seeds. Biological agents should be carefully released as a part of an agroecological weed management framework. Future research should focus on the development of cross-boundary protocols and actions to monitor the introduction pathways for the early detection and agroecological management of S. elaeagnifolium.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>