<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117047704</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117047704</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.78.95050</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>_Knowledge needs in economic costs of invasive species facilitated by canalisation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Balzani, Paride</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cuthbert, Ross N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Briski, Elizabeta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Galil, Bella</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Castellanos-Galindo, Gustavo A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kouba, Antonín</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kourantidou, Melina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leung, Brian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Soto, Ismael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haubrock, Phillip J</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-12-19</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Canals provide wide-ranging economic benefits, while also serving as corridors for the introduction and spread of aquatic alien species, potentially leading to negative ecological and economic impacts. However, to date, no comprehensive quantifications of the reported economic costs of these species have been done. Here, we used the InvaCost database on the monetary impact of invasive alien species to identify the costs of those facilitated by three major canal systems: the European Inland Canals, Suez Canal, and Panama Canal. While we identified a staggering number of species having spread via these systems, monetary costs have been reported only for a few. A total of $33.6 million in costs have been reported from species linked to European Inland Canals (the fishhook waterflea Cercopagis pengoi and the zebra mussel Dreissena polymorpha) and $8.6 million linked to the Suez Canal (the silver-cheeked toadfish Lagocephalus sceleratus, the lionfish Pterois miles, and the nomad jellyfish Rhopilema nomadica), but no recorded costs were found for species facilitated by the Panama Canal. We thus identified a pervasive lack of information on the monetary costs of invasions facilitated by canals and highlighted the uneven distribution of costs.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>