<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110757768</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110757768</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/METABO12010028</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Fish Skin and Gill Mucus: A Source of Metabolites for Non-Invasive Health Monitoring and Research</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ivanova, Lada</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rangel-Huerta, Oscar D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tartor, Haitham</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gjessing, Mona C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dahle, Maria K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Uhlig, Silvio</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-12-31</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Mucous membranes such as the gill and skin mucosa in fish protect them against a multitude of environmental factors. At the same time, changes in the molecular composition of mucus may provide valuable information about the interaction of the fish with their environment, as well as their health and welfare. In this study, the metabolite profiles of the plasma, skin and gill mucus of freshwater Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar) were compared using liquid chromatography coupled to high-resolution mass spectrometry (LC-HRMS). Several normalization procedures aimed to reduce unwanted variation in the untargeted data were tested. In addition, the basal metabolism of skin and gills, and the impact of the anesthetic benzocaine for euthanisation were studied. For targeted metabolomics, the commercial AbsoluteIDQ p400 HR kit was used to evaluate the potential differences in metabolic composition in epidermal mucus as compared to the plasma. The targeted metabolomics data showed a high level of correlation between different types of biological fluids from the same individual, indicating that mucus metabolite composition could be used for fish health monitoring and research.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>