<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q36298467</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q36298467</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0173091</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>An association between decreasing incidence of invasive non-typhoidal salmonellosis and increased use of antiretroviral therapy, Gauteng Province, South Africa, 2003-2013.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Keddy, Karen H</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Takuva, Simbarashe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Musekiwa, Alfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Puren, Adrian J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sooka, Arvinda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Karstaedt, Alan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klugman, Keith P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Angulo, Frederick J</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-03-06</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>anti-retroviral agent</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>South Africa</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive non-typhoidal salmonellosis</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>BackgroundHIV-infected persons are at increased risk of opportunistic infections, including invasive nontyphoidal Salmonella (iNTS) infections; antiretroviral therapy (ART) reduces this risk. We explored changing iNTS incidence associated with increasing ART availability in South Africa.MethodsLaboratory-based surveillance for iNTS was conducted in Gauteng Province, South Africa, with verification using the National Health Laboratory Service's Central Data Warehouse (CDW), between 2003 and 2013. Isolates were serotyped at the Centre for Enteric Diseases. CDW data on patient numbers obtaining HIV viral load measurements provided estimates of numbers of HIV-infected patients receiving ART. A Poisson regression model was used to measure the changing incidence of iNTS infection from 2003 to 2013. The correlation between the incidence of iNTS and ART use from 2004 to 2013 was determined using Pearson's correlation coefficient.ResultsFrom 2003-2013, the incidence of iNTS per 100,000 population per year decreased from 5.0 to 2.2 (p ConclusionsThe incidence of iNTS infections including Salmonella Typhimurium decreased significantly in Gauteng Province in association with increased ART utilization. Adult men accessed ART programs less than women, translating into increasing iNTS incidence in this group. Monitoring iNTS incidence may assist in monitoring the ART program. Increasing incidence of invasive Salmonella Enteritidis infections needs further elucidation.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>