<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114918229</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114918229</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/BIOLOGY11071013</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Nidus vespae Built by an Invasive Alien Hornet, Vespa velutina_nigrithorax, Inhibits Adipose Tissue Expansion in High-Fat Diet-Induced Obese Mice</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Seul Gi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Dong Se</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chae, Jongbeom</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Eunbi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hahn, Dongyup</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Il-Kwon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Chang-Jun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Choi, Moon Bo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nam, Ju-Ock</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-07-06</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Vespa velutina</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Nidus vespae, commonly known as the wasp nest, has antioxidative, anti-inflammatory, antimicrobial, and antitumor properties. However, the anti-obesity effects of Nidus vespae extract (NV) have not yet been reported. This study aimed to elucidate the potential anti-obesity effects of NV in vivo and in vitro, using a high-fat diet (HFD)-induced obese mouse model and 3T3-L1 adipocytes, respectively. NV administration to HFD-induced obese mice significantly decreased the mass and plasma lipid content of adipose tissues. Uncoupling protein-1 expression was significantly higher in the inguinal white adipose tissues of NV-treated mice than in those of HFD-fed mice. Furthermore, we found that NV inhibited the differentiation and intracellular lipid accumulation of 3T3-L1 adipocytes by regulating the insulin signaling cascade, including protein kinase B, peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor gamma, CCAAT/enhancer binding protein alpha, and adiponectin. These findings suggest that NV may exhibit therapeutic effects against obesity by suppressing adipose tissue expansion and preadipocyte differentiation, thereby providing critical information for the development of new drugs for disease prevention and treatment. To our knowledge, this study provides the first evidence of the anti-obesity effects of NV.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>