<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q36187492</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q36187492</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0165427</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Experimental Test of Preferences for an Invasive Prey by an Endangered Predator: Implications for Conservation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wilcox, Rebecca C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fletcher, Robert J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-11-09</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>predation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>predator–prey system</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive prey</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pomacea maculata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Snail Kite</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>conservation biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Identifying impacts of exotic species on native populations is central to ecology and conservation. Although the effects of exotic predators on native prey have received much attention, the role of exotic prey on native predators is poorly understood. Determining if native predators actively prefer invasive prey over native prey has implications for interpreting invasion impacts, identifying the presence of evolutionary traps, and predator persistence. One of the world's most invasive species, Pomacea maculata, has recently established in portions of the endangered Everglade snail kite's (Rostrhamus sociabilis plumbeus) geographic range. Although these exotic snails could provide additional prey resources, they are typically much larger than the native snail, which can lead to lower foraging success and the potential for diminished energetic benefits in comparison to native snails. Nonetheless, snail kites frequently forage on exotic snails. We used choice experiments to evaluate snail kite foraging preference in relation to exotic species and snail size. We found that snail kites do not show a preference for native or exotic snails. Rather, snail kites generally showed a preference for medium-sized snails, the sizes reflective of large native snails. These results suggest that while snail kites frequently forage on exotic snails in the wild, this behavior is likely driven simply by the abundance of exotic snails rather than snail kites preferring exotics. This lack of preference offers insights to hypotheses regarding effects of exotic species, guidance regarding habitat and invasive species management, and illustrates how native-exotic relationships can be misleading in the absence of experimental tests of such interactions.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>