<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q118138179</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q118138179</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/PLANTS11233369</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Both Adaptability and Endophytic Bacteria Are Linked to the Functional Traits in the Invasive Clonal Plant Wedelia trilobata</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mei, Ying-Hao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Xu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhou, Jian-Yu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kong, Fang-Li</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Qi, Shan-Shan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhu, Bin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Naz, Misbah</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dai, Z-C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Du, Dao-Lin</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-12-04</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Wedelia trilobata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>functional trait</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The role of the interactions between endophytes and host plants is unclear in invasive plants from different geographical latitudes. In this study, we aimed to explore the relationship between endophytic microbes and the functional traits of the invasive plant Wedelia trilobata. We explored the relationship between endophytes and the clonal growth traits of the invasive clonal plant Wedelia trilobata from different geographical latitudes using high-throughput sequencing technology and a common garden-planting experiment. We found that: (1) Different W. trilobata populations had similar endophytic fungi but different endophytic bacteria. However, no latitudinal variation pattern of the overall microbial community was found; (2) plant clonal growth performance (i.e., spacer length) was significantly correlated with endophytic bacterial diversity but not fungal diversity; and (3) the latitudinal variation pattern of the plant clonal growth performance of W. trilobata populations was found in pre-cultivated (i.e., wild) individuals but disappeared in post-cultivated W. trilobata. Our results suggest both environmental adaptability and the endophytic bacterial community are linked to the functional traits of the invasive clonal plant W. trilobata, and these functional traits tend to increase its invasiveness, which may enhance its invasion success.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>