<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111148784</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111148784</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/SU12010057</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Physicochemical Analysis and Essential Oils Extraction of the Gorse (Ulex europaeus) and French Broom (Genista monspessulana), Two Highly Invasive Species in the Colombian Andes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Osorio-Castiblanco, Diego F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peyre, Gwendolyn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saldarriaga, Juan F</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-12-23</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Ulex europaeus</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Genista monspessulana</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>essential oil</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Gorse (Ulex europaeus) and French broom (Genista monspessulana) are two highly invasive species that have become a threat to tropical countries, especially in Andean ecosystems. This research focused on providing a physicochemical characterization and essential oils extraction of both species to better understand their potential valorization and guide further environmental management efforts. For this purpose, the following analyses were conducted for both species: higher heat value (HHV), elemental analysis, proximate analysis, thermogravimetric analysis to obtain constituent natural polymers (hemicellulose, cellulose, and lignin), and extraction of essential oils and other interest chemical compounds through supercritical fluids. Ecological closeness was found between the two species mostly regarding HHV, fixed carbon, and volatile matter, which calls for similar potential uses. Both species were also found to be suitable for combustion processes, gasification, extraction of chemical compounds, and use of lignocellulosic content; however, only U. europaeus appeared suitable for activated carbon obtention. Therefore, this work provided relevant data that can be used as preliminary basis to establish strong scientifically-based management and control strategies for these two invasive species. We recommend focusing primarily on thermal processes such as pyrolysis, gasification, or combustion, and also essential oils extractions of acetic acid, dodecanoic acid, anagyrine, amylene hydrate, caulophylline, and maltol in the future.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>