<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110663857</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110663857</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.68.68572</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>A global assessment of the potential distribution of naturalized and planted populations of the ornamental alien tree Schinus molle</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ramírez-Albores, Jorge E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Richardson, David M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stefenon, Valdir M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bizama, Gustavo A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pérez-Suárez, Marlín</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Badano, Ernesto I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-09-21</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Schinus molle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The Peruvian Peppertree (Schinus molle L.) is an evergreen tree native to semiarid environments of Peru and Bolivia in South America. This tree has been introduced and widely planted for ornamental and forestry purposes in several semiarid regions of the world because its seedlings are easily established and have a high survival rate; it also grows quickly, and it is tolerant of dry climates. We compared the global and regional niches of naturalized and planted populations of S. molle in order to examine the invasive stages and potential distribution of this species in four regions of the world. This work provides a novel approach for understanding the invasion dynamics of S. molle in these areas and elucidates the ecological processes that bring about such invasions. Most naturalized and planted populations were found to be in equilibrium with the environment. In its native range as well as in Australia and South Africa the models of the coverage area of habitat suitability for natural populations were the highest, whereas the coverage area of planted populations was lower. For planted populations in Australia and South Africa, a large percentage of predicted presences fell within sink populations. The invasion stages of S. molle vary across regions in its adventive range; this result may be attributable to residence time as well as climatic and anthropic factors that have contributed to the spread of populations.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>