<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q47264973</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q47264973</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5836269</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/GIGASCIENCE/GIX128</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>A hybrid-hierarchical genome assembly strategy to sequence the invasive golden mussel Limnoperna fortunei.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Uliano-Silva, Marcela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dondero, Francesco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Otto, Thomas Dan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Costa, Igor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lima, Nicholas Costa Barroso</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Americo, Juliana Alves</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mazzoni, Camila Junqueira</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prosdocimi, Francisco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Freitas Rebelo, Mauro</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-02-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Limnoperna fortunei</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive hybrid</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>BackgroundFor more than 25 years, the golden mussel, Limnoperna fortunei, has aggressively invaded South American freshwaters, having travelled more than 5000 km upstream across 5 countries. Along the way, the golden mussel has outcompeted native species and economically harmed aquaculture, hydroelectric powers, and ship transit. We have sequenced the complete genome of the golden mussel to understand the molecular basis of its invasiveness and search for ways to control it.FindingsWe assembled the 1.6-Gb genome into 20 548 scaffolds with an N50 length of 312 Kb using a hybrid and hierarchical assembly strategy from short and long DNA reads and transcriptomes. A total of 60 717 coding genes were inferred from a customized transcriptome-trained AUGUSTUS run. We also compared predicted protein sets with those of complete molluscan genomes, revealing an exacerbation of protein-binding domains in L. fortunei.ConclusionsWe built one of the best bivalve genome assemblies available using a cost-effective approach using Illumina paired-end, mate-paired, and PacBio long reads. We expect that the continuous and careful annotation of L. fortunei's genome will contribute to the investigation of bivalve genetics, evolution, and invasiveness, as well as to the development of biotechnological tools for aquatic pest control.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>