<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q35035009</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q35035009</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0077083</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Increase in male reproductive success and female reproductive investment in invasive populations of the harlequin ladybird Harmonia axyridis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Laugier, Guillaume J M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moguédec, Gilles Le</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tayeh, Ashraf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loiseau, Anne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Osawa, Naoya</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Estoup, Arnaud</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Facon, Benoît</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2013-10-18</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Harmonia axyridis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>reproductive success</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Reproductive strategy affects population dynamics and genetic parameters that can, in turn, affect evolutionary processes during the course of biological invasion. Life-history traits associated with reproductive strategy are therefore potentially good candidates for rapid evolutionary shifts during invasions. In a series of mating trials, we examined mixed groups of four males from invasive and native populations of the harlequin ladybird Harmonia axyridis mating freely during 48 hours with one female of either type. We recorded the identity of the first male to copulate and after the 48 h-period, we examined female fecundity and share of paternity, using molecular markers. We found that invasive populations have a different profile of male and female reproductive output. Males from invasive populations are more likely to mate first and gain a higher proportion of offspring with both invasive and native females. Females from invasive populations reproduce sooner, lay more eggs, and have offspring sired by a larger number of fathers than females from native populations. We found no evidence of direct inbreeding avoidance behaviour in both invasive and native females. This study highlights the importance of investigating evolutionary changes in reproductive strategy and associated traits during biological invasions.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>