<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q112270999</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3389/FPLS.2022.827497</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ecological Niche Shifts Affect the Potential Invasive Risk of &lt;i&gt;Rapistrum rugosum&lt;/i&gt; (L.) All. in China</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Xian, Xiaoqing</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhao, Haoxiang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Rui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Qiao, Huijie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guo, Jianyang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Guifen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, Wanxue</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wan, Fanghao</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-04-15</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Rapistrum rugosum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>niche shift</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ecological niche</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Frontiers Media SA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Ecological niche is a key concept that links species distributions. Ecological niche shifts are expected to affect the potential invasive risk of alien species. &lt;jats:italic&gt;Rapistrum rugosum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; is an invasive agricultural weed in many countries. Wild populations of &lt;jats:italic&gt;R. rugosum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; have been recorded in China, representing a great threat to the regional crops. Based on distribution records from different regions and relevant environmental variables, the present study predicted the potential distribution and estimated the invasive risk of &lt;jats:italic&gt;R. rugosum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in China. Ecological niche shifts strongly affected the potential invasive risk of &lt;jats:italic&gt;R. rugosum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in China. The two most important variables were annual temperature range (Bio7) and mean temperature of the coldest quarter (Bio11). The total suitable habitat for the species covered an area of 287.53 × 10&lt;jats:sup&gt;4&lt;/jats:sup&gt;km&lt;jats:sup&gt;2&lt;/jats:sup&gt; and was mainly distributed in Southwest, Southeast, and Central China. Australia, Canada, Brazil, the United States, and Argentina accounted for over 90% of the inspection records of &lt;jats:italic&gt;R. rugosum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; from Chinese entry ports during 2015–2018. The intercepted &lt;jats:italic&gt;R. rugosum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; was frequently mixed in &lt;jats:italic&gt;Glycine max&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (L.) Merr., &lt;jats:italic&gt;Hordeum vulgare&lt;/jats:italic&gt; L., linseed, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Triticum aestivum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; L., and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Sorghum bicolor&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (L.) Moench. Moreover, 80% interceptions were recorded from Tianjin, Guangdong, Nanjing, and Chengdu customs. Climatic conditions do not limit the establishment capability of &lt;jats:italic&gt;R. rugosum&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in China. Our results provide a theoretical reference for the development of monitoring and control measures for this invasive weed.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>