<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117045342</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117045342</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.11606/1807-0205/2023.63.010</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Morphology, morpho-taxometric and molecular characterization of the invasive alien species Caribbean leatherleaf slug Sarasinula plebeia (Gastropoda: Veronicellidae): a first record in southern Philippines</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dalan, Loel Bacolod</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diano, Michelle Anne Bernabe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sumaya, Nanette Hope</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-02-02</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Sarasinula plebeia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Veronicellidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidade de Sao Paulo, Agencia USP de Gestao da Informacao Academica (AGUIA)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Herein, we first report the comprehensive description of the terrestrial slug, Sarasinula plebeia (Gastropoda: Veronicellidae) by employing morphology, morpho-taxometrics and molecular analysis. A rapid survey on terrestrial slug invasive alien species (IAS) was conducted in La Dicha, Malangas, Zamboanga Sibugay, the Philippines. Obtained COI gene sequences shared 100% similarities to S._plebeia from Brazil (JX532107, KM489378), Dominica (KM489500) and Vietnam (KM489367) and further supported using Bayesian analysis thus designated as S._plebeia isolate LDZS. Notably, the first reported S._plebeia in 2013 from Batan island, Batanes, northern Philippines, characterized through COI gene markers (JQ582277, JQ582278, JQ582279) showed 100% sequence similarities to a closely related veronicellid slug, Laevecaulis alte isolates (LC636101, LC636102, LC636103, and LC636104) from Japan. Taken this into account, our S._plebeia LDZS isolated from an agricultural field is the first report in the Philippines with combined diagnostic tools for the taxon.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>