<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q58703993</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q58703993</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1155/2012/837165</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Eucalypts and Their Potential for Invasiveness Particularly in Frost-Prone Regions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Booth, Trevor H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasiveness</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Eucalypts are being considered for biofuel production in the Lower Coastal Plain of the United States. The evolution of eucalypts in Australia has equipped some species to be successful in plantations and has also influenced their potential as invasive species. More than 200 eucalypt species have been evaluated in many countries around the world. Generally eucalypts have proved to have limited invasive potential for a number of reasons, including their poor dispersal capabilities. Two regions with climates similar to the Lower Coastal Plain of the United States are identified in Argentina and China. Frosts, particularly sudden frosts, are an important limitation for eucalypts in these regions, so existing plantations are very limited. However, invasive eucalypts do not appear to be a major problem in other regions of either country. The use of carefully selected frost-tolerant species and the development of genetically modified eucalypts may now open up more frost-affected areas for eucalypt plantations. Some control actions may be necessary and research needs are outlined, but it is concluded that experience in other regions around the world suggests that eucalypts are likely to be a relatively low risk as invasive species in the Lower Coastal Plain.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>