<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111148716</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111148716</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/SU12155951</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Identifying Sustainable Grassland Management Approaches in Response to the Invasive Legume Lespedeza cuneata: A Functional Group Approach</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Garrett, Erin M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gibson, David J</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-07-23</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Lespedeza cuneata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>We propose combining the filter framework model of community assembly with the passenger-driver model of non-native species behavior to help clarify the impacts of invasive species in the communities they invade and to guide sustainable management protocols. Observational field surveys and a greenhouse experiment explored the role of the invasive legume Lespedeza cuneata in the communities it invades and how natives in three functional groups—grasses, forbs, and legumes—respond to its presence. Within-site analyses from the field survey revealed differences in invaded and uninvaded areas in half of the sites, suggesting that site-specific characteristics influences whether L. cuneata’s presence corresponds to local differences in species composition. The greenhouse experiment found higher levels of saprophytic and arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi in soil conditioned by L. cuneata than in unconditioned soil. However, competition between L. cuneata or the native congener L. capitata and nine native species illustrated stronger aboveground competitive effects than belowground soil effects due to soil conditioning, with impacts differing among functional groups. The response of L. cuneata was reduced in the presence of grasses and other legumes but not forbs. Assessing the impact of L. cuneata with the combined community assembly model revealed this invasive plant acts as a driver because it alters abiotic and biotic filters to impact species composition. Managing for high grass abundance and planting native legumes will help sustain grasslands from L. cuneata invasion.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>