<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q73940505</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0031182099005958</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Richness patterns in the parasite communities of exotic poeciliid fishes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dove, Alistair</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2000-06-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://www.cambridge.org/core/terms</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>disturbance hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q115794757</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:disturbance hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q115794757</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press (CUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Three species of poeciliids (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Gambusia holbrooki&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Xiphophorus helleri&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;X. maculatus&lt;/jats:italic&gt;) and 15 species of ecologically similar 
native freshwater fishes (mainly eleotrids, ambassids, melanotaeniids and retropinnids) were examined for parasite richness 
to investigate parasite flux, qualitative differences, quantitative differences and the structuring factors in parasite communities 
in the 2 fish types in Queensland, Australia. Theory suggests that poeciliids would harbour depauperate parasite 
communities. Results supported this hypothesis; poeciliids harboured more species-poor parasite infracommunities and 
regional faunas than natives (&lt;jats:italic&gt;P&lt;/jats:italic&gt; &lt; 0·0001), despite greater sampling effort for the former. Cluster analysis of 
presence/absence data for poeciliids and the 6 most-sampled native fishes revealed that parasite communities of the 2 fish groups 
are qualitatively distinct; the proportion of parasite species with complex life-cycles was lower in poeciliids than in native 
species, and Myxosporea, Microspora, Coccidia and parasitic Crustacea were all absent from poeciliids. Limited exchange 
of parasite species has occurred between natives and poeciliids. Logistic ordinal regression analysis revealed that fish 
origin (exotic or native), environmental disturbance and host sex were all significant determinants of parasite community 
richness (&lt;jats:italic&gt;P&lt;/jats:italic&gt; &lt; 0·05). Theoretical modelling suggests that poeciliids are at a competitive advantage over native fishes because 
of their lack of parasites.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>