<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q35985678</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4827816</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0153098</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Homogenous Population Genetic Structure of the Non-Native Raccoon Dog (Nyctereutes procyonoides) in Europe as a Result of Rapid Population Expansion</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Drygala, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Korablev, Nikolay</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ansorge, Hermann</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fickel, Joerns</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Isomursu, Marja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Elmeros, Morten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kowalczyk, Rafał</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baltrunaite, Laima</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Balciauskas, Linas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saarma, Urmas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulze, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Borkenhagen, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frantz, Alain C</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-04-11</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nyctereutes procyonoides</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>population genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The extent of gene flow during the range expansion of non-native species influences the amount of genetic diversity retained in expanding populations. Here, we analyse the population genetic structure of the raccoon dog (Nyctereutes procyonoides) in north-eastern and central Europe. This invasive species is of management concern because it is highly susceptible to fox rabies and an important secondary host of the virus. We hypothesized that the large number of introduced animals and the species' dispersal capabilities led to high population connectivity and maintenance of genetic diversity throughout the invaded range. We genotyped 332 tissue samples from seven European countries using 16 microsatellite loci. Different algorithms identified three genetic clusters corresponding to Finland, Denmark and a large 'central' population that reached from introduction areas in western Russia to northern Germany. Cluster assignments provided evidence of long-distance dispersal. The results of an Approximate Bayesian Computation analysis supported a scenario of equal effective population sizes among different pre-defined populations in the large central cluster. Our results are in line with strong gene flow and secondary admixture between neighbouring demes leading to reduced genetic structuring, probably a result of its fairly rapid population expansion after introduction. The results presented here are remarkable in the sense that we identified a homogenous genetic cluster inhabiting an area stretching over more than 1500km. They are also relevant for disease management, as in the event of a significant rabies outbreak, there is a great risk of a rapid virus spread among raccoon dog populations.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>