<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111327719</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/PLANTS10071324</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Heterogenous Impact of Water Warming on Exotic and Native Submerged and Emergent Plants in Outdoor Mesocosms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gillard, Morgane B</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Caudal, Jean-Pierre</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Deleu, Carole</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thiébaut, Gabrielle</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-06-29</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>mesocosm</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Some aquatic plants present high biomass production with serious consequences on ecosystem functioning. Such mass development can be favored by environmental factors. Temperature increases are expected to modify individual species responses that could shape future communities. We explored the impact of rising water temperature on the growth, phenology, and metabolism of six macrophytes belonging to two biogeographic origins (exotic, native) and two growth forms (submerged, emergent). From June to October, they were exposed to ambient temperatures and a 3 °C warming in outdoor mesocosms. Percent cover and canopy height were favored by warmer water for the exotic emergent Ludwigia hexapetala. Warming did not modify total final biomass for any of the species but led to a decrease in total soluble sugars for all, possibly indicating changes in carbon allocation. Three emergent species presented lower flavonol and anthocyanin contents under increased temperatures, suggesting lower investment in defense mechanisms and mitigation of the stress generated by autumn temperatures. Finally, the 3 °C warming extended and shortened flowering period for L. hexapetala and Myosotis scorpioides, respectively. The changes generated by increased temperature in outdoor conditions were heterogeneous and varied depending on species but not on species biogeographic origin or growth form. Results suggest that climate warming could favor the invasiveness of L. hexapetala and impact the structure and composition of aquatic plants communities.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>