<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q35808036</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4488508</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S13199-015-0324-4</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Root-inhabiting fungi in alien plant species in relation to invasion status and soil chemical properties</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Majewska, Marta L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Błaszkowski, Janusz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nobis, Marcin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rola, Kaja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nobis, Agnieszka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Łakomiec, Daria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Czachura, Paweł</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zubek, Szymon</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2015-05-15</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>In order to recognize interactions between alien vascular plants and soil microorganisms and thus better understand the mechanisms of plant invasions, we examined the mycorrhizal status, arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) colonization rate, arbuscular mycorrhiza (AM) morphology and presence of fungal root endophytes in 37 non-native species in Central Europe. We also studied the AMF diversity and chemical properties of soils from under these species. The plant and soil materials were collected in southern Poland. We found that 35 of the species formed AM and their mycorrhizal status depended on species identity. Thirty-three taxa had AM of &lt;i&gt;Arum&lt;/i&gt;-type alone. &lt;i&gt;Lycopersicon esculentum&lt;/i&gt; showed intermediate AM morphology and &lt;i&gt;Eragrostis albensis&lt;/i&gt; developed both &lt;i&gt;Arum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Paris&lt;/i&gt;. The mycelia of dark septate endophytes (DSE) were observed in 32 of the species, while sporangia of &lt;i&gt;Olpidium&lt;/i&gt; spp. were found in the roots of 10. Thirteen common and worldwide occurring AMF species as well as three unidentified spore morphotypes were isolated from trap cultures established with the soils from under the plant species. &lt;i&gt;Claroideoglomus claroideum&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Funneliformis mosseae&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Septoglomus constrictum&lt;/i&gt; were found the most frequently. The presence of root-inhabiting fungi and the intensity of their colonization were not correlated with soil chemical properties, plant invasion status, their local abundance and habitat type. No relationships were also found between the presence of AMF, DSE and &lt;i&gt;Olpidium&lt;/i&gt; spp. These suggest that other edaphic conditions, plant and fungal species identity or the abundance of these fungi in soils might have an impact on the occurrence and intensity of fungal root colonization in the plants under study.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>