<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117047091</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117047091</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/RS15010212</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The Use of an Airborne Laser Scanner for Rapid Identification of Invasive Tree Species Acer negundo in Riparian Forests</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mielczarek, Dominik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sikorski, Piotr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Archiciński, Piotr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ciężkowski, Wojciech</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zaniewska, Ewa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chormański, Jarosław</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-12-30</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Acer negundo</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive tree</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive species significantly impact ecosystems, which is fostered by global warming. Their removal generates high costs to the greenery managers; therefore, quick and accurate identification methods can allow action to be taken with minimal impact on ecosystems. Remote sensing techniques such as Airborne Laser Scanning (ALS) have been widely applied for this purpose. However, many species of invasive plants, such as Acer negundo L., penetrate the forests under the leaves and thus make recognition difficult. The strongly contaminated riverside forests in the Vistula valley were examined in the gradient of the center of Warsaw and beyond its limits within a Natura 2000 priority habitat (91E0), namely, alluvial and willow forests and poplars. This work aimed to assess the potentiality of a dual-wavelength ALS in identifying the stage of the A. negundo invasion. The research was carried out using over 500 test areas of 4 m diameter within the riparian forests, where the habitats did not show any significant traces of transformation. LiDAR bi-spectral data with a density of 6 points/m2 in both channels were acquired with a Riegl VQ-1560i-DW scanner. The implemented approach is based on crown parameters obtained from point cloud segmentation. The Adaptive Mean Shift 3D algorithm was used to separate individual crowns. This method allows for the delineation of individual dominant trees both in the canopy (horizontal segmentation) and undergrowth (vertical segmentation), taking into account the diversified structure of tree stands. The geometrical features and distribution characteristics of the GNDVI (Green Normalized Vegetation Index) were calculated for all crown segments. These features were found to be essential to distinguish A. negundo from other tree species. The classification was based on the sequential additive modeling algorithm using a multi-class loss function. Results with a high accuracy, exceeding 80%, allowed for identifying and localizing tree crowns belonging to the invasive species. With the presented method, we could determine dendrometric traits such as the age of the tree, its height, and the height of the covering leaves of the trees.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>