<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q39296212</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1002/PTR.4787</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Phytochemicals isolated from leaves of Chromolaena odorata: impact on viability and clonogenicity of cancer cell lines</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kouamé, Prevost Bi-Koffi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jacques, Camille</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bedi, Gustave</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Silvestre, Virginie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loquet, Denis</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barillé-Nion, Sophie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Robins, Richard J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tea, Illa</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012-08-16</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/tdm_license_1.1</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>phytochemistry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Chromolaena odorata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The leaves of Chromolaena odorata (Asteraceae) are exploited extensively in West and Central African ethnopharmacy for the treatment of a wide range of conditions, despite this being a non-native species established in the last 50 years. With the objective of seeking bioactive principles, the nonvolatile compounds, an ethanolic (80% v/v) extract was made and fractionated. From the hexane-soluble fraction, three compounds were isolated. Two of these, 5-hydroxy-7,4'-dimethoxyflavanone and 2'-hydroxy-4,4',5',6'-tetramethoxychalcone, have previously been identified in C. odorata leaves. The third was fully characterised spectroscopically and found to be 1,6-dimethyl-4-(1-methylethyl)naphthalene (cadalene), not previously isolated from the Asteraceae. All three compounds were tested for their cytotoxicity and anticancer properties. 2'-Hydroxy-4,4',5',6'-tetramethoxychalcone was found to be both cytotoxic and anticlonogenic at 20 µm in cell lines Cal51, MCF7 and MDAMB-468, and to act synergistically with the Bcl2 inhibitor ABT737 to enhance apoptosis in Cal51 breast cancer cells.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>