<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q52727587</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5845374</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1186/S12917-018-1408-1</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasion and replication of Yersinia ruckeri in fish cell cultures</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Menanteau-Ledouble, Simon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lawrence, Mark L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>El-Matbouli, Mansour</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-03-09</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Yersinia ruckeri</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;h4&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;Like many members of the Enterobacteriaceae family, Yersinia ruckeri has the ability to invade non professional phagocytic cells. Intracellular location is advantageous for the bacterium because it shields it from the immune system and can help it cross epithelial membranes and gain entry into the host. In the present manuscript, we report on our investigation regarding the mechanisms of Y. ruckeri's invasion of host cells.&lt;h4&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;A gentamycin assay was applied to two isolates, belonging to both the biotype 1 (ATCC 29473) and biotype 2 (A7959-11) and using several cell culture types: Atlantic Salmon Kidney, Salmon Head Kidney and, Chinook salmon embryos cells at both low and high passage numbers. Varying degrees of sensitivity to Y. ruckeri infection were found between the cell types and the biotype 1 strain was found to be more invasive than the non-motile biotype 2 isolate. Furthermore, the effect of six chemical compounds (Cytochalasin D, TAE 226, vinblastine, genistein, colchicine and, N-acetylcysteine), known to interfere with bacterial invasion strategies, were investigated. All of these compounds had a significant impact on the ability of the bacterium to invade host cells. Changes in the concentration of bacterial cells over time were investigated and the results suggested that neither isolate could survive intracellularly for sustained periods.&lt;h4&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h4&gt;These results suggest that Y. ruckeri can gain entrance into host cells through several mechanisms, and might take advantage of both the actin and microtubule cytoskeletal systems.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>