<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q106606443</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.64.60050</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Urban host plant utilisation by the invasive Halyomorpha halys (Stål) (Hemiptera, Pentatomidae) in northern Utah</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Holthouse, Mark Cody</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spears, Lori R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alston, Diane G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-01-28</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic science</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>brown marmorated stink bug</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hemiptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pentatomidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The invasive and highly polyphagous brown marmorated stink bug, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Halyomorpha halys&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Stål), is a severe agricultural and urban nuisance pest in North America. Since its initial invasion into Utah in 2012, &lt;jats:italic&gt;H. halys&lt;/jats:italic&gt; has become well established in urban and suburban locations along the western foothills of the Wasatch Front in northern Utah. Bordering the Great Basin Desert, this area is unique from other North American locations with &lt;jats:italic&gt;H. halys&lt;/jats:italic&gt; due to its high elevation (&amp;gt; 1200 m), aridity (30-year mean RH = 53.1%; dew point = -1.9 °C) and extreme temperatures (the 30-year mean minimum and maximum in January and July in Salt Lake City range from -3.1 to 3.6 °C and 20.3 to 32.4 °C, respectively). To document which plant species harbour &lt;jats:italic&gt;H. halys&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, surveys were conducted in 17 urban/suburban sites in four counties during 2017 and 2018. &lt;jats:italic&gt;Halyomorpha halys&lt;/jats:italic&gt; was more abundant in Salt Lake and Utah counties than in the more northern counties of Davis and Weber and was found on 53 plant species, nine of which hosted two or more developmental stages in both years. The majority of hosts were in the families Fabaceae, Rosaceae and Sapindaceae. Northern catalpa, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Catalpa speciosa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Warder), was the most consistent host, supporting a majority of &lt;jats:italic&gt;H. halys&lt;/jats:italic&gt; detections in all life stages; thus we identify it as a sentinel host. Twenty-nine species were novel hosts for &lt;jats:italic&gt;H. halys&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in North America; of these, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Acer ginnala&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Maxim, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Populus tremuloides&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Michx., &lt;jats:italic&gt;Prunus armeniaca × domestica&lt;/jats:italic&gt; ‘Flavor King’ and &lt;jats:italic&gt;Prunus virginiana&lt;/jats:italic&gt; ‘Schubert’ were detected with two or more life stages of &lt;jats:italic&gt;H. halys&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in both years. Peak populations of &lt;jats:italic&gt;H. halys&lt;/jats:italic&gt; occurred from mid-June to mid-September. We describe &lt;jats:italic&gt;H. halys&lt;/jats:italic&gt; plant utilisation by life stage and seasonal period to aid future detection and management of this invasive insect in the greater Intermountain West region.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>