<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114725927</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114725927</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.55355/SNV2022112102</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Annual and biennial invasive species in the flora of Ivanovo</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Borisova, Elena Anatolyevna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dmitrieva, Zhanna Mikhailovna</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-06-01</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Samara State University of Social Sciences and Education</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The paper analyzes invasive plant species in a large regional center of European Russia  the city of Ivanovo. Based on the conducted research (by 2022) a group of 25 annual and biennial invasive plant species were identified in Ivanovo, which belong to 10 families and 19 genera. The authors have established ecopopological features of successfully naturalized of these species within the city limits, as well as their association with certain natural and anthropogenic ecotopes. 4 most active species (Bidens frondosa, Heraculum sosnowsky, Impatiens glandulifera, I. parviflora) are classified as transformers. They form dense monodominant thickets in various parts of the city, successfully compete and displace species of native flora. The largest number of species occurs in ecotopes, which are characterized by a simplified structure and lability. 17 species are in the composition of natural ecotopes, and the most vulnerable among them are water bodies and riparian communities. Among the anthropogenic ecotopes, habitats (24 species), roadsides (20 species) and wastelands (19 species) are more actively populated by invasive annual and biennial species. The problems of control and management of the spread of invasive species, including a large group of annual and biennial plants, should be solved comprehensively, within the framework of general economic and social urban programs based on scientific monitoring data.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>