<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q37223851</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5007670</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/SREP32646</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive stink bug favors naïve plants: Testing the role of plant geographic origin in diverse, managed environments</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Martinson, Holly M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bergmann, Erik J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Venugopal, Dilip</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Riley, Christopher B</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shrewsbury, Paula M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raupp, Michael J</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-09-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;With the introduction and establishment of exotic species, most ecosystems now contain both native and exotic plants and herbivores. Recent research identifies several factors that govern how specialist herbivores switch host plants upon introduction. Predicting the feeding ecology and impacts of introduced generalist species, however, remains difficult. Here, we examine how plant geographic origin, an indicator of shared co-evolutionary history, influences patterns of host use by a generalist, invasive herbivore, while accounting for variation in plant availability. The brown marmorated stink bug, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Halyomorpha halys&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, is a highly polyphagous Asian herbivore and an economically important invasive pest in North America and Europe. In visual surveys of 220 plant taxa in commercial nurseries in Maryland, USA, &lt;jats:italic&gt;H. halys&lt;/jats:italic&gt; was more abundant on non-Asian plants and selected these over Asian plants. The relationship between the relative use of plants and their availability was strongly positive but depended also on plant origin at two of our three sites, where the higher relative use of non-Asian plants was greatest for highly abundant taxa. These results highlight the importance of considering both plant origin and relative abundance in understanding the selection of host plants by invasive generalist herbivores in diverse, natural and urban forests.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>