<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117046537</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117046537</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/F14010112</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The Effectiveness of Natura 2000 Network in Conserving Salix_alba and Populus alba Galleries against Invasive Species: A Case Study of Mureșul Mijlociu—Cugir Site, Romania</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Avram, Cristina Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Proorocu, Marian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mălinaș, Anamaria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mălinaș, Cristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-01-06</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Populus alba</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Romania</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>There is currently a lack of knowledge regarding the effectiveness of the Natura 2000 (N2000) network in providing protection against biological invasion by invasive alien species (IAS). In this study, we analyzed two Salix alba and Populus alba riparian habitats located both inside and outside a N2000 site from Romania in order to assess the efficacy of N2000 network in conserving this type of ecosystem against IAS. Field investigations were conducted both using polygon method for vegetation study and semi-structured interviews focusing on the local people knowledge and their contribution to biological invasion. We found that the research area located within the N2000 network is highly exposed to biological invasion by IAS, the major threat to this type of habitat being expressed by Acer negundo, which occupied more than half of the vegetation cover. It seems that not only the management strategy should be blamed for this situation, but rather its failure in popularization and application. As such, in our opinion, future management plans developed by N2000 network should rely on the intertwined co-evolutionary mechanisms existing between poplar and willow stands diversity and cultural diversity, by integrating aspects related to local traditional knowledge.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>