<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q49182433</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q49182433</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5799775</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/ZOOKEYS.730.21599</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>New records of an alien aphid species Tinocallis (Sappocallis) takachihoensis from countries in central and northern Europe (Hemiptera, Aphididae, Calaphidinae)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kanturski, Mariusz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Yerim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Depa, Łukasz</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-01-17</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hemiptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Aphididae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The aphid genus Tinocallis Matsumura, 1919 (Hemiptera: Aphididae: Calaphidinae) in central and northern Europe is reviewed; it includes four species. The first records of the Asian elm aphid Tinocallis takachihoensis Higuchi, 1972 are reported from the Czech Republic, Denmark, and Poland. The record in Denmark is the first in Scandinavia. Alate viviparous females and nymphs of T. takachihoensis were collected from Ulmus glabra "Pendula" (the Czech Republic and Poland) and from U. minor (Denmark) in 2017. Tinocallis takachihoensis is the fourth Tinocallis species to be recorded from Poland and together with two other species from the subgenus Sappocallis, T. nevskyi and T. saltans, is a species of alien origin. The alate viviparous females are reviewed and re-described and their affinities and distribution in central and northern Europe are discussed. A key to the European species of Tinocallis based on the characters of live and slide-mounted specimens is also given.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>