<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111165953</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111165953</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0376892920000211</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive vertebrate eradications on islands as a tool for implementing global Sustainable Development Goals</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wit, Luz A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zilliacus, Kelly M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Quadri, Paulo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Will, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grima, Nelson</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spatz, Dena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Holmes, Nick</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tershy, Bernie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Howald, Gregg R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Croll, Donald A</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-08-13</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive vertebrate</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sustainable Development Goals</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>island invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>species eradication</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press (CUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>SummaryThe United Nations 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development sets a framework of universal Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) to address challenges to society and the planet. Island invasive species eradications have well-documented benefits that clearly align with biodiversity conservation-related SDGs, yet the value of this conservation action for socioeconomic benefits is less clear. We examine the potential for island invasive vertebrate eradications to have ecological and socioeconomic benefits. Specifically, we examine: (1) how SDGs may have been achieved through past eradications; and (2) how planned future eradications align with SDGs and associated targets. We found invasive vertebrate eradication to align with 13 SDGs and 42 associated targets encompassing marine and terrestrial biodiversity conservation, promotion of local and global partnerships, economic development, climate change mitigation, human health and sanitation and sustainable production and consumption. Past eradications on 794 islands aligned with a median of 17 targets (range 13–38) by island. Potential future eradications on 292 highly biodiverse islands could align with a median of 25 SDG targets (range 15–39) by island. This analysis enables the global community to explicitly describe the contributions that invasive vertebrate management on islands can make towards implementing the global sustainable development agenda.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>