<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q41549469</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q41549469</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-017-10315-Z</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Global invasion network of the brown marmorated stink bug, Halyomorpha halys.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Valentin, Rafael E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Anne L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wiman, Nik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Doo-Hyung</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fonseca, Dina M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-08-29</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>brown marmorated stink bug</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractHuman mediated transportation into novel habitats is a prerequisite for the establishment of non-native species that become invasive, so knowledge of common sources may allow prevention. The brown marmorated stink bug (BMSB, Halyomorpha halys) is an East Asian species now established across North America and Europe, that in the Eastern United States of America (US) and Italy is causing significant economic losses to agriculture. After US populations were shown to originate from Northern China, others have tried to source BMSB populations now in Canada, Switzerland, Italy, France, Greece, and Hungary. Due to selection of different molecular markers, however, integrating all the datasets to obtain a broader picture of BMSB’s expansion has been difficult. To address this limitation we focused on a single locus, the barcode region in the cytochrome oxidase I mitochondrial gene, and analyzed representative BMSB samples from across its current global range using an Approximate Bayesian Computation approach. We found that China is the likely source of most non-native populations, with at least four separate introductions in North America and three in Europe. Additionally, we found evidence of one bridgehead event: a likely Eastern US source for the central Italy populations that interestingly share enhanced pest status.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>