<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q92095524</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q92095524</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7171142</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-020-63611-6</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Antibodies against a short region of PfRipr inhibit Plasmodium falciparum merozoite invasion and PfRipr interaction with Rh5 and SEMA7A</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nagaoka, Hikaru</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kanoi, Bernard N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ntege, Edward H</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aoki, Masamitsu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fukushima, Akihisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tsuboi, Takafumi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Takashima, Eizo</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-04-20</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Plasmodium falciparum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractPlasmodium falciparum merozoite invasion into erythrocytes is an essential step of the blood-stage cycle, survival of parasites, and malaria pathogenesis. P. falciparum merozoite Rh5 interacting protein (PfRipr) forms a complex with Rh5 and CyRPA in sequential molecular events leading to erythrocyte invasion. Recently we described PfRipr as a conserved protein that induces strain-transcending growth inhibitory antibodies in in vitro assays. However, being a large and complex protein of 1086 amino acids (aa) with 87 cysteine residues, PfRipr is difficult to express in conventional expression systems towards vaccine development. In this study we sought to identify the most potent region of PfRipr that could be developed to overcome difficulties related to protein expression, as well as to elucidate the invasion inhibitory mechanism of anti-PfRipr antibodies. Using the wheat germ cell-free system, Ecto- PfRipr and truncates of approximately 200 aa were expressed as soluble proteins. We demonstrate that antibodies against PfRipr truncate 5 (PfRipr_5: C720-D934), a region within the PfRipr C-terminal EGF-like domains, potently inhibit merozoite invasion. Furthermore, the antibodies strongly block PfRipr/Rh5 interaction, as well as that between PfRipr and its erythrocyte-surface receptor, SEMA7A. Taken together, PfRipr_5 is a potential candidate for further development as a blood-stage malaria vaccine.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>