<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q58765727</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q58765727</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6101356</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0201312</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive Streptococcus pneumoniae infection among hospitalized patients in Jingzhou city, China, 2010-2012</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jiang, Hui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huai, Yang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chen, Hui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Uyeki, Timothy M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chen, Maoyi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guan, Xuhua</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, Shali</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peng, Youxing</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yang, Hui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luo, Jun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zheng, Jiandong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huang, Jigui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peng, Zhibin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xiang, Nijuan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Yuzhi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klena, John D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hu, Dale J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rainey, Jeanette J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huo, Xixiang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xiao, Lin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xing, Xuesen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhan, Faxian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yu, Hongjie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Varma, Jay K</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Streptococcus pneumoniae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hospitalization</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>urban ecology</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>BACKGROUND:Streptococcus pneumoniae (Sp) is a leading cause of bacterial pneumonia, meningitis, and sepsis and a major source of morbidity and mortality worldwide. Invasive pneumococcal disease (IPD) is defined as isolation of Sp from a normally sterile site, including blood or cerebrospinal fluid. The aim of this study is to describe outcomes as well as clinical and epidemiological characteristics of hospitalized IPD case patients in central China. METHODS:We conducted surveillance for IPD among children and adults from April 5, 2010 to September 30, 2012, in four major hospitals in Jingzhou City, Hubei Province. We collected demographic, clinical, and outcome data for all enrolled hospitalized patients with severe acute respiratory infection (SARI) or meningitis, and collected blood, urine, and cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) for laboratory testing for Sp infections. Collected data were entered into Epidata software and imported into SPSS for analysis. RESULTS:We enrolled 22,375 patients, including 22,202 (99%) with SARI and 173 (1%) with meningitis. One hundred and eighteen (118, 3%) with either SARI or meningitis were Sp positive, 32 (0.8%) from blood/CSF culture, and 87 (5%) from urine antigen testing. Of those 118 patients, 57% were aged ≥65 years and nearly 100% received antibiotics during hospitalization. None were previously vaccinated with 7-valent pneumococcal conjugate vaccine (PCV 7), 23-valent pneumococcal polysaccharide vaccine, or seasonal influenza vaccine. The main serotypes identified were 14, 12, 3, 1, 19F, 4, 5, 9V, 15 and 18C, corresponding to serotype coverage rates of 42%, 63%, and 77% for PCV7, PCV10, and PCV13, respectively. CONCLUSIONS:Further work is needed to expand access to pneumococcal vaccination in China, both among children and potentially among the elderly, and inappropriate use of antibiotics is a widespread and serious problem in China.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>