<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q55872245</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q55872245</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/ZOOKEYS.776.26149</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ecto- and endo-parasitic monogeneans (Platyhelminthes) on cultured freshwater exotic fish species in the state of Morelos, South-Central Mexico</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mendoza-Franco, Edgar F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Caspeta-Mandujano, Juan Manuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Osorio, Marina Tapia</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-07-26</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>fresh water</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Platyhelminthes</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>An extensive parasitological study of 365 freshwater exotic fish specimens belonging to 13 species of seven families (Cichlidae, Cyprinidae, Osphronemidae, Pangasidae, Poeciliidae, Characidae, and Loricariidae) collected from 31 Aquaculture Production Units (APU) from Central Mexico revealed the occurrence of 29 ecto- and endo-parasitic monogeneans found on gills and stomachs: Cichlidogyrussclerosus, C.thurstonae, C.tilapiae, Cichlidogyrus sp. 1, Cichlidogyrus sp. 2, Enterogyruscoronatus, E.malmbergi, Gusseviaspiralocirra, Sciadicleithrumiphthimum, Sciadicleithrum sp., Scutogyruslongicornis (all Dactylogyridae), Gyrodactyluscichlidarum, and G.yacatli (Gyrodactylidae) on Oreochromisniloticus, Pterophyllumscalare and Hemichromis sp. (Cichlidae); Dactylogyrusbaueri, D.formosus, D.intermedius, D.vastator, D.extensus, Dactylogyrus sp. (all Dactylogyridae), and G.kobayashii on Carassiusauratus, Cyprinuscarpio and Ctenopharyngodonidella (Cyprinidae); Trianchoratusacleithrium and T.trichogasterium (Dactylogyridae) on Trichogastertrichopterus (Osphronemidae); Thaparocleiduscaecus, T.siamensis (Dactylogyridae), and Dactylogyridae sp. on Pangasianodonhypophthalmus (Pangasidae); G.poeciliae on Poeciliareticulata (Poeciliidae); Diaphorocleidusarmillatus (Dactylogyridae) on Gymnocorymbusternetzy (Characidae); Unilatusunilatus (Dactylogyridae) and Gyrodactylidae sp. on Hypostomus sp. (Loricariidae). The paramount importance of the establishment of these monogeneans due to the importation/exportation of non-native ornamental and other exotic host fish species cultured for food in Mexico is briefly discussed. Quarantine is recommended for all transferred host species.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>