<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q120374092</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q120374092</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/INP.2021.36</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Comparison of visual estimation and line-point intercept vegetation survey methods on annual grass–invaded rangelands of Wyoming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>De Stefano, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fowers, Beth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mealor, Brian A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-12-15</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>rangeland</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>annual grass</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>plant invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press (CUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractScientists and natural resource managers require suitable vegetation survey methods to assess the success of rangeland restoration projects. Visual estimation and point intercept methods are commonly used to evaluate vegetation cover. This study compared the performance of one visual (quadrat-based) and two line-point intercept (LPI, canopy and basal) methods to assess biodiversity and cover and to estimate biomass production on sites invaded by introduced annual grasses across Wyoming, USA. Greater species richness and higher Shannon index values were measured in quadrats, while introduced annual and native perennial graminoid cover values were higher in LPI canopy in general. Overall, these outcomes indicate quadrats as the most suitable survey method when biodiversity monitoring is the primary objective, while suggesting LPI canopy when monitoring vegetation cover is prioritized. Finally, our regression models indicated quadrat-based estimates as the most reliable to predict introduced annual and native perennial graminoid biomass.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>