<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q120000178</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q120000178</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1111/OIK.09634</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Transient dynamics in plant–pollinator networks: fewer but higher quality of pollinator visits determines plant invasion success</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Valdovinos, Fernanda S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dritz, Sabine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marsland, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-02-21</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q109467185</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>plant invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pollination network</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive plants often use mutualisms to establish in their new habitats and tend to be visited by resident pollinators similarly or more frequently than native plants. The quality and resulting reproductive success of those visits, however, have rarely been studied in a network context. Here, we use a dynamic model to evaluate the invasion success and impacts on natives of various types of non‐native plant species introduced into thousands of plant–pollinator networks of varying structure. We found that network structure properties did not predict invasion success, but non‐native traits and interactions did. Specifically, non‐native plants producing high amounts of floral rewards but visited by few pollinators at the moment of their introduction were the only plant species able to invade the networks. This result is determined by the transient dynamics occurring right after the plant introduction. Successful invasions increased the abundance of pollinators that visited the invader, but the reallocation of the pollinators' foraging effort from native plants to the invader reduced the quantity and quality of visits received by native plants and made the networks slightly more modular and nested. The positive and negative effects of the invader on pollinator and plant abundance, respectively, were buffered by plant richness. Our results call for evaluating the impact of invasive plants not only on visitation rates and network structure, but also on processes beyond pollination including seed production and recruitment of native plants.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>