<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q118138210</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q118138210</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/PLANTS11182377</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Assessing Seedbank Longevity and Seed Persistence of the Invasive Tussock Grass Nassella trichotoma Using in-Field Burial and Laboratory-Controlled Ageing</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Humphries, Talia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Florentine, Singarayer</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-09-12</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Nassella trichotoma</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive grass</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The ability to produce highly dense and persistent seedbanks is a major contributor to the successful widespread establishment of invasive plants. This study seeks to identify seed persistence and seedbank longevity for the invasive tussock grass Nassella trichotoma (Nees.) Hack. ex Arechav in order to recommend management strategies for preventing re-emergence from the seedbank. To determine the seedbank longevity and persistence, two experiments were conducted: (i) seeds were buried at four depths (0, 1, 2, and 4 cm) and collected and assessed for viability, seed decay, and in-field germination after 6, 9, 12, 15, and 18 months of field burial; and (ii) seeds were exposed to artificial ageing conditions (60% RH and 45 °C) for 1, 2, 5, 9, 20, 30, 50, 75, 100, and 120 days, and viability was determined through germination tests and tetrazolium tests. Less than 10% of the seeds collected after 12 months of in-field burial were viable. The artificial ageing treatment found germination declined to 50% after 5.8 days, further suggesting that N. trichotoma seeds are short lived. The results from both experiments indicate that N. trichotoma has a transient seedbank, with less than 10% of the seeds demonstrating short-term persistence. It is likely the persistent seeds beyond 12 months were exhibiting secondary dormancy as viable seeds did not germinate under optimal germination conditions. The “Best Practice Guidelines” recommend monitoring for seedbank recruitment for at least three years after treating N. trichotoma infestations. The results of this study support this recommendation as a small proportion of the seeds demonstrated short-term persistence.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>