<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q90171571</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q90171571</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.7717/PEERJ.7655</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Effects of mechanical and chemical control on invasive Spartina alterniflora in the Yellow River Delta, China</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Xie, Baohua</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Han, Guangxuan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Qiao, Peiyang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mei, Baoling</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Qing</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhou, Yingfeng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Anfeng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Song, Weimin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guan, Bo</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-09-03</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Spartina alterniflora</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>PeerJ</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Spartina alterniflora is one of the most noxious invasive plants in China and many other regions. Exploring environmentally friendly, economic and effective techniques for controlling Spartina alterniflora is of great significance for the management of coastal wetlands. In the present study, different approaches, including mowing and waterlogging, mowing and tilling and herbicide application, were used to control Spartina alterniflora. The results suggest that the integrated approach of mowing and waterlogging could eradicate Spartina alterniflora, the herbicide haloxyfop-r-methyl could kill almost all the Spartina alterniflora, and the integrated approach of mowing and tilling at the end of the growing season was a perfect way to inhibit the germination of Spartina alterniflora in the following year. However, no matter which control approach is adopted, secondary invasion of Spartina alterniflora must be avoided. Otherwise, all the efforts will be wasted in a few years.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>