<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q113694569</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113694569</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/TOXINS14090587</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Worldwide Web: High Venom Potency and Ability to Optimize Venom Usage Make the Globally Invasive Noble False Widow Spider Steatoda nobilis (Thorell, 1875) (Theridiidae) Highly Competitive against Native European Spiders Sharing the Same Habitats</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rayner, Sean</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vitkauskaite, Aiste</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Healy, Kevin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lyons, Keith</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McSharry, Leona</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leonard, Dayle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dunbar, John P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dugon, Michel M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-08-26</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>phenotypic plasticity hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q116193364</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:phenotypic plasticity hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q116193364</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Theridiidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Steatoda nobilis</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Venom compositions include complex mixtures of toxic proteins that evolved to immobilize/dissuade organisms by disrupting biological functions. Venom production is metabolically expensive, and parsimonious use is expected, as suggested by the venom optimisation hypothesis. The decision-making capacity to regulate venom usage has never been demonstrated for the globally invasive Noble false widow Steatoda nobilis (Thorell, 1875) (Theridiidae). Here, we investigated variations of venom quantities available in a wild population of S. nobilis and prey choice depending on venom availability. To partially determine their competitiveness, we compared their attack rate success, median effective dose (ED50) and lethal dose (LD50), with four sympatric synanthropic species: the lace webbed spider Amaurobius similis, the giant house spider Eratigena atrica, the missing sector orb-weaver Zygiella x-notata, and the cellar spider Pholcus phalangioides. We show that S. nobilis regulates its venom usage based on availability, and its venom is up to 230-fold (0.56 mg/kg) more potent than native spiders. The high potency of S. nobilis venom and its ability to optimize its usage make this species highly competitive against native European spiders sharing the same habitats.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>