<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q34206140</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q34206140</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0033185</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Preimaginal stages of the emerald ash borer, Agrilus planipennis Fairmaire (Coleoptera: Buprestidae): an invasive pest on ash trees (Fraxinus)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chamorro, Lourdes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Volkovitsh, Mark G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Poland, Therese</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haack, Robert A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lingafelter, Steven W</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012-03-16</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Coleoptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Emerald ash borer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Buprestidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>This study provides the most detailed description of the immature stages of Agrilus planipennis Fairmaire to date and illustrates suites of larval characters useful in distinguishing among Agrilus Curtis species and instars. Immature stages of eight species of Agrilus were examined and imaged using light and scanning electron microscopy. For A. planipennis all preimaginal stages (egg, instars I-IV, prepupa and pupa) were described. A combination of 14 character states were identified that serve to identify larvae of A. planipennis. Our results support the segregation of Agrilus larvae into two informal assemblages based on characters of the mouthparts, prothorax, and abdomen: the A. viridis and A. ater assemblages, with A. planipennis being more similar to the former. Additional evidence is provided in favor of excluding A. planipennis from the subgenus Uragrilus.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>