<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110809171</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110809171</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.2298/GSF0897197M</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Obolodiplosis robiniae (Haldeman) (Diptera: Cecidomyiidae): A new invasive insect pest on black locust in Serbia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mihajlovic, Ljubodrag</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Glavendekic, Milka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jakovljevic, Ivana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marjanovic, Sasa</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive insect</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Obolodiplosis robiniae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cecidomyiidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>National Library of Serbia</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Locust gall midge Obolodiplosis robiniae (Haldeman) originates from Pennsylvania, USA. It was introduced to Europe in 2003, to Italy, Veneto. Its spreading was very fast and in the following year it was identified from the Check Republic and Slovenia. In 2005, it was recorded from South Tyrol and in 2006 from Hungary, south Slovakia, Germany, Croatia, Ukraine and Serbia. During 2007 it was identified from Albania, Austria, Belgium, Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina, France, Montenegro, the Netherlands, Poland, Switzerland, Russia and UK. The expansion of locust gall midge was also recorded in Japan, South Korea, where it was identified for the first time in 2002, and in 2005 it was identified from China. The first finding from Serbia was recorded in the autumn 2006 in the surroundings of Sabac. During 2007, it was identified from Belgrade, and in the same year and the following year (2008) it was found at numerous sites in Serbia, the Republic of Srpska and Montenegro. This study presents O. robiniae biology, method of distribution, natural enemies and the ecological significance.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>