<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q107468725</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q107468725</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.65.64686</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Revisiting the non-native insect fauna of Greece: Current trends and an updated checklist</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Demetriou, Jakovos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kalaentzis, Konstantinos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kazilas, Christos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koutsoukos, Evangelos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Avtzis, Dimitrios N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Georgiadis, Christos</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-05-28</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic science</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>checklist</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Alien invasive species not only have adverse environmental impacts, they may also pose socioeconomic and human health threats. The increase in detected non-native (alien) and cryptogenic species, followed by the necessity for up-to-date scientific information on biological invasions, prompted a thorough literature investigation on the non-native entomofauna of Greece. Supplementing previous studies concerning Europe and Greece, a checklist for the non-native insect species of the country is provided, while their number is elevated from 266 to 469. Current trends regarding species richness and taxonomy, deliberate or accidental means of introduction, as well as their native range and trophic preferences are analysed and discussed. This publication illustrates the current state of non-native insects of Greece, highlighting the need for an effective early warning system integrated in national phytosanitary legislation, survey protocols and strategies towards the eradication and mitigation of their detrimental impacts.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>