<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q46305151</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1111/PLB.12628</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Local pre-adaptation to disturbance and inbreeding-environment interactions affect colonisation abilities of diploid and tetraploid Centaurea stoebe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rosche, C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hensen, I</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lachmuth, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-10-06</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/tdm_license_1.1</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>propagule pressure hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q110620464</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:propagule pressure hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q110620464</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>disturbance hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q115794757</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:disturbance hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q115794757</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Centaurea stoebe</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Primary colonisation in invasive ranges most commonly occurs in disturbed habitats, where anthropogenic disturbance may cause physical damage to plants. The tolerance to such damage may differ between cytotypes and among populations as a result of differing population histories (adaptive differentiation between ruderal verus natural habitats). Moreover, founder populations often experience inbreeding depression, the effects of which may increase through physical damage due to inbreeding-environment interactions. We aimed to understand how such colonisation processes differ between diploid and tetraploid Centaurea stoebe populations, with a view to understanding why only tetraploids are invasive. We conducted a clipping experiment (frequency: zero, once or twice in the growing season) on inbred versus outbred offspring originating from 37 C. stoebe populations of varying cytotype, range and habitat type (natural versus ruderal). Aboveground biomass was harvested at the end of the vegetation period, while re-sprouting success was recorded in the following spring. Clipping reduced re-sprouting success and biomass, which was significantly more pronounced in natural than in ruderal populations. Inbreeding depression was not detected under benign conditions, but became increasingly apparent in biomass when plants were clipped. The effects of clipping and inbreeding did not differ between cytotypes. Adaptive differentiation in disturbance tolerance was higher among populations than between cytotypes, which highlights the potential of pre-adaptation in ruderal populations during early colonisation on anthropogenically disturbed sites. While the consequences of inbreeding increased through clipping-mediated stress, they were comparable between cytotypes, and consequently do not contribute to understanding the cytotype shift in the invasive range.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>