<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q57892938</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.5194/ESSD-8-177-2016</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ecological survey of the native pinewoods of Scotland 1971</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wood, Claire M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bunce, Robert G. H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-05-10</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Copernicus GmbH</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Abstract. In 1971, a comprehensive ecological survey of the native pinewoods of Scotland was carried out by the Institute of Terrestrial Ecology. The survey was initiated as a consequence of growing concern about the status of the pinewood resource. Since the twentieth century, this unique habitat is widely recognised, not only by ecologists for its inherent biodiversity but also by the general public for its cultural and amenity value. The survey, utilising demonstrably repeatable methods, collected information on ground flora, soils, forest structure and also general site information from the major 27 sites of the 35 sites identified as truly native pinewoods in Scotland. The results from the survey prompted the organisation of an international symposium in 1975, which set the conservation agenda for the old Caledonian pinewoods. The data collected during the 1971 survey are now publicly available via the following DOI: doi:10/7xb ("Habitat, vegetation, tree and soil data from Native Pinewoods in Scotland, 1971"). Although the data are now 44 years old, the repeatable methods will allow for a resurvey to take place, in order to assess changes in the vegetation, habitats and tree composition in a statistically robust manner.
                    &lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>