<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q58997216</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q58997216</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1155/2013/476862</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Dominant Occurrence of Cleistogamous Flowers of Lamium amplexicaule in relation to the Nearby Presence of an Alien Congener L. purpureum (Lamiaceae)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sato, Yasuhiro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Takakura, Koh-Ichi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nishida, Sachiko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nishida, Takayoshi</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>henbit deadnettle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Lamiaceae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Lamiaceae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Here we document a novel phenomenon that, based on field observations in central Japan, cleistogamous flowers (or closed flowers) of an annual herb Lamium amplexicaule were dominantly expressed near an alien congener L. purpureum. The proportion of cleistogamous flowers in an individual L. amplexicaule increased with the frequency of L. purpureum occurring in the same patches but did not increase with the total density of Lamium plants and their own size. To confirm the consistency of the effect of the coexisting alien species, we assessed the cleistogamous frequency at the patch level for three other populations. In these populations as well, the proportion of L. amplexicaule producing cleistogamous flowers increased with the frequency of L. purpureum. Our transplant experiment at one site found no effect of the nearby presence of L. purpureum on the seed set of L. amplexicaule and therefore did not support the hypothesis that the adverse effect on the reproduction via interspecific pollination favored cleistogamous flowers that accepted no external pollen. Further studies must be conducted to examine the negative interactions between the related species before and after seed development.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>