<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q28818315</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q28818315</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/MD14110210</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The Potential Exploitation of the Mediterranean Invasive Alga Caulerpa cylindracea: Can the Invasion Be Transformed into a Gain?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stabili, Loredana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fraschetti, Simonetta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Acquaviva, Maria Immacolata</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cavallo, Rosa Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De Pascali, Sandra Angelica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fanizzi, Francesco Paolo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gerardi, Carmela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Narracci, Marcella</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rizzo, Lucia</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-11-15</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>drug discovery</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Caulerpa cylindracea</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Recently, there is a growing interest towards the development of strategies for invasive seaweed control and exploitation as source of secondary metabolites. Here, we investigated the potential of exploitation in biotechnology and recycling options in eradication programs of the lipidic extract of the Mediterranean invasive seaweed Caulerpa cylindracea (Chlorophyta). The chemical characterization was carried out by means of multinuclear and multidimensional NMR spectroscopy. The fatty acid profile of C. cylindracea assessed the presence of several types of molecules known for antioxidant activity such as carotenoids, chlorophylls, pheophytins, and sterols. The NMR spectroscopy showed also the characteristic signals of saturated, unsaturated, and free fatty acids as well as other metabolites including the biopolymer polyhydroxybutyrate. The lipidic extract exerted an antioxidant activity corresponding to 552.14 ± 69.13 mmol Trolox equivalent/g (ORAC) and to 70.3 ± 2.67 mmol Trolox equivalent/g (TEAC). The extract showed an antibacterial activity against several Vibrio species, suggesting its potential use in the control of diseases in mariculture. Our results show that C. cylindracea, representing a critical hazard in coastal areas, could be transformed into a gain supporting specific management actions to reduce the effects of human pressures.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>