<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q124153008</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q124153008</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/LIMNOLREV24010001</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>A Modelling Approach for the Management of Invasive Species at a High-Altitude Artificial Lake</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moutopoulos, Dimitrios K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Douligeri, Alexandra S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ziou, Athina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kiriazis, Nikolaos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Korakis, Athanasios</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petsis, Nikolaos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Katselis, George N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-12-30</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Aoös Springs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>pumpkinseed</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ecosystem resilience</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ecological modeling</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Ecopath</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>EcoSim</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The ecosystem structure of a Mediterranean high-altitude artificial lake (Aoos Springs, Northwest Greece) was assessed and quantified using the Ecopath with Ecosim model. The artificial lake was created in 1990 for hydroelectric production and the fish fauna has been enriched across years due to deliberate or accidental fish stockings, as well as the introduction of the invasive pumpkinseed (Lepomis gibbosus), which may cause adverse effects on aquatic ecosystems and their biota. The model considered 20 species/taxa groups with biological data gathered during 2021–2022 from field surveys, interviews with recreational anglers and literature. The results revealed that the artificial lake of Aoos is a resilient ecosystem to unexpected events with low intensity of fisheries exploitation. The biomass of the introduced invasive species Lepomis gibbosus is low, due to the low biomass level of its diet, Chironomidae and zoobenthic organisms as well as other fish species.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>