<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114955629</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114955629</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S10530-022-02932-1</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Biotic resistance or invasional meltdown? Diversity reduces invasibility but not exotic dominance in southern California epibenthic communities</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Beshai, Ryan A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Truong, Danny A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Henry, Amy K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sorte, Cascade J. B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-10-05</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q112148709</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biotic resistance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasional meltdown</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion resistance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractHigh community diversity may either prevent or promote the establishment of exotic species. The biotic resistance hypothesis holds that species-rich communities are more resistant to invasion than species-poor communities due to mechanisms including greater interspecific competition. Conversely, the invasional meltdown hypothesis proposes that greater exotic diversity increases invasibility via facilitative interactions between exotic species. To evaluate the degree to which biotic resistance or invasional meltdown influences marine community structure during the assembly period, we studied the development of marine epibenthic “fouling” communities at two southern California harbors. With a focus on sessile epibenthic species, we found that fewer exotic species established as total and exotic richness increased during community assembly and that this effect remained after accounting for space availability. We also found that changes in exotic abundance decreased over time. Throughout the assembly period, gains in exotic abundance were greatest when space was abundant and richness was low. Altogether, we found greater support for biotic resistance than invasional meltdown, suggesting that both native and exotic species contribute to biotic resistance during early development of these communities. However, our results indicate that biotic resistance may not always reduce the eventual dominance of exotic species.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>