<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q103812553</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0243002</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Modeling the trophic impacts of invasive zooplankton in a highly invaded river</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dexter, Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Katz, Stephen L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bollens, Stephen M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rollwagen-Bollens, Gretchen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hampton, Stephanie E</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-12-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>zooplankton</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The lower Columbia River (Washington and Oregon, USA) has been heavily invaded by a large number of planktonic organisms including the invasive copepod &lt;jats:italic&gt;Pseudodiaptomus forbesi&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and the planktonic juveniles of the invasive clam, &lt;jats:italic&gt;Corbicula fluminea&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. In order to assess the ecological impacts of these highly abundant invaders, we developed a multivariate auto-regressive (MAR) model of food web dynamics based upon a 12-year time-series of plankton community and environmental data from the Columbia River. Our model results indicate that plankton communities in the lower Columbia River are strongly impacted by the copepod &lt;jats:italic&gt;P&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;forbesi&lt;/jats:italic&gt; at multiple trophic levels. We observed different ecological effects across different life stages of &lt;jats:italic&gt;P&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;forbesi&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, with nauplii negatively impacting ciliates and autotrophs, and copepodite stages negatively impacting &lt;jats:italic&gt;Daphnia&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and cyclopoid copepods. Although juvenile &lt;jats:italic&gt;C&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;fluminea&lt;/jats:italic&gt; were highly abundant in the summer and autumn of each year, our best fit MAR model did not show significant &lt;jats:italic&gt;C&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;fluminea&lt;/jats:italic&gt; impacts. Our results illustrate the strong ecological impact that some zooplankton invaders may cause within rivers and estuarine systems, and highlight the need for further research on the feeding ecology of the planktonic life-stage of &lt;jats:italic&gt;C&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. &lt;jats:italic&gt;fluminea&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. Overall, our study demonstrates the manner in which long-term, high resolution data sets can be used to better understand the ecological impacts of invasive species among complex and highly dynamic communities.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>