<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111153859</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111153859</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/D13080380</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Dittrichia viscosa: Native-Non Native Invader</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sladonja, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Poljuha, Danijela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krapac, Marin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Uzelac, Mirela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mikulic-Petkovsek, Maja</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-08-16</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Dittrichia viscosa</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Dittrichia viscosa (L.) Greuter is a shrub native to the Mediterranean, however, declared as a very invasive species in Australia and North America. Environmental (climatic) and socio-economic (land abandonment) changes can trigger different adaptive mechanisms and cause changes in species behavior, influencing invasion dynamics. Motivated by the recently noticed change of D. viscosa behavior in its native Mediterranean habitat, we discuss the invasion properties, its behavior in the native habitat and new areas, and its management options. We review the species’ adverse effects and its positive ecosystem services in the Millennium Ecosystem Assessment framework. In this review, we provide information on the phytochemical properties of D. viscosa and highlight its potential use in ecological agriculture, phytopharmacy, and medicine. The presented data is useful for developing effective management of this contentious species, with emphasis on mitigating environmental and economic damages, especially in agriculture. The final aim is to achieve a balanced ecosystem, providing a high level of possible services (provisioning, regulating, cultural and supporting).</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>