<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q36441468</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q36441468</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1186/S13613-015-0103-7</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Systemic antifungal therapy for proven or suspected invasive candidiasis: the AmarCAND 2 study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leroy, Olivier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bailly, Sébastien</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gangneux, Jean-Pierre</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mira, Jean-Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Devos, Patrick</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dupont, Hervé</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Montravers, Philippe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perrigault, Pierre-François</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Constantin, Jean-Michel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guillemot, Didier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Azoulay, Elie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Azoulay, Elie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lortholary, Olivier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bensoussan, Caroline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Timsit, Jean-François</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>study group, AmarCAND2</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-01-08</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>candidiasis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive candidiasis</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>BackgroundIn the context of recent guidelines on invasive candidiasis (IC), how French intensive care units (ICUs) are managing IC?MethodsThis is a prospective observational multicenter cohort study. During 1_year (2012-2013), 87 French ICUs enrolled consecutive patients with suspected or proven IC (SIC or PIC) and receiving systemic antifungal therapy (SAT). Data were collected up to 28_days after inclusion.ResultsWe studied 835 patients, 291 with PIC and 544 with SIC. At SAT initiation, patients with SIC were significantly more severe (SAPS II 50.1_±_18.7 vs. 46.2_±_18.0). Severe sepsis or septic shock prompted to initiate empiric SAT in 70_% of SIC. Within 4_days in median, the initial SAT was modified in 49_% of patients with PIC vs. 33_% patients with SIC. Modifications were most often motivated by mycological results, and de-escalation was the most frequent change. Regarding compliance to IC management guidelines, echinocandin was used for 182 (62.5_%) patients with PIC, and 287 (52.7_%) of those with SIC; central venous catheter was removed in 87 (54.3_%) of patients with candidaemia, and 43 of the remaining patients received echinocandin; and de-escalation was undertaken after 5_days of SAT in 142 patients, after 10_days in 13 patients. As 20.6_% of SIC were secondarily documented, 403/835 (48_%) patients had finally a proven IC. Candida albicans was the main pathogen (65.3_%), then Candida glabrata (15.9_%). The 28-day mortality rates were 40.0_% in candidaemia, 25.4_% in cIAI, and 26.7_% in deep-seated candidiasis. In the overall population of patients with proven IC, four independent prognostic factors were identified: immunosuppression (Odds Ratio (OR)_=_1.977: 1.03-3.794 95_% confidence interval (CI), p_=_0.04), age (OR_=_1.035; 1.017-1.053 95_% CI; p_46 on ICU admission (OR_=_2.894; 1.81-4.626 95_% CI; p_ConclusionWhen SAT is initiated in French ICUs, the IC is ultimately proven for 48_% of patients. Empiric SAT is initiated in severely ill ICU patients. The initial SAT is often adapted, with de-escalation to fluconazole when possible. Mortality rate remains high.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>