<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q112278479</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3389/FMICB.2022.800061</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Environment and Co-occurring Native Mussel Species, but Not Host Genetics, Impact the Microbiome of a Freshwater Invasive Species (&lt;i&gt;Corbicula fluminea&lt;/i&gt;)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chiarello, Marlène</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bucholz, Jamie R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McCauley, Mark</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vaughn, Stephanie N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hopper, Garrett W</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>González, Irene Sánchez</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Atkinson, Carla L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lozier, Jeffrey D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jackson, Colin R</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-04-04</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Corbicula fluminea</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Frontiers Media SA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;The Asian clam &lt;jats:italic&gt;Corbicula fluminea&lt;/jats:italic&gt; (Family: Cyneridae) has aggressively invaded freshwater habitats worldwide, resulting in dramatic ecological changes and declines of native bivalves such as freshwater mussels (Family: Unionidae), one of the most imperiled faunal groups. Despite increases in our knowledge of invasive &lt;jats:italic&gt;C. fluminea&lt;/jats:italic&gt; biology, little is known of how intrinsic and extrinsic factors, including co-occurring native species, influence its microbiome. We investigated the gut bacterial microbiome across genetically differentiated populations of &lt;jats:italic&gt;C. fluminea&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in the Tennessee and Mobile River Basins in the Southeastern United States and compared them to those of six co-occurring species of native freshwater mussels. The gut microbiome of &lt;jats:italic&gt;C. fluminea&lt;/jats:italic&gt; was diverse, differed with environmental conditions and varied spatially among rivers, but was unrelated to host genetic variation. Microbial source tracking suggested that the gut microbiome of &lt;jats:italic&gt;C. fluminea&lt;/jats:italic&gt; may be influenced by the presence of co-occurring native mussels. Inferred functions from 16S rRNA gene data using PICRUST2 predicted a high prevalence and diversity of degradation functions in the &lt;jats:italic&gt;C. fluminea&lt;/jats:italic&gt; microbiome, especially the degradation of carbohydrates and aromatic compounds. Such modularity and functional diversity of the microbiome of &lt;jats:italic&gt;C. fluminea&lt;/jats:italic&gt; may be an asset, allowing to acclimate to an extensive range of nutritional sources in invaded habitats, which could play a vital role in its invasive success.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>