<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q34202827</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3303875</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0033164</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Physical stress, not biotic interactions, preclude an invasive grass from establishing in forb-dominated salt marshes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>He, Qiang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cui, Baoshan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>An, Yuan</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012-03-14</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>salt marsh</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biotic interaction</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive grass</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>&lt;h4&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;Biological invasions have become the focus of considerable concern and ecological research, yet the relative importance of abiotic and biotic factors in controlling the invasibility of habitats to exotic species is not well understood. Spartina species are highly invasive plants in coastal wetlands; however, studies on the factors that control the success or failure of Spartina invasions across multiple habitat types are rare and inconclusive.&lt;h4&gt;Methodology and principal findings&lt;/h4&gt;We examined the roles of physical stress and plant interactions in mediating the establishment of the smooth cordgrass, Spartina alterniflora, in a variety of coastal habitats in northern China. Field transplant experiments showed that cordgrass can invade mudflats and low estuarine marshes with low salinity and frequent flooding, but cannot survive in salt marshes and high estuarine marshes with hypersaline soils and infrequent flooding. The dominant native plant Suaeda salsa had neither competitive nor facilitative effects on cordgrass. A common garden experiment revealed that cordgrass performed significantly better when flooded every other day than when flooded weekly. These results suggest that physical stress rather than plant interactions limits cordgrass invasions in northern China.&lt;h4&gt;Conclusions and significance&lt;/h4&gt;We conclude that Spartina invasions are likely to be constrained to tidal flats and low estuarine marshes in the Yellow River Delta. Due to harsh physical conditions, salt marshes and high estuarine marshes are unlikely to be invaded. These findings have implications for understanding Spartina invasions in northern China and on other coasts with similar biotic and abiotic environments.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>