<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q104467263</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q104467263</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1186/S13021-020-00165-0</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Colonization by native species enhances the carbon storage capacity of exotic mangrove monocultures</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>He, Ziying</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sun, Huaye</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peng, Yisheng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hu, Zhan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cao, Yingjie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Shing Yip</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-12-14</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>mangrove</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>carbon storage</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>native species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract
                Background
                The fast-growing introduced mangrove Sonneratia apetala is widely used for mangrove afforestation and reforestation in China. Some studies suggested that this exotic species outperforms native species in terms of carbon sequestration potential. This study tested the hypothesis that multi-species mangrove plantations might have higher carbon sequestration potential than S. apetala monocultures.
              
                Results
                Our field measurements at Hanjiang River Estuary (Guangdong province, China) showed that the carbon stock (46.0_±_3.0_Mg/ha) in S. apetala plantations where the native Kandelia obovata formed an understory shrub layer was slightly higher than that in S. apetala monocultures (36.6_±_1.3_Mg/ha). Moreover, the carbon stock in monospecific K. obovata stands (106.6_±_1.4_Mg/ha) was much larger than that of S. apetala monocultures.
              
                Conclusions
                Our results show that K. obovata monocultures may have a higher carbon accumulation rate than S. apetala monocultures. Planting K. obovata seedlings in existing S. apetala plantations may enhance the carbon sink associated with these plantations.
              </dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>