<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114749741</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114749741</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/APP12073217</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Metallic Study of the Invasive Species Cronius ruberAssessment of Toxic Risk</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thorne-Bazarra, Thabatha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lozano-Bilbao, Enrique</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Triay-Portella, Raül</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hardisson, Arturo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paz, Soraya</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rubio, Carmen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martín, Verónica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gutiérrez, Angel José</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-03-22</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Three toxic heavy metals (Cd, Pb, and Hg) were analyzed in the newly found invasive species in the Canary Islands, Cronius ruber. Its high growth rate and its widely varied diet are affecting the Canary marine ecosystem. The study was conducted using electrothermal vaporization atomic absorption spectrometry (GF-AAS) and cold-vapor atomic absorption spectrophotometry (CV-AAS). Significant differences were found in terms of the location and sex of the specimens, with the highest concentrations being found in areas with higher tourism activity and in the female specimens. On the other hand, the conclusion of the study is that human consumption of this species does not pose any toxic risk to public health, as the levels obtained in muscle tissue do not exceed the established limits for these metals. Therefore, its consumption and the fishing of this species can stop the proliferation of the same in the Canary coasts and thus not be harmful for the ecosystem.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>