<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q64095026</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6494794</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/PHYTOKEYS.121.33573</dc:identifier>
  <dc:link>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6494794</dc:link>
  <dc:title>Asclepiasspeciosa (Apocynaceae, Asclepiadoideae): a rare or unrecognized alien species in Europe?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gudžinskas, Zigmantas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petrulaitis, Lukas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Žalneravičius, Egidijus</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-04-24</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Studies on populations of &lt;jats:italic&gt;Asclepiassyriaca&lt;/jats:italic&gt; L. in Lithuania revealed the occurrence of a new alien plant species, the North American native &lt;jats:italic&gt;Asclepiasspeciosa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; Torr. (Apocynaceae, Asclepiadoideae), in southern parts of Lithuania – the first report of the latter species in Europe. Interestingly, a thorough analysis of herbarium specimens revealed that &lt;jats:italic&gt;A.speciosa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; had first been collected in Lithuania in 1962, but the specimen was misidentified at the time as &lt;jats:italic&gt;A.syriaca&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. The newly discovered population of &lt;jats:italic&gt;A.speciosa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; occupies mesic grasslands, tall-herb fringe communities and arable field habitats. Sexual reproduction of this species was not recorded; it spreads locally by means of vegetative reproduction. We present here an exhaustive analysis of morphological characteristics and differences between &lt;jats:italic&gt;A.speciosa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;A.syriaca&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and other species of the genus, as well as a key for identification of alien &lt;jats:italic&gt;Asclepias&lt;/jats:italic&gt; species in Europe. We predict that the effect of &lt;jats:italic&gt;A.speciosa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; on native habitats and communities, and its economic impact, are comparable to those of the highly invasive &lt;jats:italic&gt;A.syriaca&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. Although &lt;jats:italic&gt;A.speciosa&lt;/jats:italic&gt; currently occurs very rarely as an alien species in Europe, its existence in other regions of Europe is highly probable.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>