<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117804653</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117804653</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.83.97325</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>_Escape from the garden: spreading, effects and traits of a new risky invasive ornamental plant (Gaillardia aristata Pursh)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Süle, Gabriella</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Miholcsa, Zsombor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Molnár, Csaba</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kovács-Hostyánszki, Anikó</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fenesi, Annamária</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bauer, Norbert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Szigeti, Viktor</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-03-23</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Gaillardia aristata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive plant</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Ornamental plants constitute a major source of invasive species.Gaillardia aristata(great blanketflower) is planted worldwide and its escape has been reported in several European countries without ecological impact assessment on the invasive potential. As there is a markedly spreading population with invasive behaviour in Hungary, we aimed to reveal the distribution, impacts and traits ofG. aristata. We gathered occurrence data outside the gardens in Hungary, based on literature, unpublished observations by experts and our own records. We investigated the impacts of an extended population, where the species invaded sandy old-fields within a 25 km2area. Here, we compared the species richness, diversity, community composition and height of invaded and uninvaded vegetation. Furthermore, we evaluated the traits potentially associated with the invasiveness ofG. aristatain comparison with other herbaceous invasive species in the region. We found thatG. aristataoccurred mostly by casual escapes, but naturalised and invasive populations were also detected in considerable numbers.G. aristatausually appeared close to gardens and ruderal habitats, but also in semi-natural and natural grasslands and tended to spread better in sandy soils. We found lower plant species richness and Shannon diversity in the invaded sites and the invasion ofG. aristatasignificantly influenced the composition of the plant community. The trait analyses revealed that the invasive potential ofG. aristatais backed by a wide germination niche breadth, extremely long flowering period, small shoot-root ratio (large absorption and gripping surface), large seeds (longer persistence) and dispersal by epizoochory of grazing livestock (mostly by sheep), probably helping the species’ survival and spreading in the disturbed, species-poor, sandy, open habitats. These functional traits, as well as the ornamental utilisation, may act together with the aridisation of the climate and the changing land-use practices (e.g. abandoned, disturbed sites) in the success ofG. aristata. We raise awareness of the rapid transition ofG. aristatafrom ornamental plant to casual alien and then to invasive species in certain environmental conditions (i.e. sandy soils, species-poor communities, human disturbances), although it seems to be not a strong ecosystem transformer so far. Nonetheless, banning it from seed mixtures, developing eradication strategy and long-term monitoring of this species would be important to halt its spreading in time.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>