<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q114730600</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q114730600</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/W13212952</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Pilot Application of ‘Invasive Alien Species in Europe’ Smartphone App in the Danube Region</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Trichkova, Teodora</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paunović, Momir</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cogălniceanu, Dan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schade, Sven</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Todorov, Milcho</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tomov, Rumen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stănescu, Florina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Botev, Ivan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>López-Cañizares, Celia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gervasini, Eugenio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hubenov, Zdravko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ignatov, Kostadin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kenderov, Marian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marinković, Nikola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mitton, Irena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Preda, Cristina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spinelli, Fabiano Antonio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tsiamis, Konstantinos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cardoso, Ana Cristina</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-10-20</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>mobile app</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The present pilot study tested and validated the use of the ‘Invasive Alien Species in Europe’ smartphone app (IASapp) in the Lower Danube Region. The study was conducted in three stages: (1) Testing the effectiveness of the app in Bulgaria, Romania and Serbia by organizing information and field testing campaigns; (2) Improving and extending the functionality of the app and developing a list of the invasive alien species (IAS) of concern to the Danube River Basin (DRB); and (3) Testing the updated app during the Joint Danube Survey 4 campaign. Overall, 13 campaigns were carried out, during which seven aquatic IAS of EU concern and nine IAS relevant to the DRB were recorded. Currently, the developed new functionality of IASapp allows the recording of 64 IAS of DRB concern. The updated IASapp has an important role in increasing public awareness on IAS issues, as well as in enlarging the participation and output of citizen science in the IAS early detection, monitoring and reporting in the DRB. Therefore, the constant communication with existing stakeholder groups and establishment of new citizen science groups is crucial for increasing the effectiveness of using the IASapp in the Danube Region and tackling the IAS issues.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>