<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q36023285</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/SREP26316</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Predicting global invasion risks: a management tool to prevent future introductions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fletcher, D H</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gillingham, P K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Britton, J R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blanchet, S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gozlan, R E</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-05-20</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Predicting regions at risk from introductions of non-native species and the subsequent invasions is a fundamental aspect of horizon scanning activities that enable the development of more effective preventative actions and planning of management measures. The Asian cyprinid fish topmouth gudgeon &lt;jats:italic&gt;Pseudorasbora parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt; has proved highly invasive across Europe since its introduction in the 1960s. In addition to direct negative impacts on native fish populations, &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt; has potential for further damage through transmission of an emergent infectious disease, known to cause mortality in other species. To quantify its invasion risk, in regions where it has yet to be introduced, we trained 900 ecological niche models and constructed an Ensemble Model predicting suitability, then integrated a proxy for introduction likelihood. This revealed high potential for &lt;jats:italic&gt;P. parva&lt;/jats:italic&gt; to invade regions well beyond its current invasive range. These included areas in all modelled continents, with several hotspots of climatic suitability and risk of introduction. We believe that these methods are easily adapted for a variety of other invasive species and that such risk maps could be used by policy-makers and managers in hotspots to formulate increased surveillance and early-warning systems that aim to prevent introductions and subsequent invasions.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>