<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111153870</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/D13080353</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>How Do Biological and Functional Diversity Change in Invaded Tropical Marine Rocky Reef Communities?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pires-Teixeira, Larissa M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Neres-Lima, Vinicius</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Creed, Joel</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-08-02</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;Evidence so far shows that most alien species (AS) have negative impacts on native biodiversity and are changing biodiversity in almost all environments. Here, we study eight rocky shores at four sites containing reefs with invaded communities and other not-invaded (control) communities, to evaluate the effects of four marine invasive species on biological and functional diversity. We used the adjustment and selection approach of species abundance distribution models (SAD), taxonomic diversity indices and functional diversity indices based on hierarchical grouping matrices (FD—Functional Diversity). In addition to comparing invaded and not-invaded communities, we also performed the same analysis, but removed the invaders (AS removed) from the matrices. The geometric-series model was best adjusted to the majority of communities. The diversity indices suggest that the taxonomic diversity is lower in invaded communities, while the functional diversity indices suggest a change in the functional space of invaded and not-invaded communities, with a greater amount of functional space filled by species in the not-invaded communities. Taxonomic and functional diversity indices were successful in identifying processes that determine the biological diversity of invaded communities, as they seem to obey a pattern that reflects the reduced diversity of invaded communities.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>