<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q107460006</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/RETHINKINGECOLOGY.3.28516</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Sarracenia carnivorous plants cannot serve as efficient biological control of the invasive hornet Vespa velutina nigrithorax in Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wycke, Marie-Anne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perrocheau, Romaric</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Darrouzet, Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-11-12</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Vespa velutina</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vespa velutina nigrithorax</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;&lt;jats:italic&gt;Vespavelutinanigrithorax&lt;/jats:italic&gt;, an invasive species, a direct result of increased trade and climate change, is spreading rapidly in Europe and endangering entomofauna in general and more alarmingly honeybee (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Apismellifera&lt;/jats:italic&gt;) populations, and therefore their pollination services. All traps used now, to try to control this species, seem to be not efficient enough and non-selective. However, in the current context of massive disappearance of insects in general, it is urgent to find means of protection for the entomofauna. While no selective trapping is still occurring, we performed a pilot study to test a carnivorous plant as a potential biocontrol tool to trap &lt;jats:italic&gt;V.velutina&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. In our study, we analyzed the hornet-capturing ability of two &lt;jats:italic&gt;Sarracenia&lt;/jats:italic&gt; hybrids (&lt;jats:italic&gt;S.juthatipsoper&lt;/jats:italic&gt; and &lt;jats:italic&gt;S.evendine&lt;/jats:italic&gt;) on a 2-years period (2015 and 2016). Our results show that these plants trapped more dipterans than other taxa, and they do not attract many hornets. In such condition, both &lt;jats:italic&gt;Sarracenia&lt;/jats:italic&gt; hybrids cannot therefore be used in a mass trapping system, because they are not selective, and too few hornets are trapped. To maximize captures of &lt;jats:italic&gt;V.velutina&lt;/jats:italic&gt; while minimizing captures of non-target species, other systems need to be thus developed, as traps using hornet pheromone-based baiting.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>