<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q113692787</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113692787</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOTROPICAL.15.E55148</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>The bigger the better? Vigour of the exotic host plant Calotropis procera (Apocynaceae) affects herbivory</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fernandes, Geraldo Wilson</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Almeida-Cortez, Jarcilene Silva</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rodrigues-Menelau, Maria Fernanda Vicente</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arantes-Garcia, Lucas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Novais, Samuel M A</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-09-02</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Apocynaceae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Calotropis procera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>herbivory</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The Plant Vigour Hypothesis states that herbivores preferentially feed on the most vigorous plants within a plant population and/or the most vigorous modules within a plant. The goal of this study was to evaluate how shoot size (as an indication of module vigour) affects leaf herbivory in the host plant Calotropis procera, an exotic xerophyte perennial milkweed shrub. We predicted that the proportion of leaf area removed by insect herbivores would be positively related to shoot size. Eight patches were selected containing a varied number of C. procera individuals (5, 8, 29, 31, 55, 79, 116, and 172 individuals/patch) in the Brazilian seasonally dry vegetation (Caatinga), of which five individuals were randomly selected for further analysis. From each individual, three to six shoots were randomly selected, measured and had their leaves collected, for a total of approximately 200 leaves per patch. At the regional scale, the proportion of leaf area removed was positively affected by shoot size. In addition, this pattern was also found for the majority of the studied patches (29, 31, 55, 116, and 172 individuals/patch). Among the insect herbivores associated with C. procera, larvae of Danaus spp. (Lepidoptera: Nymphalidae) were commonly observed feeding on all patches. These herbivores present a specialized behaviour to circumvent the presence of latex in the host leaves. Although more vigorous plant modules should be better defended compared with the less vigorous modules, Danaus species were able to bypass host defences, and feed on healthy, rapidly growing and vigorous plant modules of C. procera, hence causing more damage to these modules.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>