<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q31166493</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q31166493</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0100423</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Competitive ability and fitness differences between two introduced populations of the invasive whitefly Bemisia tabaci Q in China</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fang, Yi-Wei</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, Ling-Yun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Hua-Li</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chu, Dong</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2014-06-19</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Silverleaf whitefly</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>competitive ability</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>BackgroundOur long-term field survey revealed that the Cardinium infection rate in Bemisia tabaci Q (also known as biotype Q) population was low in Shandong, China over the past few years. We hypothesize that (1) the Cardinium-infected (C+) B. tabaci Q population cannot efficiently compete with the Cardinium-uninfected (C-) B. tabaci Q population; (2) no reproductive isolation may have occurred between C+ and C-; and (3) the C- population has higher fitness than the C+ population.Methodology and resultsTo reveal the differences in competitive ability and fitness between the two introduced populations (C+ and C-), competition between C+ and C- was examined over several generations. Subsequently, the reproductive isolation between C+ and C- was studied by crossing C+ with C- individuals, and the fitnesses of C+ and C- populations were compared using a two-sex life table method. Our results demonstrate that the competitive ability of the C+ whiteflies was weaker than that of C-. There is that no reproductive isolation occurred between the two populations and the C- population had higher fitness than the C+ population.ConclusionThe competitive ability and fitness differences of two populations may explain why C- whitefly populations have been dominant during the past few years in Shandong, China. However, the potential role Cardinium plays in whitefly should be further explored.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>