<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q100406902</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q100406902</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0239762</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>No evidence for a dilution effect of the non-native snail, Potamopyrgus antipodarum, on native snails</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Larson, Michele D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Levri, Edward P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huzurbazar, Snehalata V</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Greenwood, Daniel J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wise, Kara L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krist, Amy C</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-10-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>New Zealand mud snail</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The dilution effect can occur by a range of mechanisms and results in reduced parasite prevalence in host taxa. In invaded ecosystems, the dilution effect can benefit native species if non-native species, acting as resistant or less competent hosts, reduce rates of parasitic infections in native species. In field experiments, we assessed whether manipulating biomass of the non-native snail, Potamopyrgus antipodarum, caused a dilution effect by reducing trematode infections in three taxa of native snails. In contrast to many studies showing resistant or less competent non-native hosts can "dilute" or reduce infection rates, we found no evidence for a dilution effect reducing infection rates of any of the native snails. We suggest that a dilution effect may not have occurred because most trematode taxa are highly host specific, and thus the trematode transmission stages did not recognize the invasive snail as a possible host. In this case, community composition appears to be important in influencing the dilution effect.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>