<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q113696805</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q113696805</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/ANI11020464</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Effect of Mixed Invasions of Hypoderma bovis and Ostertagia ostertagi in Cattle on Milk Yield and Contents in Polish Dairy Farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wiszniewska-Łaszczych, Agnieszka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wysok, Beata</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wojtacka, Joanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sołtysiuk, Marta</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-02-09</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Ostertagia ostertagi</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Wide distribution of ecto- and endoparasites in cattle is a serious problem in the sustainability of a farm, due to the negative impact on animals’ health and productivity. The aim of this study was to determine the presence of antibodies against Ostertagia and Hypoderma in udder milk samples and the comparison of milk yield and content of the basic components of milk in ELISA-positive and ELISA-negative cows. Milk samples were collected from 148 lactating cows from 3 herds. Antibody detection was performed using specific ELISAs for Ostertagia ostertagi and Hypoderma bovis. Milk yield and content of protein, fat, and dry matter were studied in samples from each individual cow 11 times per year at 4 week intervals. The extensiveness of dual parasitic invasions in individual herds, estimated on the basis of udder milk testing with the ELISA test, varied and amounted to 3.22%, 11.36%, and 4.76% in the three studied herds, respectively. No antibodies were found in 61.2%, 22.7%, and 57.1% of the milk samples from the cows in each herd. The milk yield of ELISA-positive cows was significantly lower in comparison to the efficiency of ELISA-negative cows and amounted to 294 kg and even to 3672 kg of milk per year, per cow. No significant differences were found between the fat and protein contents of milk between ELISA-positive and -negative cows for both parasites.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>