<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q97415616</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q97415616</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.mdpi.com/1422-0067/21/13/4729</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/IJMS21134729</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Hotspots in Plasmodium and RBC Receptor-Ligand Interactions: Key Pieces for Inhibiting Malarial Parasite Invasion</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Patarroyo, Manuel-Alfonso</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Patarroyo, Manuel Alfonso</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Molina-Franky, Jessica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Molina-Franky, Jessica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gómez, Marcela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arevalo-Pinzon, Gabriela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arévalo-Pinzón, Gabriela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Patarroyo, Manuel Elkin</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-07-02</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>geographic parasite invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Protein-protein interactions (IPP) play an essential role in practically all biological processes, including those related to microorganism invasion of their host cells. It has been found that a broad repertoire of receptor-ligand interactions takes place in the binding interphase with host cells in malaria, these being vital interactions for successful parasite invasion. Several trials have been conducted for elucidating the molecular interface of interactions between some Plasmodium falciparum and Plasmodium vivax antigens with receptors on erythrocytes and/or reticulocytes. Structural information concerning these complexes is available; however, deeper analysis is required for correlating structural, functional (binding, invasion, and inhibition), and polymorphism data for elucidating new interaction hotspots to which malaria control methods can be directed. This review describes and discusses recent structural and functional details regarding three relevant interactions during erythrocyte invasion: Duffy-binding protein 1 (DBP1)–Duffy antigen receptor for chemokines (DARC); reticulocyte-binding protein homolog 5 (PfRh5)-basigin, and erythrocyte binding antigen 175 (EBA175)-glycophorin A (GPA).</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>