<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q46127999</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.2166/WST.2014.394</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Evaluation of approaches to quantify total residual oxidants in ballast water management systems employing chlorine for disinfection.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zimmer-Faust, Amity G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ambrose, Richard F</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamburri, Mario N</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2014-01-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>disinfection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>water management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>sailing ballast</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>IWA Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;With the maturation and certification of several ballast water management systems that employ chlorine as biocide to prevent the spread of invasive species, there is a clear need for accurate and reliable total residual oxidants (TRO) technology to monitor treatment dose and assure the environmental safety of treated water discharged from ships. In this study, instruments used to measure TRO in wastewater and drinking water applications were evaluated for their performance in scenarios mimicking a ballast water treatment application (e.g., diverse hold times, temperatures, and salinities). Parameters chosen for testing these technologies in the past do not reflect conditions expected during ballast water treatment. Salinity, temperature, and oxidant concentration all influenced the response of amperometric sensors. Oxidation reduction potential (ORP) sensors performed more consistently than amperometric sensors under different conditions but it may be difficult to correlate ORP and TRO measurements for the multitude of biogeochemical conditions found naturally in ballast water. N,N-diethyl-p-phenylenediamine (DPD) analyzers and amperometric sensors were also tested under intermittent sampling conditions mimicking a ballasting scenario, with cyclical dosage and discharge operations. When sampling was intermittent, amperometric sensors required excessive response and conditioning times, whereas DPD analyzers provided reasonable estimates of TRO under the ballasting scenario.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>