<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q92208290</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/JEE/TOZ046</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Diaphorina citri (Hemiptera: Psylloidea) in China: Two Invasion Routes and Three Transmission Paths</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Cong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xiong, Xiao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, Xian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zou, Zhiwen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xin, Tianrong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Jing</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xia, Bin</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-05-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://academic.oup.com/journals/pages/open_access/funder_policies/chorus/standard_publication_model</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Diaphorina citri</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hemiptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion pathway</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Diaphorina citri Kuwayama (Hemiptera: Liviidae) is one of the most common pests impacting citrus orchards in southern China. Samples of D. citri were collected in southern China in order to systematically explore the genetic architecture of the species. Mitochondrial cytochrome b (Cytb) and cytochrome coxidase subunit I (COI) were amplified by polymerase chain reaction (PCR) which allowed highlighting low haplotype and nucleotide diversities among the population. Two clades could be observed in the haplotype network. Moreover, Bayesian and maximum parsimony phylogenetic trees were constructed based on the sequences of Cytb and COI. Here, we report on the significant genetic variation of the species when comparing southwestern China with other regions of southern China (southern and southeastern). This analysis also suggested that the genetic structure of D. citri in China originates may from long-term climate fluctuations concomitant with recent disturbances resulting from human activity. Combined with previous data, the present work indicates that D. citri potentially entered China through two distinct invasion routes and spread within the country via three transmission paths.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>