<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q37096614</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q37096614</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/SREP30078</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Deadly intentions: na誰ve introduced foxes show rapid attraction to odour cues of an unfamiliar native prey</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bytheway, Jenna P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Price, Catherine J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Banks, Peter B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016-07-15</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>predation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>native prey</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Introduced predators have caused declines and extinctions of native species worldwide, seemingly able to find and hunt new, unfamiliar prey from the time of their introduction. Yet, just as native species are often na誰ve to introduced predators, in theory, introduced predators should initially be na誰ve in their response to novel native prey. Here we examine the response of free-living introduced red foxes (Vulpes vulpes) to their first encounter with the odour cues of a novel native prey, the long-nosed bandicoot (Perameles nasuta). Despite no experience with bandicoots at the study site, foxes were significantly more interested in bandicoot odour compared to untreated controls and to a co-evolved prey, the black rat (Rattus rattus). So what gives introduced predators a novelty advantage over native prey? Such neophilia towards novel potential food sources carries little costs, however na誰ve native prey often lack analogous neophobic responses towards novel predators, possibly because predator avoidance is so costly. We propose that this nexus between the costs and benefits of responding to novel information is different for alien predators and native prey, giving alien predators a novelty advantage over native prey. This may explain why some introduced predators have rapid and devastating impacts on native fauna.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>