<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q92650413</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q92650413</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6682666</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3389/FMICB.2019.01769</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Lipoprotein SPD_1609 of Streptococcus pneumoniae Promotes Adherence and Invasion to Epithelial Cells Contributing to Bacterial Virulence</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Yang, Xiao-Yan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li, Nan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xu, Jing-Yu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sun, Xuesong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He, Qing-Yu</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2019-07-30</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Streptococcus pneumoniae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Frontiers Media SA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>In most bacteria, iron plays a vital role in pathogenesis processes. To support survival and infection, Streptococcus pneumoniae has evolved three ABC transporters, PiaABC, PiuABC, and PitABC. Moreover, indirect evidence supports that operon 804 may be a novel ABC transporter in S. pneumoniae. We have recently described the identification of lipoprotein SPD_1609 in operon 804; however, whether the SPD_1609 protein affects the virulence of S. pneumoniae has not yet been studied. In the present work, alignment analysis showed that lipoprotein SPD_1609 is conserved in a variety of gram-positive bacteria, and deletion of the spd_1609 gene led to a reduction in adherence and invasion of S. pneumoniae to host cells. RT-qPCR assays indicated that deletion of the spd_1609 gene resulted in decreased expression of genes involved in colonization. Furthermore, decreased virulence in a mouse bacteremia infection model caused by the loss of the lipoprotein encoded by spd_1609 was also demonstrated. Overall, these data provide insights into the functional role of lipoprotein SPD_1609 in pneumococcal pathogenesis, suggesting its possibility to be developed as a novel S. pneumoniae vaccine candidate.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>