<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q121620125</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q121620125</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1590/S2179-975X4222</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>A global review on invasive traits of macrophytes and their link to invasion success</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bora, Leticia Siman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padial, André Andrian</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-07-02</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q109467185</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion success</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive trait</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>macrophyte</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>FapUNIFESP (SciELO)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract:  Aim Biological invasions by exotic macrophytes represent one of the main reasons for biodiversity and ecosystem changes in aquatic ecosystems. The reasons for their ability to succeed in new environments have been of ecological interest in the last years. We made a global review, aiming to describe functional traits related with invasiveness of macrophytes.  Methods Our search was performed using keywords regarding invasive macrophytes and functional traits. We related the group traits of invasive species with their probability of species invasion success in new localities (invasiveness). We also performed a nestedness analysis that helped us to see which species possessed the higher number of traits related to invasiveness, as well as which traits were more common among the invasive species.  Results Traits most often related to invasiveness were those indicating growth (94.5%) and reproduction (90.1%). Nearly 70.4% of invasive macrophytes traits were related with the probability of invasion success. Invasive species had a higher number of morphological and biotic interaction traits related with invasiveness than native species. Our nestedness analysis indicated a low degree of nestedness, but showed us that Egeria densa, Elodea canadensis and Elodea nutalli were the species with a wider range of environmental tolerances, explaining their invasibility across ecosystems.  Conclusions We summarized and complement existing reviews on the functional traits related to invasion success of macrophytes. We believe this review contributed to the identification of the most common set of traits related with invasiveness, helping to speculate on successful invaders in the future.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>