<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q36333592</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q36333592</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3476562</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1155/2012/131328</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Genetic and antigenic analysis of invasive serogroup C Neisseria meningitidis in Canada: A decrease in the electrophoretic type (ET)-15 clonal type and an increase in the proportion of isolates belonging to the ET-37 (but not ET-15) clonal type duri</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zhou, Jianwei</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jamieson, Frances</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dolman, Sharon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hoang, Linda Mn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rawte, Prasad</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tsang, Raymond Sw</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012-01-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Neisseria meningitidis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>BACKGROUND: Serogroup C meningococcal disease has been endemic in Canada since the early 1990s, with periods of hyperendemic disease documented in the past two decades. The present study characterized invasive serogroup C meningococci in Canada during the period from 2002 to 2009.METHODS: Serogroup C meningococci were serotyped using monoclonal antibodies. Their clonal types were identified by either multilocus enzyme electrophoresis or multilocus sequence typing.RESULTS: The number of invasive serogroup CNeisseria meningitidisisolates received at the National Microbiology Laboratory (Winnipeg, Manitoba) for characterization has dropped from a high of 173 isolates in 2001 to just 17 in 2009, possibly related to the introduction of the serogroup C meningococcal conjugate vaccine. Before 2006, 80% to 95% of all invasive serogroup C meningococci belonged to the electrophoreic type (ET)-15 clonal type, and the ET-37 (but not ET-15) type only accounted for up to 5% of all isolates. However, beginning in 2006, the percentage of the ET-15 clonal type decreased while the ET-37 (but not ET-15) type increased from 27% in 2006 to 52% in 2009. The percentage of invasive serogroup C isolates not belonging to either ET-15 or ET-37 also increased. Most ET-15 isolates expressed the antigenic formula of C:2a:P1.7,1 or C:2a:P1.5. In contrast, the ET-37 (but not ET-15) isolates mostly expressed the antigens of C:2a:P1.5,2 or C:2a:P1.2.CONCLUSION: A shift in the antigenic and clonal type of invasive serogroup C meningococi was noted. This finding suggests vigilance in the surveillance of meningoccocal disease is warranted.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>