<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117046753</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117046753</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/LAND12030642</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ascertaining the Knowledge of the General Public and Stakeholders in the Forestry Sector to Invasive Alien Species—A Pan-European Study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bălăcenoiu, Flavius</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Japelj, Anže</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bernardinelli, Iris</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Castagneyrol, Bastien</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Csóka, György</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Glavendekic, Milka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hoch, Gernot</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hrasovec, Boris</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ostoić, Silvija Krajter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paulin, Marton</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Williams, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Witters, Johan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Groot, Maarten</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-03-08</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Against the background of the phenomenon of globalisation, which has increasingly intensified in recent decades, invasive alien species (IAS) have led to biological invasions that have resulted in multiple negative effects on economies, human health, and especially on the environment. In order to control invasive alien species, preventive actions are considered the most effective methods. In this context, society can actively participate in the process of early detection and preventing the spread of these organisms, but there is a need to raise public awareness. In order for this process to take place in the most efficient way, it is necessary to initially evaluate the knowledge of the general public to IAS. Through a questionnaire that was circulated in ten European countries and had over two thousand respondents, this study aimed to investigate the level of knowledge of some stakeholders in the forestry sector regarding IAS. The results showed that a vast majority of respondents who participated in the study had heard about IAS and provided a correct definition of these organisms. Most of the respondents in this study heard for the first time about IAS from school, the Internet, or journal articles. Data analysis also showed that stakeholders in the forestry sector (foresters, forest owners, and members of environmental NGOs) were more likely than the other respondents to be aware of the impact of IAS. The results of this study offer an insight to researchers and decision makers assessing the differences of opinion regarding invasive alien species, and the necessary steps that could be adopted in the process of raising awareness in society.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>