<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q108887626</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q108887626</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1002/ECE3.8028</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Long‐term development of species richness in a central European beech ( Fagus sylvatica ) forest affected by windthrow—Support for the intermediate disturbance hypothesis?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Meyer, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidt, Marcus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Feldmann, Eike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Willig, Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larkin, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-08-16</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Intermediate Disturbance Hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>wikidata.org/entity/Q9003976</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:Intermediate Disturbance Hypothesis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hypothesis:wikidata.org/entity/Q9003976</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>species richness</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fagus sylvatica</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>disturbance-mediated invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>forest invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractOn the basis of long‐term surveys of permanent plots and traps, we examined the communities of saproxylic beetles, fungi, herbs, and trees on an untreated 22_ha large beech forest windthrow and asked whether the results lend support to the intermediate disturbance hypothesis (IDH). We studied species richness and the similarity of community composition. Additionally, we grouped species by their frequency trend over time to successional model types to examine whether, corresponding to the IDH, the diversity of these groups explained peak richness at intermediate intervals after the disturbance. In line with the IDH, species richness showed a hump‐backed temporal course for alpha and gamma diversity. We found evidence for a linear succession directly after the disturbance. This, however, did not continue, and in all species groups, a partial recovery of the initial community was observed. In the case of fungi, herbs, and trees, but not for saproxylic beetles, alpha diversity was driven by the diversity of the successional model types. Our results underline that the mechanisms driving species richness after disturbances are more complex than the IDH suggests and that these mechanisms vary with species group. We assumed that, besides competition, legacy effects, facilitation, habitat heterogeneity, and random saturation of the species pool are important. In case of trees and herbs, we found indications for strong legacy and competition effects. For fungi and beetles, substrate heterogeneity and microclimate were assumed to be important. We concluded that disturbances contribute to increasing species richness not only by reducing the effectiveness of competitors but also by increasing the amount and diversity of resources, as well as their rate of change over time.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>