<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q37743478</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q37743478</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/NCOMMS14790</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Symbiosis limits establishment of legumes outside their native range at a global scale</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Simonsen, Anna K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dinnage, Russell</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barrett, Luke G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prober, Suzanne Mary</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thrall, Peter H</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-04-07</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>native range</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>global scale</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractMicrobial symbiosis is integral to plant growth and reproduction, but its contribution to global patterns of plant distribution is unknown. Legumes (Fabaceae) are a diverse and widely distributed plant family largely dependent on symbiosis with nitrogen-fixing rhizobia, which are acquired from soil after germination. This dependency is predicted to limit establishment in new geographic areas, owing to a disruption of compatible host-symbiont associations. Here we compare non-native establishment patterns of symbiotic and non-symbiotic legumes across over 3,500 species, covering multiple independent gains and losses of rhizobial symbiosis. We find that symbiotic legume species have spread to fewer non-native regions compared to non-symbiotic legumes, providing strong support for the hypothesis that lack of suitable symbionts or environmental conditions required for effective nitrogen-fixation are driving these global introduction patterns. These results highlight the importance of mutualisms in predicting non-native species establishment and the potential impacts of microbial biogeography on global plant distributions.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>