<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q33788211</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q33788211</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5467846</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0178805</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Socio-economic drivers of specialist anglers targeting the non-native European catfish (Silurus glanis) in the UK</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rees, E M Ann</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Edmonds-Brown, V Ronni</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alam, Fasihul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wright, Ros M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Britton, J Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Davies, Gareth D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cowx, Ian G</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>socioeconomics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Wels catfish</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ecological economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Information about the socioeconomic drivers of Silurus glanis anglers in the UK were collected using questionnaires from a cross section of mixed cyprinid fisheries to elucidate human dimensions in angling and non-native fisheries management. Respondents were predominantly male (95%), 30-40 years of age with £500 per annum. The proportion of time spent angling for S. glanis was significantly related to angler motivations; fish size, challenge in catch, tranquil natural surroundings, escape from daily stress and to be alone were considered important drivers of increased time spent angling. Overall, poor awareness of: the risks and adverse ecological impacts associated with introduced S. glanis, non-native fisheries legislation, problems in use of unlimited ground bait and high fish stocking rates in angling lakes were evident, possibly related to inadequate training and information provided by angling organisations to anglers, as many stated that they were insufficiently informed.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>