<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q91508520</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0231009</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Variability of the mitochondrial CO1 gene in native and invasive populations of Harmonia axyridis Pall. comparative analysis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Blekhman, Alla</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Goryacheva, Irina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schepetov, Dimitry</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zakharov, Ilia</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-04-02</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Harmonia axyridis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Public Library of Science (PLoS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Our study is focused on original and publicly accessible data on the intraspecific variability of the barcoding DNA fragment in ladybirds Harmonia axyridis Pall analysis. The complete dataset consists of 39 haplotypes, 16 of which we identified for the first time. The intra-population and geographical variability of the barcoding fragment was studied for seven populations of the western and eastern groups of the native range and in six invasive populations, in which 25 of the 39 haplotypes are found. Population structure inferred on base of molecular variability and haplotype frequencies showed a high level of differences between the eastern and western groups of native populations and confirm the hypothesis of the origin of all invasive populations from native populations of the eastern group. A comparative analysis of molecular variation indices testifies to various evolutionary scenarios of the formation of the western and eastern groups of native populations and confirms the hypothesis of the microevolutionary history of the species, previously suggested in morphological character based studies of the geographical variability of H. axyridis. A significant decrease in the molecular diversity of invasive populations confirms the hypothesis of a random nature of the primary invasion of this species in North America.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>