<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110829137</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/SU131910558</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Prediction Models for Evaluating the Uptake of Heavy Metals by the Invasive Grass Vossia cuspidata (Roxb.) Griff. in the River Nile, Egypt: A Biomonitoring Approach</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Farahat, Emad A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mahmoud, Waleed F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Awad, Hossam E. A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Farrag, Hussein F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arshad, Muhammad</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eid, Ebrahem M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fahmy, Gamal M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-09-23</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive grass</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:p&gt;This study aimed to develop new prediction models that include sediment properties (pH, organic matter, and silt and clay concentrations) for estimating the potential uptake of heavy metals (HMs) by the invasive grass Vossia cuspidata. Plant and sediment samples were collected from the microsites that represent the natural distribution of the species in two Nile islands in Cairo, Egypt. The results show that the root was the main accumulating organ for the analyzed HMs (Fe, Mn, Zn, Cu, Ni, and Pb). The mean concentrations of Fe and Mn and the maximum concentrations of Cu, Ni, and Pb were phytotoxic. The values of the bioconcentration factor were &gt;1, while the translocation factor was &gt;1 for Zn and Cu in rhizome and stem, Mn in leaf, and Ni and Pb in stem and leaf. There were no significant differences between the measured and the predicted HM concentrations in all organs of the species. This indicates the excellent robustness of the developed regression models. Sixteen equations (out of 24) had high R2 values. Thus, V. cuspidata could be considered a biomonitor for HM pollution, and the developed equations will benefit the prediction of HM uptake by the species in the River Nile ecosystem.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>