<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111323819</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111323819</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/BIOLOGY10111169</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Assessment of the Spatial Invasion Risk of Intentionally Introduced Alien Plant Species (IIAPS) under Environmental Change in South Korea</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Adhikari, Pradeep</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Yong-Ho</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Park, Yong-Soon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hong, Sun-Hee</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-11-12</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>ecological invasion risk</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>environmental change</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion risk analysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>South Korea</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Predicting the regions at risk of invasion from IIAPS is an integral horizon-scanning activity that plays a crucial role in preventing, controlling, and eradicating invasive species. Here, we quantify the spatial distribution area and invasion risk of IIAPS using a species distribution model under different levels of environmental change in South Korea. From the model predictions, the current average spatial extent of the 10 IIAPS is 33,948 km2, and the individual spatial extents are estimated to change by −7% to 150% by 2050 and by −9% to 156% by 2070. The spatial invasion risk assessment shows that, currently, moderate-to-high invasion risk is limited to coastal areas and densely populated metropolitan cities (e.g., Seoul, Busan, and Gwangju), but that the area with this level of risk is expected to spread toward the central and northern regions of the country in the future, covering 86.21% of the total area of the country by 2070. These results demonstrate that the risk of invasion by IIAPS is estimated to enlarge across the whole country under future environmental changes. The modeling system provided in this study may contribute to the initial control and strategic management of IIAPS to maintain the dynamic ecosystems of South Korea.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>