<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q58918353</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q58918353</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1155/2013/573808</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Establishment of Native Grasses with Biosolids on Abandoned Croplands in Chihuahua, Mexico</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jurado-Guerra, Pedro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sierra-Tristán, J. Santos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lara-Macias, Carlos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saucedo-Teran, Ruben</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morales-Nieto, Carlos</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>native grass</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The objective of the work was to evaluate establishment and forage production of native grasses with application of biosolids, a byproduct of waste-water treatment, at an abandoned field, in Ejido Nuevo Delicias, Chihuahua, Mexico. Four biosolids rates from 0 (control) to 30_dry_Mg_ha−1and two methods of application, surface applied (BioSur) and soil incorporated (BioInc), were evaluated. Seedbed preparation included plowing and harrowing before rainfall. Field plots of 5 × 5_m were manually sown with a mix of blue grama (Bouteloua gracilis) (50%) and green sprangletop (Leptochloa dubia) (50%) in early August 2005. Experimental design was a randomized block with a split plot arrangement. Grass density, height, and forage production were estimated for three years. Data were analyzed with mixed linear models and repeated measures. Green sprangletop density increased under all biosolids rates regardless of method of application, while blue grama density slightly decreased. Biosolids were more beneficial for green sprangletop height than for blue grama height. Blue grama forage production slightly increased, while green sprangletop forage production increased the most at 10_Mg_ha−1biosolids rate under BioSur method. It was concluded that BioSur application at 10 and 20_Mg_ha−1rates had positive effects on the establishment and forage production of native grasses, especially green sprangletop.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>