<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117046317</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117046317</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/AGRONOMY12123214</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Arbuscular Mycorrhiza Symbiosis as a Factor of Asteraceae Species Invasion</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sokornova, Sofia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Malygin, Daniil</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Terentev, Anton</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dolzhenko, Viktor</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-12-18</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Invasive weeds of the Asteraceae family are widespread in the world. Arbuscular mycorrhiza (AM) is one of the main factors contributing to the successful distribution of these species that is most clearly manifested in the subfamily Asteroideae. The benefits of plant-AMF symbiosis are most significant under unfavorable biotic and abiotic conditions. The specificity of the relationship between arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) communities and plants and is determined at the presymbiotic stage. The AMF colonization level is higher in invasive species than in native ones, but AMF communities associated with Asteraceae invasive species are less diverse. AMF communities of Asteraceae invaders often include fewer common species (e.g., species belonging to Diversisporales). Invaders also reduce native AMF species richness in new areas. Arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi can form mycorrhizal networks that allow the redistribution of nutrients in plant communities. The most significant influence of AMF associated with invasive Asteraceae plants is seen in the formation of soil and rhizosphere microbiota, including the suppression of beneficial soil bacteria and fungi. This review could be useful in the development of practical recommendations for the use of AMF-based fertilizers.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>