<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110758971</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1080/23802359.2021.1984327</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Complete chloroplast genome of (Ceramiales, Rhodophyta), a recently described cryptogenic species with invasive traits from Papahānaumokuākea Marine National Monument, Hawai'i</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>O Paiano, Monica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kosaki, Randall K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Williams, Taylor M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spalding, Heather L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sherwood, Alison R</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aquatic invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive trait</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Informa UK Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The complete chloroplast genome of &lt;i&gt;Chondria tumulosa&lt;/i&gt;, a red alga from Manawai (Pearl and Hermes Atoll), Hawai'i, was determined and analyzed using next-generation sequencing and &lt;i&gt;de novo&lt;/i&gt; assembly approaches. The chloroplast genome sequence of &lt;i&gt;C. tumulosa&lt;/i&gt; was 172,617 bp and contained 231 genes, consisting of 197 protein-coding genes, 29 transfer RNA genes, three ribosomal RNA genes, one transfer-messenger RNA gene, one non-coding RNA gene, and one intron inserted into the &lt;i&gt;trnM&lt;/i&gt; gene. The number of genes and genome structure was largely similar to other members of the family Rhodomelaceae. The phylogenomic analysis of 32 complete cpDNA from the red algal order Ceramiales showed that &lt;i&gt;C. tumulosa&lt;/i&gt; is a distinct species within the Chondrieae tribe, and is a diverging early relative to the other three available &lt;i&gt;Chondria&lt;/i&gt; chloroplast genomes.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>