<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q108517659</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q108517659</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/PATHOGENS10060740</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invaders as Diluents of the Cercarial Dermatitis Etiological Agent</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stanicka, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Migdalski, ukasz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Szopieray, Katarzyna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cichy, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jermacz, ukasz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lombardo, Paola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>bikowska, Elbieta</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-06-11</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Trichobilharzia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Alien Species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>dilution effect</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>cercarial dermatitis</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Research on alien and invasive species focuses on the direct effects of invasion on native ecosystems, and the possible positive effects of their presence are most often overlooked. Our aim was to check the suitability of selected alien species (the snail Physa acuta, the bivalve Dreissena polymorpha, and the gammarid Dikerogammarus villosus) as diluents for infectious bird schistosome cercariaethe etiological factor of swimmer’s itch. It has been hypothesized that alien species with different feeding habits (scrapers, filterers and predators) that cohabit the aquatic environment with intermediate hosts of the schistosomatid trematodes are capable of feeding on their free-swimming stagescercariae. In the laboratory conditions used, all experimental animals diluted the cercariae of bird schistosome. The most effective diluents were P. acuta and D. villosus. However, a wide discrepancy in the dilution of the cercariae between replicates was found for gammarids. The obtained results confirm the hypothesis that increased biodiversity, even when alien species are involved, creates the dilution effect of the free-living stages of parasites. Determining the best diluent for bird schistosome cercariae could greatly assist in the development of current bathing areas protection measures against swimmer’s itch.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>