<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q36170822</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q36170822</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2094953</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1155/2003/219027</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Invasive Streptococcus pneumoniae infection causing hemolytic uremic syndrome in children: Two recent cases</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vanderkooi, Otto G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kellner, James D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wade, Andrew W</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jadavji, Tajdin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Midgley, Julian P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Louie, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tyrell, Gregory J</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2003-11-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Streptococcus pneumoniae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Hindawi Limited</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>INTRODUCTION:Streptococcus pneumoniaeis an uncommon cause of hemolytic uremic syndrome (HUS) with a unique pathophysiology that differs from Shiga toxin-related HUS.METHODS: Case descriptions for each patient are provided. Each strain ofS pneumoniaewas subjected to a pulsed-field gel electrophoresis (PFGE) analysis, Shiga toxin assay and polymerase chain reaction to detect Shiga toxin genes. A review of the current literature was conducted.CASE PRESENTATIONS: Two patients withS pneumoniae-related HUS that presented to the Alberta Children's Hospital, Calgary, Alberta, within four weeks of each other in 2001 are described. Both presented with pneumonia and empyema with associated HUS. Both patients required dialysis, one patient for 10 days and the other for 18 days. Neither patient demonstrated evidence of Shiga toxin-related disease.S pneumoniaeisolated from blood or pleural fluid was penicillin susceptible. One isolate was serotype 3 and the other was serotype 14. The two strains had different PFGE patterns. Both patients recovered well with no persistent renal dysfunction.CONCLUSIONS:S pneumoniaecontinues to be an uncommon but important cause of HUS. Most cases can be confirmed or at least considered probable without performing a renal biopsy.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>