<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q66811161</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q66811161</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.16418/J.ISSN.1000-3045.2016.10.010</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Ecological Consequences and Management of Biological Invasions in Chinese Coastal Zone</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>黎静</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>鞠瑞亭</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>吴纪华</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>李博</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2016</dc:date>
  <dc:language>zh</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biological invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>coastal invasion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>coast</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>coastal ecology</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Ecosystem in the coastal zone provides vital ecosystem services for human society, but also is one of the most vulnerable ecosystems to alien species invasions. There are at least 196 alien invasive species in Chinese coastal zone, accounting for more than 25% of the total number of invasive species in China. Intentional introductions and unintentional transport by vessels and ballast water are the main ways of alien species to invade Chinese coastal zone. Biological invasions in the coastal zone not only lead to many serious ecological consequences such as competition with native species, loss of biodiversity, and degradation of ecosystem services, but also cause considerable damage to local aquaculture, fishery, agriculture, and human health. To effectively manage biological invasions in Chinese coastal zone, we suggest several issues that need to be addressed in the future, i.e., conducting comprehensive inventories of alien species, performing risk analyses of important alien species and planned introductions, systematically studying major invasive species for control purpose, and making regulations and policies regarding invasive species and their vectors such as ballast water and vessels.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>