<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110809349</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110809349</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/JISESA/IEAB062</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Comparison of Yellow and Blue Sticky Cards for Detection and Monitoring Parasitoid Wasps of the Invasive Halyomorpha halys (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Holthouse, Mark Cody</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spears, Lori R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alston, Diane G</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-09-01</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>brown marmorated stink bug</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hemiptera</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pentatomidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Abstract
               The invasive Halyomorpha halys (Stål) is a significant agricultural and urban nuisance pest in many parts of the world. In North America, biological control of H. halys by parasitoid wasps in the families Scelionidae and Eupelmidae has shown promise. An effective technique for detection and monitoring native and exotic parasitoids is the deployment of yellow sticky cards; however, yellow cards also attract nontarget arthropods, reducing efficiency and accuracy of parasitoid screening. This study sought to identify an alternative yet effective trapping technique by comparing the number of target parasitoid wasps [Anastatus spp. Motschulsky (Hymenoptera: Eupelmidae), Telenomus spp. Haliday (Hymenoptera: Scelionidae), and Trissolcus spp. Ashmead (Hymenoptera: Scelionidae)] and arthropod bycatch on yellow and blue sticky cards deployed in urban, orchard, and vegetable landscapes in northern Utah from late May to early October in 2019 and 2020. Yellow sticky cards captured 54–72% more target parasitoids than blue cards from June through August in all three landscape types in both years; however, a positive correlation in parasitoid capture indicated blue cards detect target parasitoids, just in fewer numbers. Both card colors detected adventive Trissolcus japonicus (Ashmead) (Hymenoptera: Scelionidae) in initial findings of 2019, and in expanded locations of 2020. Furthermore, blue cards captured 31–48% less Diptera and nontarget Hymenoptera than yellow cards in both years across all three landscapes, translating to reduced card processing time and impacts to beneficial insect populations. Our results suggest that blue vs yellow sticky cards offer an alternative monitoring technique to survey for H. halys parasitoids.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>