<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117042858</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117042858</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1002/PS.7379</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Quantification of flight times of aerial treatments targeting invasive species: the interplay of helicopter or drone with bait‐delivery systems, flight speed and bait form</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hoffmann, Benjamin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tessmann, Adam</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Quinn, Greg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lawton, Faye</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-03-08</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q113019190</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion management</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Wiley</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractBACKGROUNDAerial treatments for invasive species management are now common, but we are unaware of any work published in the scientific literature quantifying how the interplay of numerous factors affects flight time and therefore operational costs. Here, we analyse aerial treatment data collected from two ant‐eradication programmes, quantifying how the relationships between flight time and area are influenced by numerous aircraft/delivery system/bait/flight speed combinations.RESULTSFor bait dispersal by helicopters, and when swath widths are equivalent, side‐mounted Isolair was significantly more efficient than the simultaneous use of two underslung buckets, and use of two buckets was slightly but not significantly more efficient than one bucket. In this scenario, delivery by Isolair was, on average, 39.8% and 31.5% more efficient than the use of one or two buckets, respectively. However, when the swath width used with Isolair was halved to 10_m and flight speed was increased slightly, flight time was significantly greater compared to the other configurations. For bait dispersed by drone, flights conducted using an upgraded Flight Management System (FMS) and greater flight speed but smaller swath width were significantly more efficient than flights using the older FMS and lower flight speed. Over 10 and 50_ha the helicopter was 2.87 and 4.82 times more time efficient than the drone.CONCLUSIONWe encourage practitioners to publish data from their aerial treatments, and to try new methods, to accelerate improvements in efficiency and reduce the costs of aerial treatments. © 2023 The Authors. Pest Management Science published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Society of Chemical Industry.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>