<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111741726</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-10047-9.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-022-10047-9</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Integrative taxonomy reveals cryptic diversity in North American Lasius ants, and an overlooked introduced species</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schär, Sämi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Talavera, Gerard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rana, Jignasha D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Espadaler, Xavier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cover, Stefan P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>O. Shattuck, Steven</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vila, Roger</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2022-04-08</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Biological invasions are a grave threat to ecosystems. The black garden ant (&lt;jats:italic&gt;Lasius&lt;/jats:italic&gt;&lt;jats:italic&gt;niger&lt;/jats:italic&gt;) is a pest species in Europe. Current literature states that &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. niger&lt;/jats:italic&gt; occupies a disjunct native distribution in the Holarctic, however, based on recent work, we re-evaluate this distribution. The native range of &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. niger&lt;/jats:italic&gt; is reconsidered based on phylogenetic relationships (nine mitochondrial and nuclear markers, 5670 bp), DNA-barcoding (98 Holarctic specimens), morphometry (88 Holarctic specimens, 19 different measurements) and subjective assessment of phenotype. The potential spread of this species is estimated using ecological niche modeling. &lt;jats:italic&gt;Lasius niger&lt;/jats:italic&gt; is more closely related to other Palearctic species than to the Nearctic ants known under this name. The latter are described as a distinct species, &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. ponderosae&lt;/jats:italic&gt; sp. nov. However, DNA-barcoding discovered established populations of &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. niger&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in metropolitan areas in Canada (Vancouver and Halifax). We describe a morphometrical method to delineate &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. ponderosae&lt;/jats:italic&gt; sp. nov. and &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. niger&lt;/jats:italic&gt;. MtDNA diversity and divergence is high within &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. ponderosae&lt;/jats:italic&gt; sp. nov., but low within &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. niger.&lt;/jats:italic&gt; More than 1,000,000 km&lt;jats:sup&gt;2&lt;/jats:sup&gt; are suitable as a habitat for &lt;jats:italic&gt;L. niger&lt;/jats:italic&gt; in North America. This case emphasizes the critical role of integrative taxonomy to detect cryptic species and identify potential biological invasions in their nascent stages.&lt;/jats:p&gt;</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>