<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q117804674</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q117804674</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3897/NEOBIOTA.81.97736</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>_Status and distribution of an introduced population of European Goldfinches (Carduelis carduelis) in the western Great Lakes region of North America</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Craves, Julie A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Anich, Nicholas M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2023-01-24</dc:date>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>European Goldfinch</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>introduced species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Pensoft Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Despite the importance of monitoring introduced species, reports of non-native birds are often initially dismissed by observers. This leads to serious information gaps about source localities, founding numbers, and growth and expansion of potential new populations. Here, we report on European Goldfinches in North America between 2001 and 2021, focusing on the western Great Lakes region. We compiled over 7000 records of European Goldfinches from multiple sources; over 3300 records were from the western Great Lakes. This species was initially reported widely in this region, but over time, birds were most consistently reported between Milwaukee, Wisconsin and Chicago, Illinois. They have been breeding in this area continuously since 2003 and the number of reported observations has increased in recent years. From our compiled records, we describe their distribution, breeding status, nesting phenology, and natural food sources. From import records, we provide evidence that the likely primary founding event of this population was release or escape from a cage bird importer in northern Illinois and provide information on possible origins. We briefly discuss possible ecological impacts. We highlight weaknesses in the way data on non-native species are currently collected and how it has impeded our ability to thoroughly reconstruct the recent history of this species in the western Great Lakes region. Formal study is needed on this population of European Goldfinches, including their potentially increasing population and range, ecology, and an evaluation of the potential effects on native ecosystems.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>