<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q58447207</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q58447207</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6090645</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1186/S12936-018-2445-8</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Comparative 1D Blue-Native electrophoresis analysis of Plasmodium falciparum and human proteins associated with cytoadherence</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wu, Yang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wagstaff, Simon C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Al-Harthi, Saeed A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Craig, Alister G</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-08-13</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>parasitology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>infectious disease</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Plasmodium falciparum</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>BackgroundTo understand more about changes to the molecular components that occur when host endothelium interacts with Plasmodium falciparum-infected erythrocytes, a combined technique of protein separation (1D Blue-Native electrophoresis) and mass spectrometry of infected erythrocytes with endothelial cells (EC) in a co-culture system has been used.MethodsNative proteins were extracted from co-cultures and identified by mass spectrometry. Proteomic data from different parasite strains, either adhesion proficient (to endothelial cells) or non-adherent, were analysed in parallel to reveal protein associations linked to cytoadherence. Informatic approaches were developed to facilitate this comparison.ResultsBlue-Native gel separation and LC/MS/MS identification revealed major differences in samples produced from endothelial cell co-culture with adherent and non-adherent parasite strains. This approach enabled us to identify protein associations seen only with the adhesion proficient parasite strain.ConclusionsThe combination of proteomic and analytical approaches has identified differences between adherent and non-adherent parasite lines in co-culture with EC, providing potential candidates for complexes or associations formed during cytoadherence involved in cell structure, signalling and apoptosis.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>