<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q51148922</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q51148922</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5871849</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/S41598-018-23657-Z</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>A globally-distributed alien invasive species poses risks to United States imperiled species.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>McClure, Meredith L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Burdett, Christopher L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Farnsworth, Matthew L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sweeney, Steven J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Miller, Ryan S</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-03-28</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasion biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>United States of America</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>pig</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractIn the midst of Earth’s sixth mass extinction event, non-native species are a driving factor in many imperiled species’ declines. One of the most widespread and destructive alien invasive species in the world, wild pigs (Sus scrofa) threaten native species through predation, habitat destruction, competition, and disease transmission. We show that wild pigs co-occur with up to 87.2% of imperiled species in the contiguous U.S. identified as susceptible to their direct impacts, and we project increases in both the number of species at risk and the geographic extent of risks by 2025. Wild pigs may therefore present a severe threat to U.S. imperiled species, with serious implications for management of at-risk species throughout wild pigs’ global distribution. We offer guidance for efficient allocation of research effort and conservation resources across species and regions using a simple approach that can be applied to wild pigs and other alien invasive species globally.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>