<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q60300643</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q60300643</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.7717/PEERJ.6107</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Climatic niche shift and possible future spread of the invasive South African Orchid Disa bracteata in Australia and adjacent areas</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Konowalik, Kamil</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konowalik, Kamil</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kolanowska, Marta</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-12-20</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>niche shift</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>climatic niche</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Australia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Disa bracteata</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>PeerJ</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Orchids are generally regarded as plants with an insignificant invasive potential and so far only one species has proved to be harmful for native flora. However, previous studies on Epipactis helleborine and Arundina graminifolia indicate that the ecological aspects of range extension in their non-native geographical range are not the same for all species of orchids. Disa bracteata in its native range, South Africa, is categorized as of little concern in terms of conservation whereas in Australia it is naturalized and considered to be an environmental weed. The aim of this research was to determine the ecological preferences enabling the spread of Disa bracteata in Western and South Australia, Victoria and Tasmania and to evaluate the effect of future climate change on its potential range. The ecological niche modeling approach indicates that most of the accessible areas are already occupied by this species but future expansion will continue based on four climate change scenarios (rcp26, rcp45, rcp60, rcp85). Further expansion is predicted especially in eastern Australia and eastern Tasmania. Moreover, there are some unpopulated but suitable habitats in New Zealand, which according to climate change scenarios will become even more suitable in the future. The most striking result of this study is the significant difference between the environmental conditions recorded in the areas which D. bracteata naturally inhabits and invasive sites—that indicates a possible niche shift. In Australia the studied species continues to populate a new niche or exploit habitats that are only moderately represented in South Africa.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>