<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q110862519</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q110862519</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/S10530-020-02367-6</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Impacts of invasive trees on alpha and beta diversity of temperate forest understories</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dyderski, Marcin K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jagodziski, Andrzej M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-09-28</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>theme:invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>theme:wikidata.org/entity/Q112148709</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive tree</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasion impact</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>beta diversity</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>AbstractDespite good recognition of distributions and spread mechanisms of the three most invasive trees in Europe (Prunus serotina,Quercus rubraandRobinia pseudoacacia), their impacts on forest biodiversity are unevenly recognized. Most studies cover only taxonomic alpha diversity, and only a single study included functional and phylogenetic diversity. Using a set of 186 study plots in western Poland we assessed the impacts of these invasive tree species on the alpha and beta taxonomic, functional and phylogenetic diversity of understory vascular plants. Alpha diversity was higher inR. pseudoacaciaforests and lower inQ. rubraforests compared to mature native forests. Compared to non-invaded plantations and forests, alpha diversity was higher inP. sylvestrisplantations invaded byP. serotina, but lower in invaded nutrient-poorP. sylvestrisforests. Alien species richness was higher and beta diversity was lower in forests invaded byP. serotinaorR. pseudoacaciathan in non-invaded forests. In contrast, beta diversity was higher inQ. rubraforests than in native forests. We proved that invaded forests differed from non-invaded forests in species composition, but not always with decreased alpha and beta diversity. Impacts of particular invasive species also depended on the reference ecosystem properties (here mature native forests, which did not always have the highest biodiversity), which is a source of inconsistency in previous studies, usually referring to single native ecosystem types.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>