<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q100383204</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q100383204</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/S20195488</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Bearing Damage Detection of a Reinforced Concrete Plate Based on Sensitivity Analysis and Chaotic Moth-Flame-Invasive Weed Optimization</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Huang, Minshui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lei, Yongzhi</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2020-09-25</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>invasive weed optimization</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive weed</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>This article proposes a novel damage detection method based on the sensitivity analysis and chaotic moth-flame-invasive weed optimization (CMF-IWO), which is utilized to simultaneously identify the damage of structural elements and bearings. First, the sensitivity coefficients of eigenvalues to the damage factors of structural elements and bearings are deduced, the regularization technology is used to solve the problem of equation undetermined, meanwhile, the modal strain energy-based index is utilized to detect the damage locations, and the regularization objective function is constructed to quantify the damage severity. Then, for the subsequent procedure of damage detection, CMF-IWO is proposed based on moth-flame optimization and invasive weed optimization as well as chaos theory, reverse learning, and evolutional strategy. The optimization effectiveness of the hybrid algorithm is verified by five benchmark functions and a damage identification numerical example of a simply supported beam; the results demonstrate it is of great global search ability and higher convergence efficiency. After that, a numerical example of an 8-span continuous beam and an experimental reinforced concrete plate are both adopted to evaluate the proposed damage identification method. The results of the numerical example indicate that the proposed method can locate and quantify the damage of structural elements and bearings with high accuracy. Furthermore, the outcomes of the experimental example show that despite the existence of some errors and uncertain factors, the method still obtains an acceptable result. Generally speaking, the proposed method is proved that it is of good feasibility.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>