<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q35958060</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.1186/2047-783X-17-7</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Caspofungin for treatment of invasive aspergillosis in Germany: results of a pre-planned subanalysis of an international registry</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Egerer, Gerlinde</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reichert, Dietmar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pletz, Mathias W</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kaskel, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krobot, Karl J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maertens, Johan</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2012-04-17</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>aspergillosis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Germany</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive aspergillosis</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>&lt;h4&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;This study is a pre-planned country-specific subanalysis of results in Germany from a multinational multicenter registry to prospectively assess real-world experience with caspofungin administered for treatment of proven or probable invasive aspergillosis (IA).&lt;h4&gt;Methods&lt;/h4&gt;Data from patients treated with caspofungin for a single episode of IA were collected. Effectiveness was determined by the local investigator as favorable (complete or partial response) or unfavorable (stable disease, failure or death) at the end of caspofungin therapy. Descriptive statistics with binomial exact confidence intervals were employed.&lt;h4&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;Forty-two consecutive patients were identified in three German centers. Three patients (7%) had proven IA and 39/42 (93%) had probable IA (modified European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer/Mycosis Study Group (EORTC/MSG) criteria). Forty-one patients had pulmonary IA and one had tracheal IA. Caspofungin monotherapy was received by 36/42 patients (86%); of these, 26/36 (72%) received salvage therapy. A favorable response was observed in 29/42 patients (69%; 95% CI 53 to 82%); of these, 21/29 (72%) had a complete and 8/29 (28%) a partial response. Favorable response rate was 69% in patients with monotherapy (95% CI 52% to 84%; 25/36 patients), and 67% in patients receiving combination therapy (95% CI 22% to 96%; 4/6 patients). Favorable response rate in patients with first line therapy was 64% (95% CI 31% to 89%; 7/11 patients), and 73% in patients with second line therapy (95% CI 54% to 88%; 20/30 patients). No adverse events were reported. In total, 35/42 patients (83%; 95% CI 69 to 93%) survived seven days after completion of caspofungin therapy.&lt;h4&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h4&gt;These real-life findings in Germany are consistent with the international findings from this registry and with findings from randomized studies.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>