<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q111322854</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q111322854</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.3390/BIOLOGY10100998</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Risk Assessment of &lt;i&gt;Anopheles philippinensis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Anopheles nivipes&lt;/i&gt; (Diptera: Culicidae) Invading China under Climate Change</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Li, Chao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gao, Yuan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chang, Nan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Delong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhou, Ruobing</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhao, Zhe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Jun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Qinfeng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, Qiyong</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2021-10-03</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Anopheles philippinensis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Anopheles nivipes</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Culicidae</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>climate change</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Background: Anopheles philippinensis and Anopheles nivipes are morphologically similar and are considered to be effective vectors of malaria transmission in northeastern India. Environmental factors such as temperature and rainfall have a significant impact on the temporal and spatial distribution of disease vectors driven by future climate change. Methods: In this study, we used the maximum entropy model to predict the potential global distribution of the two mosquito species in the near future and the trend of future distribution in China. Based on the contribution rate of environmental factors, we analyzed the main environmental factors affecting the distribution of the two mosquito species. We also constructed a disease vector risk assessment index system to calculate the comprehensive risk value of the invasive species. Results: Precipitation has a significant effect on the distribution of potentially suitable areas for Anopheles philippinensis and Anopheles nivipes. The two mosquito species may spread in the suitable areas of China in the future. The results of the risk assessment index system showed that the two mosquito species belong to the moderate invasion risk level for China. Conclusions: China should improve the mosquito vector monitoring system, formulate scientific prevention and control strategies and strictly prevent foreign imports.</dc:description>
  <dc:coverage>n/a</dc:coverage>
</oai_dc:dc>