<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:identifier>https://scholia.toolforge.org/work/Q49704141</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q49704141</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5767085</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>doi:10.7717/PEERJ.4223</dc:identifier>
  <dc:title>Using underwater video to evaluate the performance of the Fukui trap as a mitigation tool for the invasive European green crab (Carcinus maenas) in Newfoundland, Canada.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bergshoeff, Jonathan A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McKenzie, Cynthia H</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Best, Kiley</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zargarpour, Nicola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Favaro, Brett</dc:creator>
  <dc:type>journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:date>2018-01-10</dc:date>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:subject>Carcinus maenas</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Canada</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>invasive species</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fukui trap</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>PeerJ</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The European green crab (Carcinus maenas) is a destructive marine invader that was first discovered in Newfoundland waters in 2007 and has since become established in nearshore ecosystems on the south and west coast of the island. Targeted fishing programs aimed at removing green crabs from invaded Newfoundland ecosystems use Fukui traps, but the capture efficiency of these traps has not been previously assessed. We assessed Fukui traps usingin situobservation with underwater video cameras as they actively fished for green crabs. From these videos, we recorded the number of green crabs that approached the trap, the outcome of each entry attempt (success or failure), and the number of exits from the trap. Across eight videos, we observed 1,226 green crab entry attempts, with only a 16% rate of success from these attempts. Based on these observations we believe there is scope to improve the performance of the Fukui trap through modifications in order to achieve a higher catch per unit effort (CPUE), maximizing trap usage for mitigation. Ultimately, a more efficient Fukui trap will help to control green crab populations in order to preserve the function and integrity of ecosystems invaded by the green crab.</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc>